I mean I think it's just obvious is this
ridiculous it just gives some celebrity
a creative director role of anything
there's only like three guys that I
think could even possibly work
you know consistently and then that's
Ryan Leslie me and will.i.am Wow what's
up everybody once again is brain man
Sean and today I have to talk about
arguably one of the most successful
independent artists as a matter of fact
one of the most independent independent
artists there is in the game that would
be Ryan Leslie I mean I'm talking about
somebody who did two million dollars in
one album cycle without any major record
label and without having his music on
streaming services first I got to give a
shout out to all of you guys out there
who asked me to do a video on Ryan
Leslie because y'all have been asking
for a minute now here it is how for
those of you guys who don't know who
Ryan Leslie is he hit the scene hard
with the song addiction back in 2008
which was featuring Cassie but not only
is he a good singer and rapper he also
is an off the chain producer and got a
lot of traction for a video that went
viral of him just producing the song
addiction in the studio but what makes
Ryan Leslie so unique in terms of being
independent when I think about what
makes Ryan Leslie unique I always go
back to my personal experience when I
first met Ryan Leslie it was actually at
a conference a tech conference and there
were only like five black people there
it was me Ryan Leslie one of the guys
was Ryan Leslie's team member or his
assistant or something Paul George and
maybe somebody else me Ryan chopped it
up a little bit alluded to following up
and then he told me to take down his
phone information he gave me this link
that was basically similar to kind of a
B card type feel a couple of months
later we hadn't necessarily follow up
but then my phone vibrates I pick it up
look at it and it's a happy birthday
text message from Ryan Leslie I remember
thinking hmm like this guy can't be like
me because me I know I'll schedule a
text so far at events I mean it's not
even December yet and I already got a
happy Valentine's Day scheduled for my
girls I did a little bit of research
about a Ryan Leslie super phone and this
is what makes Ryan Leslie so unique Ryan
Leslie a Harvard government major who
became a great
me nominated recording artist has
removed his music from iTunes and
launched a company to reach fans in new
ways and he's made more money as an
independent than ever before super fun
is basically a crm for fans now if you
guys are not familiar with the concept
of a CRM CRM stands for customer
relationship manager and a lot of
companies use CRM because they have a
large amount of customers but they want
to be able to be as personal with their
customers as possible especially in
sales at the very least you want to
understand your history with that
customer so whenever you reach out
you're not starting from square one
because you know you know talk to the
same people every day it might be months
in between but what's all that mean just
imagine you're outside you know going
through your everyday life and then
somebody walks up to you like oh my god
I'm here number one thing imagine
yourself being able to go really oh man
that's dope let me um oh actually when I
look it up it looks like you're really
my fifty seven thousand and three
hundred and four fan because you haven't
bought any of my projects in about three
years you actually haven't been any my
concerts what makes you think you're my
number one fan again Ryan Leslie can do
that I want to talk about why this is
the future but first check out this
example of one really cool way that Ryan
Leslie used the platform and so just
over this last New Year's I threw a
party and I just put it out there to all
my fans I said look if you guys reserved
at a 200 euro price point a ticket to my
New Year's Eve party I'll throw a
private New Year's Eve party I didn't
have a venue I didn't have anything
forty-eight hours later I was up 40,000
euros and I rented a palace in Vienna
Austria and two hundred of my top fans
came to Vienna Austria and had a big
party with me for New Year's Eve
and then this year we did it again and
this time I said well if you guys wanted
a super exclusive package
the tickets are $1700 that intimate
experience that access it's not really
about the money it's it's really about a
priceless moment so go ahead and just
let that soak in a little bit you can
simply have an idea text your fans
directly no marketing in terms of having
to pay for advertising get on certain
platforms don't have to get a graphic
designer none of that time you can just
come up with the concept get the money
in return or at least you're fans of
pins and then execute it if you still
decide you want to do it the amount of
money and effort that that saves
especially if somebody as independent is
invaluable as Ryan Leslie says he does
with no manager no record label none of
those things he has a record label of
his own he's running from his phone now
check out this other really unique thing
that Ryan Leslie was able to do because
of this platform and his access to his
fans I realized that maybe they didn't
want to support me by buying a digital
copy of my record but I did have folks
that decided hey Ryan if you want to
make a video I'd love to give you my
services if you need 30 Lamborghinis in
a video I run the Lamborghini Club in
Belgium and I can have them all pull up
his name is t-bar van Rini grande myself
are under wishes demi knowledge
when I'm pulling beauties out that meet
up with very people I'm disguising 30
cause of me you never see me and the
cool thing about it is when you have a
fan base you have no way of knowing what
every single person does what they have
access to this person ran a Lamborghini
Club so you got all these Lambos for
free once again as an independent artist
any resources are extremely valuable and
when you have this access to resources
in these unorthodox ways you're gonna be
able to create experiences that other
people can't recreate with their fan
base now let's talk about themselves
though look at my major label release
180,000 copies album 1 and 60,000 copies
album two how does that make sense
you know when the second album was
grammy-nominated the real disconnect is
why wasn't the marketing plan to
personally reach out to the 180,000
people that got my first record well
that can't be the marketing plan because
we don't know those people
all right well if you want to continue
chasing that dream with those people
that don't know those people
then be my guest for everybody else me
I'll lead you to the promised land
take my ass well superphone allows him
to do is say hey y'all like my project
here's my next project speaking to the
people who actually bought the first
project he a loose citizen talks about
this but it really is a true business
principle that it's cheaper to maintain
a customer than it is to create a new
one you spend a lot of money trying to
create these customers but once they're
in the house all you have to do is
maintain the relationships they're the
ones who are most likely to buy more a
lot of the brands that you use or
partake in you do it more than once and
they don't really have to convince you
again but the very first time that you
were ever introduced to that it costed
them something to get that brand in
front of you many of you have heard the
concept of a thousand true fans I never
did a video on it because I thought it
was enough videos talking about it out
there so holla we'll do a link in the
description below somewhere Ryan Leslie
is truly an example of that concept
because as he said in one video he did
two million dollars for an album cycle
and it was with around 15,000 fans now
if you think about that you do the math
that's about one hundred and thirty
three dollars per fan but if you do the
math if he only had one thousand fans he
could have did one hundred and thirty
three thousand dollars off of that one
project with a thousand person fan base
but he's only able to get the most out
of his fan base with the least amount of
effort because he's able to identify and
communicate with his strongest fans do
you get his music through his platform
through his website even if he decides
to put something on a Spotify or Apple
music his fans his biggest fans have
access to it first and they literally
get it through a text message link this
is exactly why this is the future of
music if you want to be successful in
the digital era you need to know who
your supporters are and what this type
of contact does is it allows you to cut
the marketing costs and it also allows
you to cut out the middleman for
independent artists that's a lot of
money safe which is important when they
don't have a lot of money to spend this
is why have you listened to Steve Stoute
talk about the music tech company that
he just launched United masters two big
things you hear him talking about his
marketing and also his company has its
own crm that next level of connection
with fans is going to be huge as a
matter of fact I wouldn't be surprised
if Ryan Leslie had something to do with
the United Master CRM because when I
think about it injuries and Horowitz is
actually an investor in United masters
and they're also an investor in Bevil
Ryan Leslie and Tristan and walk or a
good friends so it probably makes sense
they all run in a similar circle I'm
pretty sure if not at the least he's
very aware that there's that competition
at play competition and those sorts of
spaces just let you know how real the
opportunity is but also validates how
much that really is the future I want to
end this video in a slightly different
way because I want to end it with some
words from Ryan Leslie so that's it you
know what to do that subscribe button
and number two is it's about sales right
when music is available for free every
sale counts
so you have to understand that 1% of
releases accounts for 77% of money spent
on music right so that means that less
than 3 less than 3% of albums released
every year sell more than a thousand
copies and so for me I'm interested I'm
first of all I'm part of the 3% right I
might be part of the 1% right yep and
what's also interesting is that I'm
interested in teaching young musicians
how to be part of that 3% there's so
many kids I hear man they put so much
passion