[Music]
house of everybody once again is brain
man Shawn and I got another snippet from
my conversation with TJ Chapman
now who is TJ Chapman he's Bo be his
manager truck pickles manager guy super
experienced you gotta listen to this guy
in his wisdom or in this video right
here it's something that is really a lot
deeper than a lot of artists realized
and I swear if you reprogram this about
how you think about your marketing as an
artist you will find far more success
because this one thing honestly has the
power to in an artist career before they
ever have a real shine and it's funny
it's funny to me how many artists feel
like advertising is cheating they want
to be organic and advertising isn't
organic what you crazy on man you think
Apple says there when they drop new damn
iPhone all every brand you think you
think of Atlantic says that with cardi B
know they put millions of dollars into
the marketing to make sure they put it
in front of everybody
yep you know but you have to put in
front of people so they can see it in
the first place to make that decision
whether or not they want to listen yep
and they it just trips me out how they
they feel like is cheating or or it's
not right and man that is business 101
at the end of the day you have to figure
out which of music how you going first
off you got to find a place for it to
live
number two you got to figure out how you
gonna give it like and I can't tell you
none of that for sure I'm gonna shoot at
all these methods to try to find the
right one and if all of them work or
whatever that's the more the merrier but
I'm not limiting my odds you know in
breaking this record I'm gonna try to
expose it every way possible I'm going
to use all the methods that I told you
to make sure
I expose it to people till I find
something to catch and this record
actually gets life it's weird that in
the marketplace today is there's this
big pushback or desire to be organic as
if it makes you look right and I don't
and organic and marketing don't
necessarily go in and it has to be
artificial I don't care if you didn't
pay any money but I axed you the fact I
asked you to listen to my song
personally is me putting in some
artificial effort to get you to listen
but you want to you want to start or
spark some organic that's what you want
your artificial marketing to do but you
gotta get like that ball rolling and
like you have there's so many people
that are like I'll do a video about an
artist on channel for example and
someone might be like oh man this is
fake or their industry plan or they paid
already had money and it's like you're
talking about them for the methods they
use but they're hauling their where you
want to get like so try to use those
methods as opposed to understand but
they did killing themselves up for sure
alright so you might have heard the
point you might get the point but I have
to expand on this conversation because
honestly I don't think artists
understand the gravity of what this is
rooted in first and foremost you have to
consider that it's been marketed to
artists for years this whole idea of the
starving artists that used to be a real
thing that signify purity artists
actually took pride in being a starving
artist but do you know why artists were
starving because the record labels were
taking their money somebody was making
money off of the artist and then the
other artist which is being sold the
dream so you have to struggle and hustle
to even get in a position to get your
money taken that's been pushed and
pushed on artists for a long time now
and there's still some remnants of that
stuff left over to the point where you
have this weird classism and artistry
where artists tried to downgrade and
discredit people who aren't moving with
a starving artist mentality of this just
happens for me it was super organic I
didn't use a
is mine and infrastructure and way of
going about things to boost my career so
even though you might not have that in
all aspects there might be small
subjects where you're thinking about it
that way because at the end of the day
when you're complaining about these
other people it does nothing but make
you sound like a loser and why do I say
it like that because I think that's the
only way to drive through the point that
y'all are playing the same game so to
speak really you're playing your own
game but everybody is playing this music
game in the artist space right well if
that's true just like any video game
there's people who have strengths and
weaknesses right you might have a
hundred on power but 50 on speed and
something notes on the agility that you
might have certain weapons it's the same
thing everybody has different advantages
you might have more time to spend or
waste there's certain things that people
have and some people is there certain
things other people don't at the end of
the day there's the things you have and
the things that you don't have but when
you work through those certain levels of
the game you're either losing or you're
winning and various parts of the game
you get to the big boss and hey they
have all these different powers that you
will have and you either beat them or
you lose you have to make the most out
of what you have because you wouldn't be
complaining if you had the money if you
had a Rich Dad or if you had a big
investor if you had some of these other
situations you're not going to be saying
hey yeah I got a million dollars in the
bank but I'm not gonna use it so I can
keep it real that's stupid first of all
like money does not guarantee success in
the game connections do not even
guarantee success in the game so you
really playing yourself if you allow
yourself to get continue having that
narrative out there you're just allowing
that to exist because it makes you feel
better since I don't have that then I
can get this that's the only reason they
have that and I don't
but again the truth is that's not the
only differentiator it isn't because
there's so many rich parents or so many
successful artists that have kids that
are nowhere near as big as some of these
other artists right how many artists are
as big as Chris Brown are as big as
Drake or as big as chance to rapper are
as
big-ass Taylor Swift Beyonce not to say
that these people didn't have certain
connections at certain points of their
career but for the most part most of
these people started outside of the
industry and worked their way up
but there's so many people with kids
that are legends in the game that are
not doing it big no one wants to listen
to their music they have connections but
nobody cares about their money they're
still not going to the shows a girls are
telling me the other day out she just
went to this show of a girl who has 1.2
million followers on Instagram and the
person inside to a legend in the game
and I'm not even talking about old
school old school legend I'm talking
about the legend still has high cultural
impact today but the girl didn't have
like 50 people at her show stop looking
at people and say oh of course they made
it because they got a lot of money the
money does not guarantee the success
which brings me back to the fact this
whole organic thing as well it's
something that you guys have to get your
mind off of this whole idea if you're
going to market if you're working on
marketing right now then it's not
organic if you pay for one post to be
posted by the influencer you're already
doing something that's not organic by
that type of definition your whole
marketing initiative is to do as many
artificial things as possible that will
bring attention to your product and hope
that your product is quality enough that
it sparks and creates organic traffic
anybody else who just having to blow up
and they didn't know what was happening
yeah those people are out there they did
just go viral but that's a look at a car
that's to draw the cars it's not because
they were better than somebody else
that's just good timing there's a lot of
people who can sing well right well all
these things but they didn't post it on
the platform and didn't get seen by
certain people and it didn't go viral
and keep in mind whenever a new platform
ages it will be harder and harder to be
organic if you're five six seven years
into Instagram and posting there's not
gonna be that much organic growth and
help because the platform's build their
technology against it they're different
now and that goes for any other platform
if you get on there early yes you might
find some good organic growth but the
chances of that go down and
down and down every single month of
platform ages that's just how it goes
I'm not going to get into all the
particular reasons I just need you guys
to realize is there is no dishonor in
building an audience from paid traffic
if this is a fan base you have fans
that's all that matters it's not smart
just to be spending money and then
people don't come in to fans that's why
we talk about strategy and how to do
things right but if you get the end
result then great because there's a lot
of people out there spending the money
way more money than you can even imagine
and still not getting the result the
link to my full interview of TJ's
deejays will be in a description below
once that interview is dropped that link
will become active and other than that
if you like this video go ahead and like
button if you liked it might as well
share it and if you're not subscribed
you know what to do he dares subscribe
[Music]
you