yeah B what's up everybody what's did
it's brand man Sean and today I'm going
to do a video on how XXX ton AKA X AKA
Jaden Dark Side built his cult following
and you can thank this video to maze so
let's get this started the number one
most important thing is X is this huge
ball of unique pairings if you don't
want to know what a unique pairing is
then you got to check out my unique
pairing video but is basically these
contradictions and he amplifies them
people are extremely attracted to
contradictions primarily because we are
contradictions but most people hide
their contradiction because they want to
be politically correct but when you're
like X then you amplify it and then it
turns you into a polarizing figure that
attracts a lot of attention X is the bad
guy X is the good guy X has been to jail
and he's beat people up and he talks
about it openly and still looks like he
doesn't regret it he's happy about it
but he does all this talk about love and
stuff like that he speaks about himself
as this fragile emotional creature uh
talking about his mom and all this stuff
he even talked about transparently that
he did a blood bomb with a girl the kind
of stuff that people usually don't
really reveal about themselves open to
the public but at the same time all of
this emotion that he has he's also this
extremely masculine defensive figure
where he's hotheaded and he's going to
beat you up if you say something and you
make him unhappy all these
contradictions he talked about how he
grew up the pretty boy but then he like
ugli himself up because he doesn't want
to try to look good kind of like Johnny
Depp so he's like the pretty ugly boy
it's all these contradictions that just
make him interesting people are
intrigued by what they do not understand
and what pequs their curiosity being a
mystery is not necessarily about not
being seen so when you take this
misunderstanding that people have for
him and somebody like him who amplifies
himself he doesn't hide any of his
contradictions he speaks about them with
as much conviction as as possible he'll
he'll talk about beating somebody up
with as much confidence and and bravado
and energy in the same way he'll talk
about I want to better the world and
make people love each other and all that
stuff again to understand the power of
that you have to look at my unique
pairing video I'll link it up and then
I'll also provide in the description or
something but that level of polarization
makes people really love you or really
really hate you and that's something
that the type of figure that he is plays
off of he focuses obviously though on
really cultivating that audience that
really loves him and when you recognize
that like he does he even breaks down
that my fans are people who do anything
that I'll say Mike supporters are people
that they wish the best for me and then
obviously you have the haters but he
makes it very clear that he knows who
his his fans are and he gives them all
of his energy which goes into number two
number two is connection he connects so
deeply with his audience with his fans
which is why they push for him they
fight for him they go to bat for him
right it's not about just being
authentic yes he's completely
transparent about all these things all
these hardships he had all how fragile
he is how uh sad he's had just all these
bad times and things that he's been
through but he's taking a level up by
basically saying I'm a represent of that
he knows and he's even said straight up
that I'm a representative for those
people who haven't expressed themselves
who haven't Express their pain night
what you feel in the morning what you
feel midday that you don't think other
people have the same thoughts you feel
alone in this thought but other people
have the same thoughts and it breeds and
when you when you display this thought
it breeds a certain amount of comfort
within people and people start to feel
like all right this person understands
me this person is [\h__\h] cool so when I
when I say some [\h__\h] like hey I want to
[\h__\h] gut myself right now I want to
jump off this [\h__\h] cliff I saw you
and it broke my heart when I say
different things like that and these
people they want to say these things to
that person but they can't say it
because it's been so like it's they gone
through all these things all it's un you
feel me you can't say certain things
exctly I I am the
epitome of the Misunderstood right I am
literally the people that that that
aren't aren't understood right there's
no other way to say that he's a symbol
for human suffering and how you can lash
out and fighting back and pushing
against the system and your own inner
demons in a way that a lot of people
don't do um particularly openly it takes
a lot of Courage that's a huge huge
portion of why people support him and
love him the way they do people might
hate these comparisons but it's not that
much different for when you think about
a Tupac what he stood for right yes he
loved black people and want to better
things for black people but really his
overall message was about humanity and
even X talks about more so humanity and
representing those emotions for those
type of people and everybody has those
emotions and not just a specific hey
young people want to come up or I
represent no he's talking about
representing a feeling and a freedom
from those feelings and everybody can
relate to feeling like suffering feeling
human suffering and wanting to be freed
from that and last but not least number
three three Marty him X became a martyr
the day he went to jail and the day
people start hearing his music and
finding out that he was in jail when you
go through jail it's just again and
again in hip-hop we see that going to
jail can really help people's careers
when I was in ninth grade I was
suspended for I don't know second third
time whatever but when I was suspended I
didn't have anything to do with this but
one of my friends created a free Sean
Page and this
it was early days of Facebook and next
thing you know all these people are
signing up supporting hey frean let him
out the school's tripping y Yad Y and it
just happened right X didn't plan to
make jail fuel his career but him being
in jail unbeknownst to him did because
once people find their music and then
they're like man what I'm going to get
something else from this guy and then
they find out he's in jail and then
people already have a thing against the
system in hip-hop it helps it turns you
into to a martyr of sorts and the best
type of martyr to be is the Martyr
that's actually alive because most art
Martyrs have to die before they get that
status and I don't encourage anybody to
go to jail on purpose just so they can
try to use it as a marketing tactic but
it's worked right Little Bootsy just got
out of jail Gucci man it's helped so
many people's careers in a weirdish way
but hey go ahead and share this if you
like X and you want to support X and
think other people might agree and just
be interested in seeing this video and
of course if you want to see a video
about somebody else or another topic go
ahead and ask me in the comments you
know what to do hit that subscribe
button