what's up what's up what's up everybody
once again it's Sean Taylor and I
believe that artists should control
their own destiny which is why I bring
information like this nipy hustle 12
tips to build a music Empire
independently so if you don't know who
nipy hustle is he's that guy that might
you might have heard of when he sold
that $100 mixtape and Jay-Z bought like
a thousand copies of the mix tape but he
also sold other copies of it um so
that's just a real short snippet and how
can somebody that's not really super
known sell $100 copies of his mtape
we'll get into it and how he does it
here's his tips like I talk about I I
was in the streets I had money I had
spots and I sold all my jewelry sold my
cars and bought studio equipment and
devoted myself to it and U I made a lot
of music majority of the stuff that was
on bullet sing I names one and two I
made before my
deal number one commit he got rid of all
his chains and sold all his stuff like
he said just because he knew he was
going in a New Direction he didn't want
to be on the streets no more he's
committed to this music number one
commit number two collaborate so
Kendrick YG Don Kennedy Nic hustle
himself those guys all collaborated a
lot in the beginning of their careers
particular with each other because they
were in the same areas and you could
take advantage of this too because it
allows you to build a fan base
especially if you're in a city so you
can get the most out of the area that
you're in
I got a few mentors that just put me on
books and literature and all that big
Bob Francis one of them and so um you
know he he he told me about this book
called contagious contagious uhhuh yeah
so I got to the second chapter of that
and it was just talking about how this
this restaurant owner in Philly started
selling Philly cheese Stakes for $100
out his restaurant and it just was like
it set off all type of conversation
everybody was talking about it then all
type of influential people came through
him and just wanted to check out why it
was $100 like Oprah K through and bought
one David Letterman bought one he got
all type of exposure and publicity M and
then it became like a staple and
everybody start coming through support
Buy $100 cheese so I put the book down
and I was like yeah we got to do that
with theb nobody did that with music so
this is how he came up with this $100
mixtape or album idea studying He also
mentioned having a mentor I suggest
everybody get mentors help him a career
building an empire whatever you want to
do but study study study he's looking
for other information a lot of people in
the hip-hop game don't study he's
reading books and he's actually using
the information yeah won't even go back
and get it though if it's whack you know
you you like I ain't going to listen to
it I pay for it I hear you so I'm like
you know I just wanted to test out what
offering it free would do
experiment right once again like I said
not only is he studying but he
experimented and tested those ideas out
right he not because not only did he
have that $100 copy that came with merch
and a um a free concert pass and things
like that but he also had a $9.99 copy
that was just a streaming copy and then
he also had a free copy he said he
wanted to see what it did and then he
paid attention which is also going right
into this right here when I came back
from from uh T the world on TMC I was
like you know I know why they [\h__\h]
with me I'm like I know what it is it
took me five six mixtapes to really
catch it but I was like I know why I
know I know what it is that they
connecting to so CR shw was was me
trying to just saturate thing with a
project with the with the with the type
of raps and the type of music that
they' connected to me before I think so
this is that experimenting and paying
attention he had six mixtapes obviously
you experimented your own music but then
he paid attention to say okay throughout
this entire process of all these
mixtapes I'm starting to realize exactly
what they [\h__\h] with about me because
once you do that then you have all the
power you paid attention to the people
now you can give the people what they
want I think it's your job to
distinguish yourself Brandon is about
your differences yeah right right it's
about It's Shouting Out Your differences
It Ain't About You Know What's the same
about you
know exactly right just like that
process so once he paid attention saw
what they connect with now he knows what
his differences are he knows what other
people like about him and he can give
them more of that so then they can give
themselves more of them and now he has
these this fan base that's growing
that's tip number five from nipy but it'
be the right move for you yeah they know
My Philosophy they know my business
model I need to be involved as a partner
I need to be an owner I heard and they
know that we ain't going to have comos
if it don't start like that and that's
STP number six it gets real heavy o
seven when it comes to that ownership
did I skip something I don't know but
when it comes to nipy he's super strong
on the ownership and we'll see a little
bit more on this
later like you know what I'm saying
right right but I'm at the table at
every negotiation I'm in control of
everything to do with my my brand to me
that's the power that's where the you
know the side conversation turns into
new
opportunity right so not only does being
an owner mean you own something because
there's this additional benefit when it
comes to the power that affords you so
when you want to think about ownership
if you don't own you're not you don't
have the power for decision making if
you don't have the power for decision
making you're not going to be in
decision-making meetings and those
meetings that's when the Big Wigs that's
when the people who really make those
moves are meeting right so if you can't
be in that meeting you're not going to
build relationships for the people who
really make stuff happen yeah it's nice
to deal with some kind of distributor or
just your manager or anr but if you
can't have that meeting with the guy who
runs let's just say Disney
or some kind of huge company that might
even just want to license all your stuff
and give you all these additional
opportunities then you're missing out on
opportunities which is what most artists
do I'm not trading ownership of the only
asset I have which is my intellectual
prop property that's his music it's
pretty much true for every artist all
they got is their music don't give it up
not go anywhere else why you feel like
man you know what I need to I need to
build my own compound man I just believe
in ownership yeah you know what I mean I
believe in you know um investing
yourself when you make money you know
you could easily go a lot of places but
I just feel like you know your
foundation should be strong he's super
consistent with this so he made his own
compound his own recording studio like
four recording studios worth of in one
studio so I think he had like four
session rooms but when you do something
like this you have to invest in yourself
when you own then you want to invest
then own more invest own more continue
this cycle and this is how you slowly
but surely build an Empire and next
thing you know you buy out the building
you are helping and putting other people
on that's what really really having an
Empire is like data so how I know he's
really super into Data he had
conversation when he was talking about
him using Ryan Leslie superphone app
right and this really really tracks fan
data it's one thing you need to really
collect fan data generally speaking but
this goes to the extent of if you come
up to nipy and say you're his number one
fan he could look in his phone in about
10 seconds figure out exactly if you are
his number one fan or not he could just
see his data and say hey well actually
such and such in Tokyo is my number one
fan you're number 76 because it's basing
on how much you've supported him how
many many shows you've gone to how much
how many albums you bought and he has
all that data at the tip of his fingers
this kind of stuff is great because
let's just say you had a thousand fans
if you had a thousand fans like a
thousand like super super fanatical fans
that bought every single thing you put
out even if he has a 100,000 people that
like him but only a thousand people buy
everything he knows if he puts out
something for $120 at least those
thousand people are going to buy it and
I'm going to make $1 $2,000 off those
people at the very least know the game
change like we in control to an exent
you know we got the internet we got um a
global village that we could deliver
content to you know what I'm saying in
it's in it's worldwide you can tour you
can sell your Merchant you can build
businesses so if you not stuck on you
know being a Fame junky and being some
type of social like you can look at the
game for what it is and eat you know
what I'm saying and and and you know
build something that R slowly tip number
10 know the [\h__\h] a lot of artists do
not do this they're huge on the fame
junkie social light lifestyle and what
happens is or what's going to happen to
a lot of them is what happened to people
in past Generations where the ogs have
these great stories of what was and who
they used to hang with but they're not
on top anymore they're right there
sitting next to you because they didn't
keep making the moves and they didn't
make the Right Moves which was focusing
on the money in addition to the art as
opposed to just saying Hey I want to be
seen that's what a lot of people do
ignore that Fame stuff if you're telling
me that all y'all gauging is sound
scanning billboard we don't need y'all
y'all getting an eviction notice what's
nipy saying about this is hey I don't
care if I'm on your main media Outlets I
don't care if I'm on your radio stations
none of this stuff and which he's on
none of that he's only had like one
radio um song for real for real and he
doesn't need that because he can get to
his fans which means he can get to his
money if he can get to his money he can
build and then create more music and
then get back to his fan and get more
money if you got your fans and you got
your money you don't need anybody else
all that other stuff is an illusion I
swear how much you get paid the the
writer that wrote that I pay them type
of salaries to my employees at my
business that got felonies and that
can't get jobs no disrespect so who's
the underachiever I own my company I own
the asset of this whole industry which
is your your Masters your your
intellectual property you know what I'm
saying your publishing so you know you
you your metrics and what you gauging as
achievement is actually like a peon or
under boss way of looking at it because
you know like I'm not in it for the fame
everybody want to be seen and and held
at the highest regard obviously but you
know you can't cash that out you can't
take that to the bank well you can in
other ways but you know what's the asset
what what do the labels do it for they
do it for the ownership they do it for
the for the catalog for the mailbox
money and so you know I think if you up
on what's what's going on you you will
respect that you wouldn't say A do
underachieving for that yeah for you see
I play longer Clips with nipy than the
other videos because the stuff he says
is so real don't think like a peon what
he was referring to as a complex
magazine writer saying hey this guy is
underachieving they let rated him one of
their top 10 underachieving rappers and
he's like no you measuring people off of
this little media buzz and this you know
this little Fame over here but no man I
I can I could pay you if I wanted to I
could hire 10 of you if I wanted to
because I'm over here winning with what
matters paying attention to the mailbox
money what he was saying with that part
is record labels they pay attention to
mailbox money which is that money when I
wake up it's in a new check is in my
mailbox and that just keeps happening
keeps happening but most artists they
don't focus on that that's why we have
all these past stories of artist being
ripped off he's saying no he has both of
those things he has the art and he has
the money and he's going stay focusing
on that he doesn't need to get complex
to give him a AOK you know it's just
like a metaphor for being a long you
don't judge it by one leg of the race CU
if you judge me by my first leg You'
have been like you know ni the biggest
dude on the west but then if you judg me
by the second leg you might be like nip
didn't drop album and disappointed but
if you judge me by the third leg you
gonna be like nip a independent mile but
if you step back and look at it as a as
a marathon like this dude came from you
know single house family a gang banging
environment you know what I'm saying
didn't graduate high school and been
through the [\h__\h] so way you saying
here is
hey this is everything you put him in a
nutshell it's a marathon
it's a long game because building an
empire is a long game ask Jay-Z ask py P
didy literally start running marathons
because he's obsessed with the idea of a
marathon because he knows he's playing a
long game right it's a marathon so it
doesn't matter about the ups and downs
they they will affect you in the time
being but really if you know you're
playing a long game that helps you not
get caught up in some of that BS when I
said ignore the BS right keep that in
mind that's number 12 and now we're
going to go out with a quote from nipy
on a miss
your worst enemy is idle time that just
means hey don't waste your time
onbs Point
Blank subscribe if it was helpful I'm
going to go out with a quick video um
just of nipy talking about some other
stuff because I still think it's so dope
and feel helpful