Universal Music Group just made a deal
that could change how artists are
getting paid. And most artists don't
even realize how big this is yet. This
isn't just another major label tech
partnership. This is infrastructure.
This could change rollout strategy. This
could change monetization. And this
could change how artists are building
out a sustainable career. Let me
explain. Now, before I break down the
universally even deal, I want you to
listen to how industry veteran Disa
explains what's happening right now.
Because what he's describing isn't just
a platform. It's a shift in how artists
monetize their audience.
>> Major labels return to the physical
world. Universal Music Group has struck
a new multi-year deal with super fan
platform Even, a direct to consumer tool
that lets artists sell music,
merchandise, and exclusive content
straight to fans. The partnership
positions even as a turnkey D2C resource
across UMG's global label system, giving
artists tools for early access drops,
fan communities, exclusive releases, and
physical product sales powered by UMG's
existing vinyl and merch infrastructure.
The move is the latest expansion of
UMG's broader superfan strategy,
arriving just weeks after its investment
in social audio platform station head
and following Lucian Graange's internal
memo naming superfan monetization the
top priority for 2026. launched in 2024,
even says it's already onboarded over
500,000 artists across more than 3,000
labels and distributors in 110 countries
while reporting to the sales to Luminate
for Billboard chart eligibility. You
know, the deal reflects a larger
industry shift where direct to consumer
channels are becoming central to release
strategy. In the US alone, D2C accounted
for a majority of first week physical
album sales across multiple genres. The
bottom line is UMG is building a global
superfan infrastructure designed to let
artists own fan relationships, drive
higher margin sales, and create a deeper
engagement beyond traditional streaming
platforms. And it feels so indie story
developing. So what he just described is
exactly why Universal is partnering with
the platform. Even and to better
understand this deal, you have to
understand what's been happening in the
music industry over the last decade or
so. For the past what 10 to 15 years,
everything has been built around
streaming. Everything revolved around
getting streams, getting playlisted,
going viral, and getting as much social
media reach as one possibly could. And
all of this conditioned us to make
streaming the main priority goal. But
streaming has a fundamental limitation.
Artists don't own the relationship with
their fans. They don't own the platforms
that they have to put their content out
on. I mean, really think about it.
Spotify owns the listener. Tik Tok owns
the algorithm. Instagram owns the reach.
And artists are basically renting access
to their own audience. Now, this is
something that I've personally seen
working with artists, both indie major,
and everything in between. And artists
can generate millions of streams, get
massive exposure from a viral moment,
and still struggle to turn that into
real sustaining income for their
business. Because exposure and ownership
are not the same thing. You can have
attention without any control. And when
you don't control access to your
audience, you're dependent on these
platforms to reach the people who
already support you. And that's the core
problem that even is solving. So let's
take a sec to see everything directly
from the horse's mouth. Check out this
LinkedIn post from Even. All right, so I
want to go through the announcement real
quick. even says, "Today, we announced a
multi-year agreement with Universal
Music Group, the world's largest music
company, to provide directto fan
infrastructure for their labels and
artists worldwide. This means UMG
artists can now use our platform to
build dedicated fan destinations, sell
music ahead of streaming releases with
sales counting towards Billboard charts,
create exclusive content and community
experiences, and offer physical music
and merchandise through UMG's global
DTOC infrastructure. We've always
believed Direct to Fan works alongside
streaming, not against it. This
partnership is the strongest signal yet
that the industry sees it the same way.
From developing artists earning their
first meaningful revenue to established
acts debuting at number one on the
Billboard 200. We serve the full
spectrum of musical talent and we're
just getting started. So I do think that
this multi-year deal and what Even is
allowing artists to do is extremely
important. Right? They're giving these
artists the ability to sell early access
to albums, to sell exclusive content,
merchandise, fan experiences, the whole
shebang in terms of what we look for for
a real DTOC infrastructure for artists
and they can do all of this stuff before
music even hits the streaming platforms,
which is great. So, I do believe that
this is going to change the order of
monetization for artists. Instead of a
artist waiting on streaming revenue,
artists can generate income directly
from their core fans first. And at that
point, we start to see streaming as
amplification and not the starting point
like we've been kind of conditioned to
see it for the last once again 10 to 15
years or so. Now, the part that I think
that most people don't fully understand
is that Universal didn't just partner
with Even Randomly, right? They're
coming off of a really great year.
They've been a part of many, many viral
DDC campaigns for the artist Lar Russell
and other independent artists like him.
Um, they just came off of doing a
campaign for JCole in which that
campaign helped him to get his album to
number one on the Billboard. And so once
again, this is not a random partnership.
This is Universal partnering with a
winning DTOC company because this solves
a structural weakness in the streaming
era. Because no matter how much artists
will [\h__\h] on streaming, streaming is
incredible for discovery. I've been
saying for a long time, if you can, you
know what I'm saying, put the revenue to
the side and look at Spotify and Apple
as just marketing platforms. They are
two of the greatest marketing platforms
for music ever created. But I think that
somewhere within the last 5 to 10 years
or so, we all realize that direct to fan
is way more powerful for monetization
and ownership. And the new formula for
artist growth is going to look like
this, right? Like streaming will give
the artist the reach, but direct to fan
is what will give them the control and
the ability to massively grow their
revenue. And labels already understand
that the most valuable fans are not the
passive listeners. They're not the
people who are just casually listening
to you on the playlist or, you know,
randomly finding you on a Tik Tok feed
at 2:00 a.m. in the morning or something
like that. They know that it's the
active supporters who matter the most,
right? So, those are the fans who care
enough to buy something from you, the
the fans who care enough to engage with
you or engage with things that you post.
And these are the fans that invest
emotionally into your career. major
labels have realized that those fans are
the foundations of a sustainable career
and then they're putting all of their
resources and attention into helping
their artists achieve their goals
through those means. Now, I've been
saying this for a while, but the
industry model has been quietly shifting
right in front of your very eyes. The
old model was release music, try to get
massive streams, hope for revenue. The
new model is going to be build fans,
monetize those fans, and then amplify
what you've received through streaming.
Which in this new model, streaming
basically gets reduced to another
discovery platform while fans become the
real source of income that artists are
looking to sustain their careers. And
this is important because artists will
no longer need millions of passive
listeners just to build a real income
from their music. They will just need a
couple of thousands of real fans who
need incentives and are invested in
their growth and in their career
potential. Basically, you're going to
have to build fans who care not only
about, you know, you and your music, but
also they care about the journey that
you're about to go on. And honestly,
this validates something that I thought
for a very long time. The most valuable
thing an artist can build isn't streams,
but it's an actual core fan base. And
I'm telling you guys, as a marketer who
has gotten their boom in basically the
viral era of the music industry, Yeah. A
lot of artists and a lot of able were
overly concerned with their streaming
numbers at times when the rest of the
fan base may not be catching up to the
massive numbers they are portraying on
the outside using these streaming
platforms. But trust and believe that
the artist will fill it once the check
hit their bank account. So yeah, the
most valuable thing a artist can build
isn't going to be their streaming
numbers. Once again, it's going to be
their fans because these streams can
disappear. The algorithms change every
couple of months, if not every couple of
weeks. And platforms can shift, right?
They can shift their algorithm. They can
shift fans incentive. They can shift an
artist incentive to post or create
content, but real fans will stay with
you and support you through all of that.
And they'll follow you through these
different platforms and through these
different cycles of your career. And
because of that, real fans help artists
build stability. And when artists have a
direct relationship with their fans,
they do gain leverage and they're no
longer fully dependent on these
platforms or really any institution. And
once they have infrastructure and they
have ownership and they have DTOC
figured out, then they have real control
over their career. Now, I do believe
that this partnership is a signal on
where the industry is going, right?
Because in the old model, artists have
to really care about streaming numbers
and artists are being discovered by
these major labels based on the impact
of a viral moment or based on, you know,
how quickly a song rose through the
ranks on platforms like Spotify and like
Apple Music. But I do believe that where
labels are going to start to focus their
attention and their new signing dollars
on next are artists who have already
capitalized and built a strong core fan
base around them that they can already
monetize through DTOC. Now, a lot of you
may not know this, but I once was a part
of the Universal Network, right? I
worked for a label called Def Jam for a
few years and one of the very last
meetings that I ever had with the UMG, I
guess, marketing team was they had a
meeting with us about exactly this. They
sat down and told us that, hey, going
into 2026, we want to focus a lot more
on DTOC. We want to make sure that not
only our big artists, you know, our
Janelle Ekos, our big shuns, our Justin
Bers are focused on DTOC, but we also
want to make sure our newer artists are
focusing on it as well and are
developing that alongside whatever
streaming strategies or whatever seating
or whatever marketing strategies you
guys are developing for these acts. And
they sat down and told us, right, that
they were going to provide the
infrastructure to do so. But I don't
think that even we at the time could
have predicted that they were going to
go with even. Well, actually, now that I
said it out loud, you know, I don't know
who Even's real competitor is at the
moment, but it does make sense they went
with even. But I say to say that this is
a part of a much larger plan for
Universal. They have also realized that
streaming isn't where it's at, right?
Like you guys think that the streaming
uh platforms payout is just a indie
artist problem or a small artist
problem. Like no, even major labels feel
it. I mean, really think about Universal
and any other labels relationships with
these platforms. They're beefing like
every other year, you know what I'm
saying? Like every couple of months
they're going through something. Every
other year they have to rework some new
agreement, you know what I'm saying? Or
rework some new plan that they feel like
is beneficial to to both sides. And I
could imagine Universal just been like,
"Fuck it, bro. We going straight to the
people." You know what I'm saying? Like,
if we can get the people to put money
directly into our artist pockets, which
in return will put money into our
pockets, then we don't have to be nice
to you guys, which we don't want to be
anyway. But I don't want you guys to
take this news as streaming is no longer
going to matter because trust and
believe it will still be a measurement
that is used to weigh the trajectory of
an artist and weigh the potential of an
artist. But direct to fan monetization
will become a large part of an artist
career. And not only that, but it will
become a part of their discovery process
for those who do desire to be signed to
a major or independent label. So the
artists who focus on building real fan
bases instead of just building up, you
know, arbitrary streaming numbers or
viewing numbers, those will be the
artists who have better relationships,
who have more stability, who will have
more leverage, more control, and will
also be higher on the list to be
discovered by these institutions that
want to back artists and the artists who
only focus on chasing streaming numbers
and followers [snorts]
and view counts. Those are the artists
who will continue to be stuck and
dependent upon these platforms. And at
its core, this is a foundational shift
and one that I personally am very glad
that came along. So once again, this
deal between Universal and Even isn't
just about one platform, even though we
should take some time out to give
flowers to Even and, you know,
congratulate them for how far they've
come in such a short amount of time. But
this whole thing is really a signal
about the direction of the industry that
I really want to make sure that
independent artists are paying attention
to. The industry is moving towards fan
ownership. The industry is moving
towards direct fan relationships, which
in turn means that the industry is
moving towards artists having a better
relationship with and more control over
their audience. And artists who
understand this early will have a
massive advantage and will have I think
you know a little bit harder of an
upcoming but probably a more rewarding
one once they start to actually become
monetized or they do get discovered. And
the artists who don't understand this
shift, those are the artists who will be
stuck chasing algorithms and chasing
viral moments instead of building out a
real foundation for their career. So
guys, let me know your thoughts in the
comments section below. Do you think
that this deal between Universal and
Even is a net positive for the industry?
Like do you see this changing the music
industry in a in a way that benefits all
artists or do you think that, you know,
this is just another play at Universal
trying to take some money and take a
play out the indie artist playbook? Let
me know your thoughts in the comment
section below. Other than that, if you
like this video, make sure you hit that
like button, subscribe, share this with
an artist that needs a little bit of
gain today.