[Music]
wow
what's up brandman network it's sean and
i'm back with
the second video of the music release
strategy series and once again these
first three
are just some basic frequently asked
questions that are important though
because they can help you guide
how you move you know for a long time
anybody who does not have an audience
right now a big fan base
do not do not worry about your album
pre-launch series don't worry about what
you do leading up to your project
everything needs to be focused on after
the project i already just got right
into it
but obviously the question is what
should i do before i drop my project
there are some things you should do
but it shouldn't be too focused on
marketing and teasing people and getting
them excited about it because
this is what happens right you're
teasing and oh that teaser sounds good
however when it comes out there's likely
not going to be a great way that you can
get right back out to those same people
my attention is valuable so while you
have my attention make sure you convert
it into something and that's true for
every single potential fan that you have
so if you push out an advertisement i'm
like yo that song sounds dope
that sounds cool and i can't find a song
once i decide to look for it
it's going to be like oh well and i'm
going to move on and who knows if you'll
be able to get my attention again
if you do you'll probably have to pay
for it and we don't want to spend his
you know that much money do we nah cause
we don't have it yet because we're
working on becoming bigger
the alternate is you already have a
project out so when you do an ad
or when you uh just drop an interview or
whatever you're doing post
drop then people can see it and then say
you know what i'm interested
they check out the project or they check
out the song or whatever you have going
on and from there
now you get that attention they make a
decision whether they want to be a fan
all of that good stuff so make sure
you're not spending too much energy on
what you're doing beforehand if you do
not have a
fan base a decent sized fan base to
start
to not only tease but to amp up to
possibly give you a first
big week on your playlist and things of
that nature if you don't have anybody to
do that for you
people who are already checking for you
then it's irrelevant
let's look at it this way like we're
independent we're not worried about
the music charts necessarily billboard
do we even have a chance on getting on
billboard or
some of these other random charts are we
really expecting to get those kind of
results
or get visibility from those folks
probably not
so if you aren't then that whole
mentality of what happens the first week
is really built for those charts it has
nothing to do with
the actual success of the artist there's
been a lot of songs
that had a horrible first week but then
ended up being the first
one of the best charting songs of the
year right long term meaning people
still love the song it doesn't have a
great first week
because to bring it full circle even if
you have some sort of fan base
it doesn't necessarily matter if you
even get those people to give you a nice
big bump in the first
week unless you're trying to drive up
your playlist views
because obviously if you get a certain
amount of playlist views in a short
period of time
you get more opportunities to get on
other playlists on things like spotify
and apple music and then of course
that has its own trickle effect but if
you don't think
you'll be able to do that in the first
place then it's probably not worth
investing
a lot in promo beforehand the things
that you do put out
of course could be you setting out the
ground just for the aesthetic for the
project or the story that you're forming
all that good stuff so when people come
back to see it later
cool but as far as spending marketing
dollars heavily on it beforehand
it's not something you probably need to
do at least not
at the time when you don't have any fans
especially
and that's it for the second video of
the music release strategy series
other than that let's get it