Most artists don't have an identity
problem. They have a commitment problem.
They try to be mysterious on Monday,
authentic on Tuesday, funny on
Wednesday, deep on Thursday, and then
turn into damn near a full-fledged
cartoon character by Friday. A lot of
artists switch their personalities more
than a guitarist switches guitar
strings. But here's the truth that
nobody ever tells artists. You're not
supposed to be everything. And once you
figure out which of the archetypes you
are, your visuals, your storytelling,
your branding, all of it gets way
easier. So, let's break this down. Let's
start with the most misunderstood
archetype, the character artist. A lot
of artists think that characters are
fake, but I think that Oliver Tree
explains it better than anyone.
>> Oliver Tree, the character, the persona.
Can you describe what that character was
like?
>> It was myself and authentic to me, but
turned up to I want to say an 11, but
it's probably more like a 22 or
something like that. The haircut was the
haircut I had my whole life. I was too
scared to get any other haircut. The
jacket was something I stole from my mom
and my mom and [snorts] my dad would
wear it in the '8s. The pants were the
pants I always wanted. The glasses were
like the little glasses I would wear as
a kid that made me feel cool. So, it was
kind of taking the most ridiculous
versions of myself and kind of just like
putting it into one place.
>> So, this is the truth behind character
artists. They're not lying. They're just
exaggerating the parts of themselves
that the world seems to be the most
drawn to. And that exaggeration gives
them everything that an artist wants.
Clarity, direction, aesthetic, and
identity. But for some artists, the
character isn't about theatrics.
Sometimes it's about survival. Listen to
the legendary artist Sia explain why she
hides her face.
>> But whenever you perform, you do not
like to show your face. And I think
people don't understand why. So explain
that first.
>> Well, I was just it's so that I can go
to Target and buy a hose if I want to.
And or if I'm in very in need of a
restroom and I can't find one, I could
go by the side of the road. Nobody would
be following me with a camera trying to
get the shot.
>> Yeah. Oh, that's true. I didn't even
think about the paparazzi thing, but I
thought,
>> well, I don't want to be famous or
recognizable. I don't want to be
critiqued about the way that I look on
the internet. I was at Target the other
day buying a hose and nobody recognized
me and my song was on the radio and I
thought, "Okay, this experiment is
working."
>> See, it's not always about being
secretive. Sometimes it's about
protecting an artist's humanity and feel
how you feel about artists who play
characters, but one thing is very clear.
They get separation. Meaning that their
audience can very clearly tell this is
the character and this is the person.
Now, I do think that one of the deepest
examples of this archetype actually
belongs to the late great MF Doom.
>> The mask really represents the the whole
like to rebel against the trying to sell
the product as a human being. You know
what I mean? It's more of a sound. So,
you know, and at the same time, you
know, it's something different. You know
what I'm saying? And it fits with the
theme of the rebel, the villain, where,
you know, to him, he don't care about
the fame and all that [\h__\h] That [\h__\h] is
of no consequence. You know what I mean?
It's more of the message of what's being
said. So, I think it helps people focus
more on what's being said. It's still
entertaining. It's still like the
theater and it has the appeal of uh you
know something that could be considered
entertaining but that message is still
there that yo [music] you know villain
represents anybody anybody in here could
wear the mask and be a villain male
female any race so-called race you know
what I mean it's about where you coming
from from your heart you know what I'm
saying like what what is the message
where you got to say you know what I
mean so that's that's mainly why I um
chose to bring the mask into the fold
>> so I think that MF Doom is the blueprint
for a lot of artists that know they want
to play characters and he understood
probably better than most artists that
the industry damn near wants faces more
than they want the music. So what did he
decide to do? Reject the whole system.
And this for me is why I think character
artists are some of the most powerful
artist archetypes because they can
create a world instead of feeling like
they're letting the industry define
their identity. But I can hear y'all
now, Corey. I don't want to play a
character. And I get that this archetype
isn't really for everyone. Some artists
don't want to wear a mask. They want to
actually be seen. And that leads us to
archetype number two, the purist. So the
purist is the artist that wants to be
real. They want to be honest. They want
to be vulnerable. They want to be human.
But that vulnerability comes with a
price.
>> Vulnerability is like it's the greatest
thing and it's the reward is very high.
But the price, you know, it's like
>> the danger is there. Like that fear of
like
>> Yeah. But that's why it's so awesome,
you know,
>> the ability or the opportunity even to
be transparent
>> to allow yourself to be a vessel. You've
realized through your music and people
coming to your shows and talking to you
about your music that you're not alone
and you're doing the same service for
someone who is hearing your music and
your story and you being giving to them
that now they're not alone. I'm trying
to like live out, you know, like hero's
journey. feel like it's actually like
it's like sacrificed to a point because
it's like I'm I really am like I'm
putting my business out there.
>> So, he's right. Being open does build
deep fan loyalty, but it also exposes
you emotionally. So, pierce artists win
because they're relatable, but they also
struggle because they feel everything.
And then you have artists like 21 Savage
who constantly struggle with the real
version of themselves versus the role
that their fans expect them to play.
>> What was the last thing that you
discovered about yourself? that I'm
really a simple person and I really
don't I don't I don't really like to do
much. Like I really like to chill. Like
I have fun. I get excited to go home at
night type [\h__\h] and just play the game
and just chill [\h__\h] Like I don't party.
I don't drink. I don't club. I just like
to just be at home just with my kids
kicking it, chilling.
>> Yeah. Do you feel like that's the season
you heading into come with age? Yeah,
but I be trying to snap out of it cuz
I'm still a rapper and I don't want to
be like dear like old man.
>> You is like
>> Yeah, for sure. That's good though. I
like being like you keep waking up every
day, you going to be too.
>> Now, I think that one line that one
answer to the question asked is so
important, right? He said, "But I'm a
rapper." And this is one of the
downsides of being a purist artist.
Purist artists deal with identity
conflict every single day because fans
want the real you until the real you
doesn't line up with their fantasy of
you. And then there's artists like Siza,
one of the most beloved purest artists
of our generation. And she has shown and
talked about the emotional cost of truly
being yourself in public.
>> I hate being famous. It sucks. I hate
scrutiny. Like I'm still the shy person
from high school. I hate being
perceived. I hate coming outside. I
don't want to party. I don't want
anybody to even look at me. Honestly, I
don't want to take pictures. I hate
being on video. It's the bane of my
existence. It makes me really really
uncomfortable to a way that like like I
cry. I love connecting with people in
the crowd when like I feel like it's
really me and you right now. And I go
eye to eye with so many people during
this show and it's like it's something
about tour that it makes the love like
real.
>> So this is the peers archetype in one
clip. They're often celebrated and
overwhelmed at the same time. And once
again, fans think they want the real you
until the real you is shy or tired or
anxious or angry or god forbid human.
And I think that that's one of the
things that makes being a Pierce artist
so hard is that pierce artists really do
carry the emotional weight and the
emotional baggage of their fan base.
Because if you make music talking about
your life and showing what you're going
through, then guess what? People that
want to talk about their life and what
they're going through are going to want
to interact with you. So then that makes
me think if character artists protect
themselves with a persona and the pierce
artists expose themselves with
vulnerability then what does the in
between look like? And that brings us to
the third archetype, the hybrid artist.
Now the hybrid artist is the one that
understands both worlds. Real identity
plus a creative persona equals success.
Now I think that one of the best modern
examples of the hybrid artist is
Kendrick Lamar. And in this next clip,
he actually explains everything
perfectly. K dot into I guess what we
want to call now Kenny Kung Fu Kenny.
Can you find a distinction point between
those two personas or are they
different?
>> K dot. This is me prepping myself as far
as the lyric for ability and being able
to go in the studio and say, you know
what, I want to be the best wordsmith.
Anybody that gets on this track, I have
to just, you know, analy however that
is, whether it's through rhyme scheme,
whether it's through metaphors, whether
it's just punchlines, whether it's just
word play. And uh I didn't have the the
actual technique of songwriting. And
this where you know this is this is this
the transition where Kendrick Lamar Kung
Fu Kenny I look at Kung Fu Kenny as a
master of the craft now. Now now you
have the ability to make songs and still
have the the the you know the wordsmith
technique and intertwine it and have a
composed mentality on how to approach
music. Now you're just not connecting
with people in the studio or your
homies. You're connecting with people
around the world universally. Now, this
is why I think Kendra Lamar is such a
master hybrid artist because he switches
identities with intention. I mean, he
explained it best himself. Kad
represents the hungry artist who is
looking to destroy the competition by
any means necessary. Whereas, Kung Fu
Kenny represents mastery and an artist
who has taken time to learn and develop
and sharpen his craft. And I think that
if we all got the chance to actually sit
down and talk to Kendra Lamar, I'm
willing to bet that he would explain
that these two sides are really two
sides of how I felt coming up as an
artist. And this is one of the beautiful
things about being a hybrid artist.
Hybrids don't have to choose one
identity. They use these different
identities to express different sides of
themselves. And I think that someone who
takes this even further is DOA. Listen
to her explain how she treats her
personas like storytelling tools.
>> Scarlet is a symbol or [music] a mascot
for the album that represents
transformation and rebirth. The story is
kind of evolving as time passes. Yeah,
it's just a way to symbolize. And I like
there being [music] some sort of
physical symbol. It represents a lot of
things. Pain, vulnerability, and
transformation, [music] and new
beginnings.
>> So, Scarlet Doicat's character isn't
necessarily a different person. It's a
different lens into the world that DOAT
is creating. So, we, the audience, get
to view this world through a different
perspective and a different aesthetic.
And once again, I think that this is why
hybrid artists dominate today. fans get
the authenticity and the world building.
And the thing is, fans aren't stupid.
They can definitely feel the difference.
As a matter of fact, check this clip
out.
>> I really miss when artists used to
release new music or their album and
they would build this entire era around
it. And one of the first people that
comes to my mind whenever I think about
this is Rihanna. It was like whenever
she released a new album, her entire
look and personality would change right
with it. And she did this so good
throughout her career to whereas though
the average person didn't even realize
it was all a marketing strategy just to
sell records. Another good example of an
artist who embodied the eras is Gwen
Stefani. Now yes, a lot of the stuff
that she did in 2004 would be considered
cosplaying today, but when it came down
to a roll out, Gwen Stefani did not play
about her music. And somehow doing these
eras, the hair, the makeup, the music
videos all gave a similar feeling to the
music on the album. And not doing this
is the reason why most artists are not
successful today. Because instead of
consistently throwing new music at us
every other month, how about putting a
little bit more thought behind what you
currently have and then maybe you'll be
able to hold our attention for longer
than a week.
>> And this this is why the hybrid artist
resonates because fans have been saying
it for a long time. We don't just want
music. We want eras and we want worlds
and we want stories and we want
evolution. a lot of the things that many
modern artists are fighting tooth and
nail to have to give to their fan base.
Now, let's take it back to the top,
right? Most artists fail because they
don't know which archetype they are. You
got characters trying to be purists,
purists trying to be characters, and
hybrids trying to be everything at once.
But once you figure out your archetype,
your visuals get easier, your content
gets easier, your story gets stronger,
and your fans stop being confused. And
if you want help figuring out your
archetype and building a world around
it, we actually provide a full world
building guide for artists where we help
them break down their visual identity,
their artist story, and their overall
visual strategy with clarity. So, that's
something that you're interested in, the
link will be in the description below.
But now, I want to hear from y'all.
Which archetype do you think you are?
Are you a character artist? Are you a
purist? Or do you think of yourself as a
hybrid? And if so, why? Drop that in the
comment section below. Other than that,
if you like this video, make sure you
hit the like button, subscribe, share
this with an artist that needs a little
bit of gain today. My name is Corey and
I'll see y'all next