There's this myth in music that if you
really care about your art, you got to
quit your job. But the truth is, most of
your favorite artists either have a 9
to5 or were definitely holding one down,
even through their biggest blowups. And
if you could talk to them, a lot of them
would tell you that that paycheck was
the only thing keeping the dream alive.
So, for today's video, we're going to
get into what exactly it looks like to
balance a job while chasing your music
dreams. But before we get into all that,
if you look below this video, you should
see a join button. Yes, we have launched
our membership space, the Inland
Backstage Pass, where we're going to be
dropping exclusive content, BTS from
videos and interviews, and we even have
some member only live streams planned.
So, if you're interested in that, check
that out. Once again, it should be a big
join button below the video, or you'll
see a link button in the description.
But if there's something that you're not
interested in, then make sure you hit
that like button, share this with an
artist that needs a little bit of gain
today, and let's get into the video. So,
I actually want to start with a story
that shows just how unpredictable the
game can be. Uh, this is Insomniac
Lambs. He's an artist that had a blow up
during the Soundcloud era and he talks
about what the reality of this game
looks like for a lot of artists. Check
this out.
>> Performing at Rolling Loud songs with
Uzi, Playboy Cardi, 21 Savage, music
video on MTV, going tour to tour, going
city to city, being a freshman
candidate, doing all this popping stuff
thinking I'm about to blow up, man. To 5
years later being a [\h__\h] construction
worker, man. You want to talk about a
whole different lifestyle adjustment,
man? Man, I wasn't prepared for none of
that. All the [\h__\h] I was doing, bro,
when my music was popping and going
crazy, for real, I thought I was be I
thought I was about to be out of here. I
thought I was about to be a millionaire,
man. The industry would never really
like gravitate towards me for real.
Like, I remember I was 26 and they told
me that I was too old to get signed. And
this is like at the time when everybody
was getting signed. Like the labels
would just they would not [\h__\h] with me
for some reason. Then my best friend
died like 2 3 weeks before my son was
born. That was weird. But I had to get
used to that cuz me and him was doing
everything together. He was shooting all
my videos. I was going out of town with
him, hitting the road, getting stuff
done, you feel me? Making sure we was
putting on for the brand. Then I really
had to adjust to being the father and
sitting down and putting time into that.
So my mind was just all over the place
cuz I couldn't leave and go do whatever
the [\h__\h] I wanted to do no more. I was
just super thrilled off for like a long
time. But it started feeling like I was
hitting every accolade, doing everything
that I could do by myself and get like
hitting millions of views on songs,
doing [\h__\h] like that. So it just started
getting depressing cuz I was like, man,
I can't keep funing this out my own
pockets. I need the label to take me to
the next level. But labels just wouldn't
[\h__\h] with me. So I was like, man, that
[\h__\h] just started getting depressing,
bro. I ain't going to lie. Hey, don't
get me wrong, when I was doing
construction, I was making like [\h__\h]
70 an hour or some [\h__\h] It was good
money, but I just never could get into
it cuz my I knew what my passion and
what my dream was. My passion and my
dream has always been music. Has always
to been to be an artist. Has always been
to showcase my talent. So, it just felt
like I was wasting my time, bro. That
[\h__\h] really like was [\h__\h] with me
every day. Like, I like, yeah, I'm
making good ass money. I'm coming home
with a nice check every week, but this
[\h__\h] just ain't me. This ain't me.
>> So, the reason that video really hits is
for me, Lamb was an artist that had the
momentum. He had the attention, right?
He was getting the the the calls from
the labels, but he is a proof that just
because somebody has momentum doesn't
necessarily mean that the money is
matching up, right? Or even, you know,
bigger, just because somebody is
streaming crazy once again doesn't mean
that they're rich. If you heard him say
it, he thought that he was going to be a
millionaire because of all the attention
and hype that he was getting at that
time. And actually, I want to show you
guys the Spotify loud and clear report
uh to kind of get a little bit deeper
into into what he was thinking and what
other artists are thinking. And if
you're unfamiliar with Spotify's loud
and clear report, this is something that
they drop once a year where they break
down the economics of artists on the
platform. And they've been doing a good
job of documenting the the rising trend
of artists being able to monetize just
their Spotify catalog, right? Uh so feel
however you feel about Spotify. Like I
said, they've been one of the best in
terms of like documenting uh everything
around it. So, if you take a look at
your screen, you can see they have it
broken down by the amount of artists
that have made x amount of money on the
platform. So, this 10 million bubble is
how many artists have made $10 million
just through their catalog on Spotify.
So, I want to take a look at 50K to 100K
cuz I think that for a lot of artists
when they're first coming up, this is
about the range that you're looking to
hit, right? to be able to just maybe
take care of your life or have a
slightly better life than you were
having when you were working your 9 to5.
So, let's dive in and see what those
numbers are looking like. So, if we take
a look at their 2024 report in terms of
artists that were able to make 50K from
just their spot their Spotify catalog,
we're looking at 22,000 artists, which
if you look at the trend, things have
been growing. And that means that over
time we will start to see more artists
who are able to make that amount. But
when you start thinking about how many
artists are out there in general, what
are we talking about? A couple tens of
thousands or hundreds of thousands of
artists, then that number starts to show
that hey, it's possible, but it's still
not the reality for the vast majority of
artists. And if we take a look at the
100K chart, the number starts to get
even smaller at just 12 a half thousand
people. So once again, throughout music,
we are seeing the trend grow of artists
and and creatives be able to take care
of themselves just off of their music.
And I will give a little bit of the
benefit of the doubt because I I do feel
like we have to make maybe like a 30 to
50% adjustment when we consider the
other streaming platforms that an artist
is streaming on. But once again, this
kind of goes back to what Insomnia
Atlance was saying. He thought he was
going to be a millionaire. And the
numbers are showing that that's still
not going to be the reality even if you
have a hot moment or you are a hot
artist at the time. And if we giving bro
even a little bit more grace, you know,
he was on Soundcloud, I want to say like
around that 2016 to 2018 era. So back
then the number was even smaller of
artists just making 100,000. If we go
back and look at the 50k mark, a little
bit bigger, but still not that crazy. So
once again, when Lamb said he thought he
was going to be a millionaire, the
numbers are showing just how unlikely
that was. Now, I know a lot of you are
thinking, "But Corey, I'm not even
trying to become a millionaire off my
music. I just want to be able to take
care of myself. I just want to be able
to live wherever I'm at. You know what
I'm saying? Maybe even at the bare
minimum. And I want you guys to check
out this video about how many streams it
takes just to be able to hit minimum
wage. Check this out. Wait, quick pause
because a lot of you have been asking,
"How can I work with you guys oneonone?"
And yes, we can run almost any type of
marketing campaign at this point, but
honestly, we prefer working with clients
from a consulting standpoint because we
actually get a chance to deep dive into
their music. We can work on their brand.
We can work on their content strategy.
We can tie it all together into a
marketing campaign. Basically, we can
give you a blueprint on how to grow,
monetize, and win. So, if you're an
artist that's serious about getting
their branding together, their content
strategy together, their marketing
together, and apply for a call with our
country brand agency arm using the link
in the description below. Serious
inquiries only, please, guys. So, if
this sounds like something you need,
once again, hit that link in the
description. And if not, we still love
you anyway. All right, guys. Commercial
break over. Let's get back to the video.
567,000
streams a month is what you need as an
artist to just make minimum wage. Yep.
That's what they just calculated. And it
took them a little bit of a while to
find somebody with like spot on that
amount of streams. And it was somebody
called Allison Moyet. She used to be in
a band called Yas back in the8s I think
it was. I used to listen to them. And uh
she's been a solo artist since. She has
an average of 567,000
streams a month. So Allison Moyet is
making minimum wage. But again, Allison
Moyet has been around since the8s and
had quite a good bit of success back
then. So remember that the next time
you're thinking about your career and
how to gauge all this and where you fit
and what you need to achieve and maybe
re-evaluate the whole picture. 567,000
streams a month every month just so you
can earn minimum wage. Is that worth it?
Is that fair?
>> So you heard it guys. 567,000
streams a month just to be able to make
minimum wage. And that's not a small
number or a small goal to hit. So that
shows you why artists who may have even
super loyal fan bases or even two to
three times that amount of streams
monthly aren't exactly, you know what
I'm saying, about to get [\h__\h] you money
no time soon, right? Like they're not
rich. So I think one of the dangerous
realities of the music industry is that
a lot of big artists aren't talking
about things like this, right? Like
they're not breaking down the exact
amount of money they're making monthly
for the smaller artists to study and
understand. And what I think happens is
that smaller artists will see these big
streaming numbers and assume I just need
to hit that and I'll be rich. I'll be a
millionaire. But music marketer Matt
Bacon breaks down what is the reality
for a lot of the music artists. Even the
ones you're paying attention to. Check
this out.
>> Your favorite musician probably has a
day job. As much as people like to
present as rock stars, most folks, even
those playing to like 500 to a,000
people a night, have a job when they're
off the road. And sometimes that might
be in a creative industry and it's tied
into their music, right? but they still
have to have a job to pay the bills. And
yeah, some folks might say that's cuz
the industry is toxic or whatever. In my
experience, it's just because to have a
successful release, to have a successful
tour, whatever. There's a lot of
infrastructure that needs to go in
place, people that need to get paid,
base expenses you can't do anything
about. And look, there are ways to make
it work and make independent music your
full-time. I know tons of people who've
done that, who made the sacrifices and
found a way. I'm just saying, let's set
the expectation and realize that a lot
of folks you love are working still. And
some of those people would argue having
a job makes their art better because it
means they don't have to sell out and do
what they think is going to be popular
so that they can keep making their art
full-time. I'm not saying that's right
either, just something to consider. So,
don't stress if you're not making a
bunch of money on this yet. There's a
lot less money in this game than people
seem to think.
>> So, what Matt is saying is absolutely
true. You will be surprised at how many
artists have a secret day job, right?
where they're not telling their fans
they have a day job and you know they
may be very active in it to minimally
active but they're using it to make sure
that they can either a supplement the
money they're making from their music or
b kind of like Matt was saying fund the
elements of their rockstar lifestyle and
that kind of goes back to what I was
just saying. I think that that's one of
the most dangerous things about the
music industry is how some artists are
portraying themselves because it makes
the everyday artists, right, the smaller
growing artists think like, hey, like
it's not going to take, you know, a lot
for me to get rich. I just need to kind
of hit this pathway and then make this
amount of streams and I'll be there.
Meanwhile, the artist that you're
looking at that's even making you think
that way, bro, is a consultant down in
Silicon Valley making 200K a year. And
that's how he's able to afford all of
these things to grow his music while
he's maybe making $400 a month, you know
what I'm saying, off of the music. So
yeah, Matt broke it down perfectly. So
many artists, whether you know it or
not, have jobs that they're using to
fund everything. And once again, I'm not
knocking it. I'm very much so a do what
you got to do type of person. I believe
that every artist should keep a job. And
we're going to get into some of those
tips in a second on how you can balance
it. But if you are an artist who's
listening to this and you you feel like
you're not convinced on why you should
keep your job, why you shouldn't call
your manager up and quit right now,
check out this clip from legendary
artist and exec Acon and listen to what
he has to say about it.
>> They feel like once they become an
artist, they don't need a job. You got
to have a job. You need your just get a
part-time job to pay your basic bills.
Phone bill, rent, like just basic. It's
okay to be It's okay to work. We all got
to do it. Nobody going to laugh at you
if you you know flipping burgers. I I
had to I I was I was stocking groceries
at Kroger's before I made it. When I
when I got out, I wasn't getting back to
the streets. But the point is, it's a
responsibility that you have to
understand to accept for yourself that
you have to have a plan A and a plan B.
Your plan A should be your gift,
whatever that is. And it don't everybody
ain't going to be good at music. I don't
care what your friends tell you.
>> Even more so than just being able to pay
for your artist image, right? Like
making fans perceive you a certain way.
You just got to live. One of my favorite
things to tell artists or even clients
that I'm working with is you can't chase
the dream if you're dead or you're
homeless. You know what I'm saying?
Well, I guess I have seen homeless
people chasing their dreams, but you for
sure can't chase it if you're dead. And
so, taking care of yourself, making sure
that you, the artist, survive to even be
able to give us the art is probably one
of the most important steps of blowing
up and becoming an artist. I will argue
at least top three steps. So, if you're
balancing work and music right now, here
are some things that I've seen artists
do to actually make it work. Number one
is going to be find a flexible job. This
could be a remote job, uh some type of
delivery gig, a night gig, something
that allows you to protect their
creative energy and to have some
flexibility to build around the
opportunities that will come to you. A
bonus tip here would be to find some
type of job within the music or the
creative industry, right? A lot of you
guys have other skills outside of being
a music artist. You can mix, you can do
graphic design, you can do video work.
And I think that a dream job for a lot
of artists should be working for another
creative because at least you get to
keep your foot within the music industry
or the entertainment industry while
you're working to figure your thing out.
But if you can't get a job in music,
once again, finding something else that
gives you a lot of flexibility and gives
you, you know, the ability to kind of
leave yourself open for opportunities is
going to be one of the best places to
start. Number two is going to be to use
that paycheck as your first investor.
Now, once you take care of your life and
you get uh, you know, all the things you
need to actually live, then make sure
that you're setting aside some of your
money to be able to do things that help
advance your music career. Because I'm
sure you still need studio time. You
probably need to run some ads. You might
have some visuals you need to pay for.
And I think that building the discipline
and building the balance, you know what
I'm saying, while you're within that,
while still making sure that you can
live and eat and do all that stuff is
going to help you as you get bigger and
as you get more money from your music.
Number three is going to be to treat
music like a second job. Now, don't get
lost in the sauce of that paycheck. You
know, especially some of you guys who go
out there and get jobs where you might
make more money short-term than you will
ever think to see in music. You know who
you are and you guys are out there. But
you want to block out regular hours to
do things like work on content or write
music or record music. And you want to
be just as structured within that
process as you are within your job so
that you can make sure that you're never
losing time to to chase the dream
because you had a work day. Number four
is going to be to leverage the story for
content. Now, this tip isn't for every
artist, but sharing that you have a job
and what you're going through while
working towards achieving your dream, it
humanizes you almost like nothing else
can. I remember a long time ago when
Tiar Wack, uh, this rapper from Philly,
posted a picture on her Instagram
stories of her clocking in to work. That
like damn near broke the internet that
day and in like a positive way, right?
So many people started to share their
stories about how they too were working
at a restaurant or a warehouse or
something like that while having bigger
dreams and bigger aspirations. So, so it
is one of those things that can make
fans root for you. But once again, I
completely understand if it's not for
everybody. And tip number five is to
stay humble and always be ready to
pivot. Now, the music industry is
interesting. It's always changing. You
know, these big impacts come along every
couple of years that shake things up for
everybody. the new people trying to
break in and the people that have been
in it for years if not decades. So even
after a good run, something might happen
that makes you need to go pick up a
shift somewhere again. And to me, that's
not failure. You know what I'm saying?
Like that's showcasing endurance. That's
showing that you really want to make it
and you're willing to do whatever you
got to do to be able to keep going and
going to the next level. And so I know a
lot of these tips weren't, you know, the
most glamorous, but I really do believe
that this is how you build
sustainability in music. This is how you
build your endurance to be able to get
through these things. And [\h__\h] let's
keep it a buck. This is how you build
the money to be able to do stuff to help
you get to that next level. And in an
industry that's as unpredictable as
music is, yeah, you want every security
blanket you can get. The music game
looks glamorous on social media, but
behind every success story is somebody
who had to figure out how to keep the
lights on. So having a job doesn't
disqualify you as an artist, and in a
lot of cases, it's the only reason you
can stay in the game long enough to even
win. So now I want to hear from you
guys. Do you think having a job helps an
artist or do you think it holds them
back? Have you ever had to balance the
two? And if so, what tips would you
share to other artists who are trying to
balance their music dreams and working
their jobs? And if you like this video,
sub up, hit that like button, and make
sure you share this with an artist that
needs a little bit of gain today. I'm
Corey, and I'll see you guys next time.
These