we help artists get billions of streams
on Spotify but the platform has changed
over the years and not enough people are
talking about how you should look at it
today so in this video I'm gonna go over
the three areas that artists asked me
about I'm gonna give you the sobering
truth as someone who has helped multiple
artists grow and has the benefit of
connections to some of these platforms
but also I'm going to end the video by
telling you why I believe this is one of
the best times ever for artists on
Spotify so here's the three areas that
we're gonna go through and it's worth
watching through every single one of
them because it's all going to connect
them you understand the market
holistically like this it'll be hard for
you to get tricked by anybody who's
offering a bad service and two for you
to waste money on the wrong strategy for
your Spotify streams
all right so number one is Bots number
two is play listening and number three
is the Spotify tools and I'll focus on
one in particular but let's start with
Bots many know who've watched this
channel that I'm not all opposed to Bots
and I know most people are like Bots are
so bad Bots are so bad but let me give
context because I feel like some people
are actually taking my advice in the
wrong way so I want to be extremely
clear by starting with this story I'm
talking with an artist probably last
week yeah it was last week and he's
independent he's early starting off and
he signed some artists right he signed
other artists this is an artist who
signed some other artists and he's like
yeah man I was getting a decent amount
of streams I was doing like over five
thousand dollars a month in Revenue but
I got this check and when I got my check
it didn't account for all of my Revenue
Spotify actually shorted me and
immediately in my head I'm like oh Bots
Bots Bots but I don't know if he knows
that Bots might have been included in
his streams right I don't know what he's
been doing so I'm just listening all
right and then he goes yeah so then I
reported it to Spotify basically trying
to make it a case and if I remember
correctly he even got a lawyer involved
and he's making this case against
Spotify Spotify is basically like nah
you know we kind of gave you the right
amount of money back and forth and
ultimately he then hits his distributor
I'm not going to say the distributor's
name because I actually think that they
might have had some case and I just
don't want to put people's name out
there like that right but this is a real
story he hits the distributor all of you
would know it is one of the major
Distributors and they were like uh we
can't really do much about this because
if we go against Spotify in this
particular scenario we're really gonna
risk tarnishing our relationship for all
our other artists and we can't just do
this for this one random artist who you
are no offense sounds a little messed up
right we're not gonna do right by this
one artist because it risked our
relationship with all these other
artists wrong they were in the right
based on hearing this scenario because
buddy was using Bots and our Spotify is
basically like yo look man your guy is
using Bots you can try to stand up for
him if you want to but you know it's
against our policy so that was really
just the distributor being nice right
and then guess what he gets kicked off
of that distributor he get all his
accounts gets closed he ends up on
another distributor and you know what
happened on that other distributor he
got kicked off that other distributor I
think he ends up getting kicked off
maybe three Distributors by the time
we're done with this conversation and
you know kind of stop it and like all
right bro I heard enough ultimately he's
using Bots and he becomes very open
about it and here we are today speaking
about another strategy that he then
again wants to spend like 20K on box and
I have to tell him bruh no why are you
trying to use pot still after you just
told me about two years of struggle
because of this so this is where we get
to the reality of the situation because
I just started with yo I'm not all the
way against bots let me make it
extremely clear I thought I've said this
very clearly Bots make sense for a very
specific set of people right number one
are people who are major label artists
who already have a real fan base and
then there's a couple of scenarios where
they're tweaking using Bots to elevate
their streams but you know why they're
doing this they're not doing it to make
it seem like they have social proof that
that you hear people talk about
they're not doing it for social proof
they're also not doing it just to seem
bigger than some other artist in most
cases there's other incentives there's
the corporate structure of the music
industry where you can play the game
things no the same reason I'll just
leave it at this because I don't want to
spend forever on bikes in this video but
the same reason that artists will
finesse and do things like bundles to
account for more sales to have a higher
ranking on the charts it's similar to
many of the reasons that they would do
things like fake streams even though
they have a huge legitimate audience
I'll just leave that at that right go to
our other videos where we really go
deeper into Bots I'll link it in the pin
comments in the description something
like that all right here's another thing
about Bots for those of you who want to
do box because here's the other type of
person who box kind of makes sense for
it if you are just a hustler and you
aren't a real artist if you've basically
thrown into town said hey I'm never
going to be a real artist I don't want
to focus on doing a real fan base okay I
just want to try to get some streams and
make my money back for those streams
there's better hustles in the world but
cool Bots can make sense for you but if
you are a real artist you want to
actually get a real fan base and you are
independent or more I don't even say
independent because that's actually
wrong there's Independent Artists who
actually do make sense and are using
Bots and it makes sense within the
context of what they're doing can't tell
you where they are but that's not for me
to speak on so a better way of saying if
you're an artist who doesn't have a real
strong fan base it makes zero sense for
you to use Bots all right cool very
strong statement very direct statement
if you are in that bucket do not use
Bots here's the last thing that I want
to add when it comes to using somebody
for their services for Bots the real the
best bot people they make hundreds of
thousands of dollars per client per
client so if you aren't spending
hundreds of thousands of dollars then
you probably aren't even working with
the best bot people now why would those
bot people have clients that are
spending hundreds of thousand dollars on
Bots because again they're working with
major artists major artists you here's
another thing the best bot people the
people who are really doing this like
for real for real you don't know who
they are you just don't why imagine this
if I'm a great bi person well I'm going
to be working with the best of the best
right I'm going to be working with these
clients that are paying me hundreds of
thousands of dollars per client and if
I'm a massive client I'm going to be
working with the best of the best black
people right those two things would make
sense why one from the client side if
I'm a major artist a bigger client who
has that kind of money I want secrecy I
don't want my bot person to be out there
in the world talking I don't want my
person to be someone who's just going to
be in the streets spreading my business
because that puts me on Front Street
yeah you can have consumers speculate
and people like look oh this doesn't
make sense this person is probably using
bikes but the actual pot person would
never put that out there why because
that validates any of the questioning so
me as a client I wouldn't want that and
if I'm a bot person all right I and I'm
working with these type of people why
would I ever put that relationship in
jeopardy when I'm getting paid that type
of money right and then comes working
with smaller artists why would I work
with smaller artists who have left to
lose and are only going to have the
budget to pay me only like a thousand
dollars twenty thousand dollars it
doesn't make sense for me to even risk
it because why would I put my client at
risk why would I work with a client who
could put miris therefore putting my
business and my clients at risk and why
would I waste time doing more work by
working with thousands of artists when I
can make the exact same money working
with like 50 artists none of it makes
sense so you should be able to add that
up if you don't fit the bucket of having
a lot of money or already having a
strong fan base or having really strong
connections to someone who happens to be
using Bots and these are the best of the
best people then you probably don't even
have access to the right people in the
first place you're not just going to be
able to go on IG or Google Bots people
and then look it up and hey here's my
bot service and have the right people
all right that's everything I gotta say
on Bots now let's get to number two and
this is extremely important as well play
listing today has finally found a
realistic positioning right there was
all this hype on play listening and now
the dust is settled here's the reality
of playlisting over time there has never
really been a huge argument for
playlisting in terms of real fans never
not a huge considerable argument where
that should be your primary strategy
doesn't mean that there haven't been
some playlists here some play list there
that have made sense but outside of a
wrap caviar that's been the only
playlist throughout Spotify ai's history
where you can almost look at that
playlist and say that playlist can break
an artist and then you have the second
tier the second tier where playlists
that just happened to be quality and it
happened to be the right artist and the
best case scenario was hey this is a r b
playlist for instance and I'm an R B
artist and it's actually organic and if
I can get on this R B playlist hopefully
my music is actually strong enough where
people hear it and then they repeat it
and then you trigger spotify's organic
algorithm that's the ultimate goal up
out of that right that was the second
tier that second tier it didn't really
get as many results as you would expect
right you would get on the editorial
playlist we've worked with editorial
playlist been on Plenty of editorial
playlists they are great placements
they're valuable they they we we
appreciate them why because it's free
marketing right they're free editorial
quality playlist placement is free but
never have we really seen it as a
massive impact on a campaign where we
say this song went completely viral all
because of editorial playlists and most
artists end up being disappointed at the
impact of editorial playlists which
leads me to the fact that editorial
playlists are even the power anymore I'm
going to give you a gem on that in a
second but let's go to the third level
so we got the cultural impact of a rap
caviar playlist pretty much one of one
then we have the second level which is
editorial and some like third party that
happen to have a moment of time
literally a moment in time that had some
similar level of impact as editorials
and then everything below that which is
vast majority of the market has very
little impact probably built up by fake
streams and mostly has a negative impact
on your actual business because they're
gonna put you in this playlist and then
after you on this playlist because it's
all mixed up you're gonna mess up your
related artist what do I mean by that if
I get on a playlist and then now now I'm
on some random playlist everybody who
actually does listen to my music these
are real people in this particular case
but these people aren't the type of
people that typically listen to my music
and the type of artists that are related
to me on my profile I will be able to
see what my relatives look like and now
I have a bunch of randos who make no
sense for my music meaning Spotify
doesn't even correctly know how to place
me within their algorithm so I'm not
gonna even be put in front of people who
could be my fans because I'm being
compared to these artists that are not
related to me that's a huge impact of a
lot of bad playlisting but now here
comes the reality of it all Spotify
themselves have noticed that this whole
playlisting thing
it's not what we wanted to be when we
started right we actually see better
impact from release radar and discover
weekly those two playlists that don't
have anything to do with meeting some
magical person behind the scenes and
we've known some of these magical people
who've had connections to some of these
magical people who are going to get me
on this editorial playlist right these
great people who actually are fans and
really love music those playlisting
people are great the ones who work at
Spotify but when they put you on there
you're not going to see that impact and
Spotify even start a CEO the impact is
just not moving and it's easier to scale
the algorithmic playlist so they've saw
more results in the algorithmic playlist
and you know what Spotify has been
laying people off right A lot of it they
try to speak on as podcast related
layoffs but hey last November they got a
couple of playlist editors out of there
as well some people who had that
influence and that's what a lot of these
big companies do they'll do these big
layoffs and then they'll throw in some
other people that they don't want you to
quite understand and then they'll use
that opportunity to lay off some other
folks that have nothing to do with the
primary narrative they're pushing that
way they don't scare people when they
start questioning well how come you were
laid off all these people in the
playlist in department or how come you
laid off all these people in the XYZ I'm
just making something up right in that
example because once that arises that
leads to some other questions that need
answers right but we know multiple
people who had their playlist in person
taken out of the game no longer at
Spotify because when you think about
things like AI if AI is becoming more
and more of a thing how valuable are
these physical bodies do we really need
that many people to be in charge of play
listing when you think about Spotify AI
radio I can't remember the name of it
the DJ or whatever I can't think of the
name right now but that's another chip
at the human capital of needing a
playlist and this is where we get to
number three and the most important of
Spotify tools right now that is changing
the game and that is discovery mode
discovery mode is changing the game and
people aren't saying it loud enough yet
so let's speak on that in the context of
everything I just talked about in this
video I just had a client homie hit me
saying yo Sean we're at 50 000 daily
streams on Spotify because of discovery
mode and he's not a new case I've heard
this story again and again of a massive
booth in your streams and monthly
listeners because of discovery mode and
why is this so important what is
discovery mode discovery mode is
something that you can have access to
now I know a lot of people are just
hearing about it a little bit more but
we first heard about discovery mode
probably a year and a half because of
the conversations we've been able to
hear about right but it wasn't for for
us to say back then and it was only it
was super super limited it went from
internal Spotify super selective and
then it became a few Distributors had
access and now there's individual
artists when I say my client homie I'm
talking about their unsigned completely
independent have no Connections in the
industry in that particular way and Bam
they have access to discovery mode
massive boost in their streams because
they said hey Spotify will collect 30
percent less off of our royalties and in
exchange for you taking that 30 from us
you are going to put us as one of the
songs that becomes up next when people
you know listen on Spotify right that's
a pretty short and sweet way of saying
what's going on with discovery mode how
it works great tool here's why it's so
powerful yet again this is way better
the results that I've seen from
discovery mode is way better than
anything I've ever seen from the
editorial playlist and you know what you
didn't have to talk to a person to get
it done you didn't have to play politics
to get it done you didn't have to have a
distributor to get it done so that takes
the Distributors power right there
because many of these Distributors their
loan power today was hey yeah we can
just do what distro kid does and
tunecore does and put you on Apple music
Spotify and all the other dsps but we
also got playlisting connections so
that's why you're coming to us you're
coming to us to get that playlist in
connection Cloud because you know distro
kid CD Baby they're not gonna do that
for you well hey distrokid artists have
discovery mode we'll get deeper into how
you can get discovery mode in a second
but imagine that you don't have to do
any politicking you don't need any of
those types of connections to have
access to discovery mode there are so
many artists that we work with who are
doing discovery mode and none of them
have any label they don't have a manager
and many of them are using the typical
Distributors that puts the power back in
your hands especially when it comes to
Spotify far more than it ever has but
look at this this is what I love about
discovery mode a lot of y'all have been
talking about that music right the music
is great all this marketing having to
run ads doing this content all of that
stuff is repulsive I just want to spend
time on my music and get that thing
Listen to I get it right or the
beautiful thing about discovery mode is
it's just the music you put your music
out there and people become fans of you
strictly through the music they're
judging you strictly off the music
that's one of the best marketing tools
out there when it comes to being an
artist and marketing yourself as a
artist specifically your actual product
I don't know anyone better than that
actually right now when I try to think
of it so discovery mode is a great
opportunity for those artists who said
hey my music is the thing I really can't
do this content stuff all right and then
you add the facts that you don't have to
do any
politicking to get access to it that's
great it's a beautiful thing but how do
you get discovery mode let's speak on
that and then I'll give you my final
strategy that you should be using to
grow on Spotify going forward all right
here's what Spotify says you may be
eligible for discovery mode if your
artist team meets all of the following
requirements you have at least three
tracks that meet the track eligibility
criteria below which will go into that
criteria secondly you have at least 25
000 monthly listeners we found the
discovery mode works best with an
audience of this size or above and then
thirdly you have an active Spotify for
artist team that's registered in one of
the countries below Africa Asia Europe
North America Oceana which is Australia
or New Zealand or South America all
right so you know if you're in one of
those countries but let's go back up to
you have at least three tracks that meet
the track eligibility criteria below
what are those criteria a track is
eligible if a participating licenser is
the distributor of the track which is
currently amused are you using CD Baby
CMD shift Dance all day actually never
heard of that one distro kid emu bands
stem United Masters Venice music and
video all right now look some of these
Distributors are a little bit more
relationship based in terms of getting
access to them but CD Baby easy United
Masters easy distrokid easy those are
all a layup to begin using so if you
want access to discovery mode and you
don't have any of these you can easily
get access to CD Baby District kit or
United Masters secondly the track has
been released on Spotify for at least 30
days and then thirdly the track has been
streamed in radio or autoplay in the
last seven days now keep in mind this is
still relatively new in terms of the
amount of artists that have access to it
and criteria so they'll probably be
evolving this over time right changing
some of the criteria maybe they take
something out maybe they add something
in but it's not that hard it's not that
hard here's the thing you need to pay
attention to right 25 000 monthly
listeners now let's get back to strategy
because
you know your distributor whoever you
use bam easy go check that box the
country that you're in Easy check that
box you don't live in the right country
go move whatever but you can do that
right that's very easy to be able to
check that box the hardest thing that is
a part of this criteria is getting 25
000 monthly listeners so what does this
bring things back to one if you're using
Bots they're not gonna count those
monthly listeners they know what's up
you're not going to get this discovery
mode for that two play listing
you can try to hack your way to getting
25 000 monthly listeners with
playlisting but again you're probably
risking having Bots and not even knowing
it and again let's go back to the guy at
the beginning of this video he got
kicked off Distributors you don't want
to put yourself in that type of
relationship with the Distributors and
now you got your name messed up nobody
wants to work with you anymore because
you've been on playlists that have been
using Bots or you've just been outright
using Bots he was doing both because he
thought he was being mindful by the way
going under the radar based on spotify's
criteria they use to try to watch if
you're using Bots but I'm not gonna get
into that so what does this mean though
if you need to have 25 000 monthly
listeners if you can get to at least 25
000 real monthly listeners how would it
not be extremely powerful than to be
able to use discovery mode to boost
yourself up even more yes that's one of
the best things you can do for yourself
right now so let me walk you through my
thought process and what we've been
seeing artists do one we've used the
same methods whether that's through
content whether that's through
advertising whether that's through
influencers the same typical methods
that are tried and true and you don't
hear people not talking about them
anymore and they're still around because
they actually work they're not one of
those trans people keep saying for a
period of time and then they disappear
they're tried and true they all work and
if you can at least get yourself to 25
000 monthly listeners and then follow
the rest of the criteria as well
especially the individual track criteria
that's the second tier in terms of these
streams right but you follow that and at
least get to that point once you're able
to use discovery mode you're gonna get
over another 20 000 monthly listeners if
you have solid product right they want
to basically use this criteria to
determine do you have a solid product or
not and then once you have a solid
product which is music then it's no
problem to be pushed out to the rest of
the world right but they don't want to
push bad music and mess up the discovery
mode algorithm for everybody so do great
content we've gotten hundreds of
millions of streams literally just off
of artists posting organic content using
our methods or run ads we've seen
millions of streams come directly from
ads people triggering the algorithm
running ads and then influencer
campaigns y'all know it influence this
campaign can do to make a song go viral
figure out how to get your streams up
from that alone and get yourself in a
position to be eligible for discovery
mode when you are eligible for discovery
mode then
it should be hard for you to get under
25 000 monthly listeners again once you
start activating that and if you stay
consistent that's it all right get
yourself in a position to be able to use
discovery mode should be your strategy
for Spotify specifically right now get
yourself in a position and then use it
if you think it makes sense that's a
whole nother video in terms of why it
might make sense numerically and how you
should look at it as a long-term
strategy I'll do that and put that here
somewhere like we'll do a conversation
about that but I have not seen a better
time on Spotify for artists that you can
have direct access to the real
without having connections a huge amount
of money or worrying about fake stuff
that's gonna mess you up anyway that's
it for this video let me know your
comments and thoughts in the comment
section below and if you want to see a
video about something else drop those
comments as well peace