what makes an artist great and how much
can a label or management team do for an
artist in a very real way today we're
going to talk about pushing the button
what it actually looks like and play
some clips which we haven't done in a
while on this pod to give y'all an
extreme breakdown of how you should be
moving today I'm brand man Sean and I'm
Cory and this is yet another episode of
no latest
necessary all right before we talk about
pushing the button that uh proverbial
button that will help taking artists off
every artist wants that moment in time
every artist wants we got to have we got
to have a deep conversation about
Artistry first to set the tone y'all
watch all this it's going to connect but
we got to play this is not possible for
an artist to be a success h no didn't
would you say that again I said it is
not possible for an artist to be a
success thank
you would you hold up I just want to
know what's going through your mind when
you hear this statement it's not art
possible from an artist to be a success
we're talking about James bwin Maya
Angelo greates saying this and she seems
to be completely affirmative before we
go further what like what you think he
gonna say I think I think I know where
he going I think he's taken it to an
artist can't be a success because an
artist's job is to push against or find
things that the people don't know they
like yet and in order for you to be a
success that means you've kind of not
necessarily mastered but you productized
some things in a certain way to appease
people hold that thought let's see what
he say think of yourself as a success
you finished foret because you know what
I find is that you begin to believe your
own publicity you begin take your
identity from other people from
something else and you stop
experimenting because somebody says well
the when you did so and so that was such
a success why don't you do that again
all right so it alludes to what you said
but it goes into a different bag of it
right so you talked about priorization
which is so much so it's a science all
right you have the Arts and the science
blowing an artist up and leaning into
the great side of them that we've
discovered is a science so the Artistry
is the experimentation and finding of
the bag that will blow that the groove
that will take off but once you lean
into that Groove now we in the science
bag once we're creating song after song
to lean into the sound that you have
created there is a sense of science
especially if we're doing it
specifically
to find more success to create the next
hit right yeah so I think obviously
that's what what you're alluding to kind
of leans into but what he talks about is
much more of an identity aspect of it
too right buying into your own hype and
obviously of course stopping
experimenting because of that that which
of course leans into what you're talking
about so it's like being an artist is
the experimentation process but how do
we how do we reconcile what he said with
I don't know Kanye West yeah successful
that's what I was thinking man like you
know I would love to know what what he
thought about the concept of the
starving artist in general does he feel
like that's a path of like yo as an
artist you're supposed to want to walk
that you know what I'm saying live it
breathe it until the day your your your
fingers with away or yeah like that's
that's where it feels like he's at right
he believes the artist have to walk that
lane because I I think that I think that
and to his credit I do believe a lot
more artists think that success comes
from their creativity or I want to say
like that but I I think there are a lot
more artists who believe
that
artists don't compromise on like their
sound or certain things in order to
sometimes like get a hit or get a
certain level of success right like
perfect example like that clip we were
watching before the Pod where Young Thug
talked about the camil Cabello situation
right I think that's a great song I
think it's a great song from we should
find that clip and play that real quick
yeah I try to yeah I try to find it um I
think it's a great song I think it's a
great verse from from Young Thug do I
think that you know what I'm saying like
he wasn't putting his artisticness into
it or or trying from his lens you know
what I'm saying to create the best thing
he can make for that situation and I
don't think that but he said it himself
like hey this was a this was just a play
you know what I'm saying like this was a
play that people around me were able to
see and so sometimes we see things from
the front end I think you know I think
sometimes we
confuse a good product with a heartfelt
product if that makes sense you know
what I'm saying yeah I know I know
exactly what you mean I know just
because I like it doesn't mean that all
of that person's Artistry went into it
yeah or just because it's good doesn't
mean that it came from a pure place
place right right right right it might
just trigger certain things in me Etc
but I think because we need to play this
Thug clip just so people can have this
context I think what he's saying here um
is the identifying with us with
success all right means you identify
with that formula or you're you're
stagnant right you have no reason to
continue to explore your job is to be in
constant exploration it doesn't mean you
can't win and make money I don't think I
think he's saying so I don't think it's
all about being a starving artist I
think it's
about making sure you are all you stay
moving and as long as you stay moving
and you're not resting on your laurels
on the plateau then you can still be an
artist which is a Pursuit not a and
success is a state there we go like art
is a Pursuit you continue to find that
new Edge new version of yourself new
sound Etc but success is a state and
which leaves out any version of uh a
need to continue on but it doesn't
necessarily even consider the outer
world of success and money I don't think
that's what he's talking about I think
it's more of a like identity and once
you identify yeah I'm a success then
like where does the rest of the hunger
go now I'm sure some artist might
disagree with this or whatever but I
think it's hard to disagree with his his
what he actually means maybe you're like
I don't know I could be a success and
still like Kanye he does continue to try
new [\h__\h] mhm yeah maybe it's an idea you
can't be both at the same time like
maybe you're like today I'm success and
I'm talking my stuff but then the next
day when you're in actual artist mode
you have to get rid of the success hat
you get what I'm saying and go deep into
the failure the experimentation that
then creates maybe your next successful
moment but again you're not the the
success yeah I can see that I can see
that where's the thug clip oh yeah I
just found it I don't care about clout I
don't care if I never get a number one
song I just love doing music I had a
song in my email for 6 months oh no it
got to the point where somebody in my
team I told my mom like yo tell this
[\h__\h] to do this my mom like son can you
just do me I'm like What's Up M can you
please just do the song did you get
Grammy for that glad I'm saying man it
was a play for this man man you know
what I'm saying like I think it I think
it was a play for his team once he got
in there I think he probably he found
his moment yeah he felt it yeah yeah he
felt it yeah but hearing what he said
though I just love music and I feel like
thug actually has moved that way in his
career like he's had moments where he
could have been like hot and then he
took a step back got in his artist
executive bag Etc then came back still
was able to do what he did um but I I
think that comes from that same spirit
so I don't got to even dissect it but I
think that that definitely continues
that same thought of all right being the
artist and being being the success are
two different things because somebody
else could easily just say oh well
that's a play that's a song I'm just
going to continue to act in that way and
become successful but the artist side of
it is a different set of decision making
yep yep let me stop and tell you
something simple if you've gotten views
on social media and streams on Spotify
and the dsps but you don't know who your
fans are you're doing it wrong you got
to use forever fan forever fan is the
simplest way to take people from views
and streams to regular fan and then
forever fans who will spend money on you
and that's the whole point of this game
right no one cares about having a lot of
numbers on social media and dsps anymore
The Jig Is up we know that could be
hacked but having real fans who will
spend money on you and show up in the
real world and then having forever fans
who will make sure you never go out of
business as an artist is the name of the
game so go to Forever fanm music.com sln
labels to get access to the software and
strategies that we've been using to help
our clients make thousands of dollars
and even hundreds of thousands of
dollars to the point that we've now
collectively made Indie artists
specifically well over a million dollars
with this one idea create forever fans
again go to www. Forever fanm music.com
labels or check the link in the
description if there is one and use
these strategies before the major labels
finally catch up and start to saturate
the game forever fanm music.com
laabs back to the episode all right now
let's talk about what it looks like to
become that
success from the marketing side this is
La Reed a legend in music industry as an
executive but he was an artist and
producer at one point in time as well
talking about his first encounter in the
old days when it comes to pushing the
button we put out a single Arista our
joint venture Partners put out a single
it was doing okay so I went to Clive
Davis and I said
Clive like I need you to push the button
on this thing man you know he said
what's the button I said you know like
you did for Whitney Houston like I need
you to push the button anyway Whitney
Houston comes on stage and Whitney
Houston
sings and he looks at me he said that's
the
button all right already right there
like he's separating and saying Talent
on one part or also I guess the song she
was singing he didn't say what song she
was singing but that alone should be a
good thing for artists to hear it's like
okay wow my talent does matter this is
back in the old days I want context La
is going to talk a little bit more but
like we're talking about the record
label if I'm a record label and I just
have a button why don't I push it on
infinite amount of artists even the old
days record labels had artists that
didn't that did fail when they were
doing all the work not today we know
they don't do work like that but that
they were doing the work back in the day
100% right and things were breaking
because of them so I always stand on
this as an artist I mean as a on the
marketer side yes we can put all the
money in it we can do everything and it
doesn't mean more money might won't make
your song perform better and it doesn't
mean that money resources won't make a
song do better than it should do
but it's gonna be a
ceiling like
if perfect example remember I showed you
the song remember I showed you that song
that had a million Tik Tok videos
created to it oh yeah but it only had
about a million streams yeah you do that
to a hit song or a a great song 10
million easy 10 million streams minimum
absolute minimum you have a million
videos created to it honestly it's way
more than 10 million prob like closer
like 30 closer to 30 across platforms
probably 70 million streams and we're
not even talking about getting into
additional efforts to make sure it
continues to like get
seen but a million videos and a million
streams said oh there was a trend that
caught on to this part of the song
people liked copying that particular
thing but when they went to hear the
song
they said uh I don't need to listen to
this again yeah that simple right like
so if you think this push the button
thing you feel like you you
misunderstand the gaps and and why one
song can go further than another song
yes you can put a lot of resources into
something but all right track be Beckham
back it up we only got like 200,000
videos created to that song Maybe
300,000 that song I don't even know what
it's at right now 7.2 million streams
yeah 7.2 million streams to try to be
and back it up we only had two to
300,000 videos Spotify this is Spotify
alone Spotify alone versus another song
only having a
million uh streams with a million videos
created to it that is the perfect
example of no matter what you do you
can't force a song that doesn't hit now
even if you don't like a song but it
goes crazy
well that just means the song wasn't for
you I feel like a lot of times people
will say well look at that song well
maybe it's not for you but obviously it
did hit for somebody there were people
who liked it so to me that that's
different and that's what people try to
do to kind of like combat the button
conversation was like no but that was
trash H even if it is objectively trash
sometimes trash hits like a good joke
like a good meme so it's still we're all
H having the same joke in of it self
like I'm not saying this is a trash
thing but when uh T chain say it's your
birthday it's your birthday and the way
he does it in the song like it's fun
we're all beyond the quality of music or
not and production it's just fun for
people to do she got a big booty so I
call her Big Booty like people are
having fun in that moment Rebecca Black
it's Friday objectively trash but people
are singing about like having fun making
fun of how trash the song actually is
right so like it's still hitting for
some reason and but you can't make a
song that doesn't hit or connect in some
way do that you just can't yeah well you
you can force it and get uh a you know
every stream or every interaction could
be paid for it could be all artificial
but you're never going to have that roll
roll uh that Snowball Effect where
something really takes off if it doesn't
connect in some in a real way yeah
pushing the button without the right
song attached to it just feels like you
just wasted a lot of money objectively
right cuz you could have elevated in
certain ways you know what I'm saying
maybe more career opportunities can like
there there could be benefits for
attempting to push the button but not
getting the the desired effect of the
button that everybody wants you know
what I'm saying but most of the times
what it feels like man I just Dro insert
large amount of money here and I ain't
go crazy and now I'm out in a certain
large amount of money right like that's
what it feels like and yep as the people
Froning these budgets I can't I can't
knock labels for not even wanting to
attempt to push the button on every
artist but then also I do think the
button has changed I think that his
era his era was an ERA where like all
aspects of distribution and and
marketing were really well controlled by
like a handful of entities right so
pushing the button for them meant that
hey we now give you access to everybody
to be able to see it yeah I would argue
today you know what I'm saying like I
will argue with label artists today
especially that their labels push micro
buttons all the time you know what I'm
saying just it's like me yeah it it
doesn't have the same impact because of
the way people receive it and just to be
real it's it the button used to be big
and expensive and then we had to hold on
to it now the buttons are smaller less
impactful but smaller buttons that we're
a lot more willing to push micro buttons
is a good way to say it and I think
nobody cares about a micro buttton they
don't from an artist side I get it like
dang bro like you're supposed to make me
go far and they're up there beep okay I
can step through that door yeah you know
that doesn't have a same effect
everybody wants the big button you know
what I'm saying but the the reality of
it is is the market has changed yes but
I also think that when you know what the
button supposed to do which a lot of
artists don't necessarily right that's
when you feel a disappointment like you
said from R in like I know when I did
this or when I put this amount of re
sources that song went to 100 this one
only went to two or three like ah but on
the artist side they're seeing still way
more streams than a typical artist y
here's the thing that you're missing
artist though that you don't want to
ever be in this
situation all right let's just pretend
the button cost a million dollars I'm
just saying a big number but the button
could be 100,000 500,000 Etc whatever
that button is let's just say we got a
button bam hit that button it's a
million
dollars if the song isn't that
song that means that song might not make
that million dollars back but if you're
in a deal you just spent a million
dollars so you shouldn't want that
button pushed on that song either yeah
you get what I'm saying yeah like
because now that you're just further in
debt harder to get out that deal versus
oh they put a million dollars in I just
recouped I just started making some more
money back matter of fact I got mailbox
money the grandkids gonna have something
to eat off of that's the difference when
we talk about what he's trying to say
with Whitney Houston You know what I
mean versus you know just doing it why
why well why Clyde Davis apparently
didn't want to do it for his song
whatever his song was I don't even know
what song he was talking about let's
hear a little bit of what he says and
actually no I'mma ask you a question
after I play a little bit more of this
oh so what you telling me my [\h__\h] is not
hot oh and cuz I thought I really did
think like you know record labels they
take Talent good bad or indifferent and
they push the button yeah and [\h__\h] goes
right that's what I thought so Clyde
push the button this button that we've
all heard about
button sit down right here young man let
me teach you something and then I saw it
I was like
oh I get it now and I thought I knew mhm
mhm all right so yeah he goes on to
speak more on like how things look more
when a a talent picking side etc etc but
this is somebody who's been an artist
all right been in a band written
executive Legacy career done all seats
and he's saying this so I just want to
put that note out there for people who
do not know here's my question do you
believe people could be tricked to
liking songs that they don't like 100% I
definitely think I I personally I
wouldn't say I was tricked into liking
it but I can think of songs that I
started out not liking that after I
heard it enough times or saw it enough
times I wouldn't say I I I I came to
love it but I was I was much funer of it
okay and I I
disagree I don't think I don't think
people could be tricked in the liking
songs they don't that they like they
don't like you saying I liked it and it
was unlocked you liked it and you were
unlocked you were yes you got unlocked
they they they gave you some foreplay
you know what I'm
saying and slowly next thing you know
you ready for it see all this is what I
think that people get wrong and I we
like to throw that statement out there
right that uh you know you just play it
a million times and people like it now
you can get stuff stuck in people's head
yeah right by playing a million times
for sure but we talk about actually
liking a
song yes there are songs that I didn't
immediately like but we also have to
realize the same idea where we here that
if you just ask people what they wanted
they would have just said they wanted a
new horse instead of getting the cars
created to me that just might be
expanding somebody's taste your taste
wasn't used to that your current taste
didn't like that song but as you got
more exposure you did like the song you
got warmed up to it you start to realize
there are some elements that I can
appreciate and the reason I know that
this is a thing is because there are
some songs that I've heard a billion
times and I hate and I hate every single
time I hear I hate it more that's a song
that you really don't like a song that
there's just taste Gap you have to
understand and acquire that taste I get
that's all and now you see what there's
there is to appreciate I don't think you
can force somebody to like a song that
they really hate bro CU again are there
songs that you heard a million times
that you hate yeah probably if I thought
hard enough about it yeah give me one
that's I'm trying to think a song that
I've heard a million times that I hate
it's kind of Niche but I I am not the
biggest fan of of all I want for you is
Christmas all I want for you this you
called that n what cuz the holiday I
know it's the biggest holiday song but
it's holiday song everybody know it
though that's not like I thought you
about to say some [\h__\h] that I don't know
everybody like I appreciate it I respect
carries all I want for Christmas is you
you hate it I I do hate it every single
time you every single year you like the
Grinch about to come God damn it it's
Christmas time bro it's crazy like
perfect example you know you heard that
a million times and you still hate my
whole life really I had my whole life to
grow to hat
it so just think about that and I think
again there's a lot of stuff all right A
lot of people objectively love um
Kanye's uh what was that again 808 and
heartbreak 808 and heartbreaks but then
a lot of people hated that at first so
why do we say oh that was actually good
music and that was and yeah people
actually do like that versus saying no
that was just some trash that got pushed
on us people were selected with
that uh I don't know man it was so much
hate for it at the time I feel like I
feel like the people that loved it
appreciated and raved about it for years
but I really feel like the album as a
whole is just starting to get his
appreciation like last I argue like five
years that's just some super lover stuff
yeah like nobody feels like that man
come on now that's I'm bro I'm telling
you you feel like people are starting to
appreciate it as much as you appreciate
it that's what you said I'm saying but I
I was there bro I remember bro [\h__\h]
was not [\h__\h] with that's my point but
but they do love it more and it got it
got a lot of claim appreciation
acknowledge it 100% that that's my whole
point like but we don't look at it as
that like you say hey y'all still got
ways to go that's what you're saying
yeah basically yeah
but but nobody got tricked into loving
it like maybe you were closed-minded to
good music and you just didn't know that
that that lane exist and you didn't how
to react you didn't know what to do with
it some people hear stuff and if they
can't play it in the club they don't
know what to do with it there's a lot of
artists like that I learned last
year yeah it's last year now I learned
last year how many people don't even
understand and know good music and
especially if it just doesn't have a
certain type of of Bop I'm not gonna go
into the details of how because I don't
want to bring that conversation up right
now you know people get distracted but a
lot of people don't
understand what good music is if it's
not a certain wave a lane know what to
do with this and I could play this in
the environment that I tend to go in
whatever that that is so then it's like
you don't know what to if you don't know
what to do with it and how to react and
absorb
it there's no utility and I think more
consumers think that way than we realize
it's like all right can I play this at
the party or can I play that when I'm
out there with my girls or can I talk to
this or can I play this in a strip club
La re said some um this about black
music he was like we are now looking at
these boxes and putting our music into
these boxes can it be played in these
environments and which is keeping us
from creating whole genres like we did
when we created Rock chz etc etc right
versus people just looking at the music
for the music yeah and then you know
figuring out where to play it or find a
new environment so I don't know man I
think I call cap on all music being able
to be forced on people and all of a
sudden like okay it's trash it's bad and
same thing for pushing the button again
if you push the button we know on the on
the wrong song people will not absorb it
yeah and actually man I want to take my
answer back too man I'm sorry I hated on
the queen man I just thought about you
want to hate on a different song cuz
hate still out there like what are you
taking back I don't understand yeah no
no yeah you're right the hat is still
out there but I I feel like a better
answer for that for me would be I
personally just got into Nirvana like
maybe lit like a week ago I just came to
respect them artistically and their
music you know saying know they you know
amazing y great songs you know what I'm
saying I think about where I was in life
when somebody first tried to get me to
listen to song it just it it wasn't
going to go it didn't fit in your life
box fit in my life exactly it didn't it
didn't fit my worldview my music tastes
at the time then for some reason man it
came on my Spotify radio actually know I
was playing this game like this game
where you like oh your video
games see and part of that's a good way
to think about it too because stuff will
catch you off guard when you when you on
video games you know it'll be playing
and it gets it does get caught in your
head a little bit more but now that you
know it and you're more familiar now
you'll listen to it for what it is and
actually it was two things it was I
played it in the game because the game
is called like Moon Rider or some [\h__\h]
and then there was this kid on Tik Tok
that had made um I can't think of the
guy's name but he's like this black guy
he does like what people hear when they
hear like a certain artist song and he
did them and I was like man that [\h__\h]
kind of f like he kind of he kind of
snapping on this and it made me go
listen to the song and I was like damn
the BR kind of f bro like I M unlocked
it finally opened up cuz probably in a
video game you weren't your whole
experience wasn't just about the music
so you were able to like not over judge
and overthink it exactly that's what it
was man so again and Nana is another
great example cuz yeah for sure like
there's a lot of people who hate entired
dramers and things and just this but
your taste just isn't there you don't
have no place for it in your life and
that's fine that's fine and I know
there's some music where you're like
yeah this is so Poppy and it has to be
considered bad music and just there
because it's forced on people no man
there's just people think it's amazing
there's just some people who purely
think is amazing and I know that sucks
maybe that's a worst thought to know
that no people genely just love this
[\h__\h] that might be the worst thought but
but yeah but the the trying to validate
music being pushed on you by saying oh I
didn't like it at first no that's just
the evolution of your taste bro and you
didn't realize how close-minded you were
yeah yeah I can take that there we go
now we got time for this last clip no we
don't even need that time this is yet
another this is yet another episode of
nol was necessary I'm R and I'm Cory and
we out peace