Most artists today are still playing the
game like it's 2010. Drop music, hope it
blows up, maybe pray for an editorial,
and then hope that the A& artist been
flirting in your DMs, reaches out about
a deal. But here's the truth. Attention
doesn't equal money anymore. And the
artists who will actually win in the
next 5 years, they're not playing the
game like normal artists. They're artist
creator hybrids. So ones who make music,
but they play the game and move like a
content creator. So, in this video, I
want to show you why that matters, why
it's going to become increasingly more
important, and why if you're an artist
playing the game the regular way, then
you're already behind. Now, the reality
is that a lot of artists have an
audience, but they're not making any
income. As a matter of fact, this clip
perfectly captures that.
>> How [\h__\h] long do I have to keep doing
this [\h__\h] to make money off of this
[\h__\h] bro? I have 100,000 [\h__\h]
followers on Instagram. I have 50,000
followers on Tik Tok. Nobody want to
give me money. I don't want to start an
Only Fans. My music career is [\h__\h]
trash. I have 40 [\h__\h] monthly
listeners. What the
>> man shot was hurt. Now, this is the
reality for a lot of artists, right?
Like, you can have the numbers, but if
you don't own the relationship with your
fans or if they don't feel that
relationship, and a lot of times the
money you're making doesn't really match
the numbers that you're showing people
on socials. And as far as I'm concerned,
that means you're not even really in the
music business. Now, we've known for a
long time that followers don't always
equal checks. And we're starting to
learn that just because someone is
getting a lot of streams, that doesn't
always equal a lot of money as well. And
we're all starting to see that the old
artist model just doesn't convert as
well as it used to. And it's definitely
not helping artists build sustainable
businesses anymore. And of course, you
know what I'm saying? Haters and
detractors are going to say, "Bro, just
get some more streams. Like, shut up and
just focus on playing the streaming
game." But in reality, here's what that
looks like. 567,000
streams a month. 567,000
streams a month is what you need as an
artist
to just make minimum wage. Yep. That's
what they just calculated.
And it took them a little bit of a while
to find somebody with like spot on that
amount of streams. And it was somebody
called Allison Moyet. She used to be in
a band called Yas back in the 80s, I
think it was. I used to listen to them.
And uh she's been a solo artist since.
She has an average of 567,000
streams a month. So Allison Moyet is
making minimum wage,
>> hundreds of thousands of streams a
month, millions of streams a year just
to hit minimum wage. And this is minimum
wage in the US. So, I don't know exactly
how it translates to you non US
listeners and watchers, but yeah, that's
what you're looking at just to be able
to live off of the music. And most
artists will never see those types of
numbers, which means that most artists
are already playing a losing game. But
some artists have figured out a smarter
way to play. Now, Lar Russell is about
to say it best. Music isn't your only
product once your life becomes content.
>> I've been um documenting my life lately.
Like all of my conversations, all of my
deals, everything. And all of that is
content. It's like it's all it's all
every time you say something special is
content. And I've been trying to
condition my [\h__\h] to see it like that.
Like the way the life that you live is
content. You're going to do something
special in a day. Like us having this
conversation is special. That's content.
That's something that somebody may see
and be like, "Oh [\h__\h] that inspired
me." Right? So when you start looking at
everything is content. People just
content is just like a trigger word for
people. It make [\h__\h] scared or feel
like they looney tuned. It's a, you
know, it's weird, but it's like, [\h__\h]
when you embrace all of it as content,
you no longer have to go make content.
You just live.
>> So, this is the hybrid mindset, right?
Artists who make music and they're still
chasing a lot of the traditional things
in the music infrastructure, but outside
of that, they're really moving like
content creators. They document their
journey. They give people reasons to
care. They build community. They
monetize aspects of their personality
and their lifestyle. This is the new
blueprint. So instead of waiting for a
label to come change their life or a
playlist to finally get their songs to
motion, they go out and create their own
momentum. And the crazy part, this isn't
even just theory at this point. It's
actually been proven to work. And this
next clip is a perfect example of that.
You don't need millions of streams to
make money. You just need some real
fans. Check this out. I made as much
money as Tiger's highest streaming song
on his recent album with only a thousand
monthly listeners. Tiger song did three
million streams, which is roughly
$15,000. So, how was I able to make
three times that amount with .004% of
his monthly listeners? And it's by
building a tight-knit community, but
it's not as easy as that. I spent 2
years essentially doing Twitter spaces
every single day building this
community, making people fall in love
with me for me rather than my music, if
that makes sense. I ended up prolonging
my ask. And then after two years of
building this, I sold these collectibles
that represented my music to my audience
and then they bought it because they
liked me for me rather than just falling
in love with my music. This may be
backwards for a lot of artists because
people want to put their music first.
But if you look at yourself as a brand
and then music as just one branch of
that tree, I think you'll see a lot of
success. Now, you could do this with
merch, you could do this with stickers,
vinyls, and I did it as collectibles for
my music for people to buy. I hope this
helps someone. I think a lot of people
are playing like this, let me get so
many streams on Spotify game and I think
it's draining and burning a lot of
people out. So, I wanted to share the
story and of course I could talk a lot
more about it, but I'll stop it right
there, but happy to answer any
questions.
>> Now, Jaden just gave you guys the
blueprint, right? Build a small engaged
community and that community can make
you more money than sometimes even a
viral moment will. And this is the core
of the hybrid model. Music brings people
in, content builds connection, and the
community drives the revenue. And the
beautiful thing is we finally hit a
point where the industry not only
recognizes it, but they're starting to
admit that this is the right way. Wait,
quick pause because a lot of you have
been asking, "How can I work with you
guys oneonone?" And yes, we can run
almost any type of marketing campaign at
this point. But honestly, we prefer
working with clients from a consulting
standpoint because we actually get a
chance to deep dive into their music. We
can work on their brand. We can work on
their content strategy. We can tie it
all together into a marketing campaign.
Basically, we can give you a blueprint
on how to grow, monetize, and win. So,
if you're an artist that's serious about
getting their branding together, their
content strategy together, their
marketing together, then apply for a
call with our country brand agency arm
using the link in the description below.
Serious inquiries only, please guys. So,
if this sounds like something you need,
once again, hit that link in the
description. And if not, we still love
you anyway. All right, guys. Commercial
break over. Let's get back to the video.
Now, Steve Stout, someone who's moved
culture both as a figurehead, right?
like as a personality and a voice and as
a behind thescenes figure with his his
agency has been talking about this for
years at this point. Check this out.
>> These brand deals be more than some
people making him off the stream
sometimes.
>> What?
>> Hell yeah. Cuz way more. The brand deals
are well, there's two things. The brand
deals are definitely could be a lot more
than you make off streams by a long shot
because a lot of times in the business,
you're actually more famous than you
have more than than the money you have.
Mhm.
>> And the streaming revenue is is you can
stream a lot.
>> You'll do good.
>> You you'll do good, but you'll actually
be more famous in the revenue you'll
earn.
>> But you could then take that fame and
use that fame to go get a brand deal.
>> Now, Steve Stout is mostly talking
about, you know, bigger acts, mainstream
acts, when he's talking about their fame
is bigger than their paychecks. But I
actually think that this applies to most
artists. Like even if you're an artist
with, let's just say, a thousand real
fans in their fan base, there's a chance
that your revenue is not matching how uh
committed your fans actually are to you
or how dedicated your fans actually are
to you. And the reality is that if your
entire strategy of monetization and
career building as an artist is built
off of streams, then you're basically
chasing crumbs at that point. But if you
build leverage, with leverage being an
audience, a brand, and a world that
people want to be a part of, then you
can tap into opportunities that content
creators have been eating off of for
years at this point. And that's why even
though the artist creator hybrid might
just sound cute on paper, I believe at
this point it's survival for music
artists. And if you want to see what
this looks like at the tiptop of the
mountain, check out what one of our
living goats has to say about this
>> industry, right? Through music. And I
always say music was the thing that got
the attention,
but God had other plans for me. And I I
was able to create in ways that was
ways that were like very sincere and
genuine and organic and authentic to the
things that I love. So it doesn't even
feel like a job. But when you bring it
home,
>> I cannot express to you guys what this
day means for me to be able to celebrate
with the people that deserve it the
most.
>> Now, I for one think it's really funny
to think about Fenty Beauty just being
like a really high-end uh merchandising
op for Rihanna. It's kind of funny to
think about. You know what I'm saying?
When you really look at it. But she
admitted it herself. music gave her
leverage, but it's what she built on top
of it that made her a mogul. And I think
what's what's amazing about what she's
saying and about where this this mall is
kind of taking artists is that I'm
willing to bet that most of you guys are
multi-hyphenate creatives, meaning that,
you know, you do music. Music may be
your main creative outlet, but you're
probably good at something else, right?
Like you probably care about other
things other than just music. And if you
can figure out how to build those things
into your operation, like your your
content, right? like the way you kind of
set your community up, then it can set
you up for some really interesting
revenue sources and also set your fans
up for some really interesting
experiences. Now, you may not be
Rihanna, but the blueprint is still the
same, right? Like, don't just make
music, actually build some leverage. So,
let's get into some tips because if you
want to win in this era with this model,
then there's a few things that I need
you to remember. Number one, attention
alone isn't enough. Followers don't
always equal fans. Streams don't always
equal big checks. You should always be
looking at the attention that you get as
the start to your community building,
right? To your world building, not as
like the metric of success. And number
two is going to be think like a creator.
Document, build your community, turn
your lifestyle and your interests into
content. Because once again, if you can
do those things, you will unlock a world
where you can sell really unique things
to your audience. You unlock a world
where you can provide really unique
experiences to your fan base. Imagine
letting your fans know that like you're
really into gardening and and they've
been following you and watching you grow
some tomatoes or some [\h__\h] like that and
then one day you drop an album and you
sell like a gardening tool kit and some
seeds to your fans and then you have an
event where like everybody gets a free
plant and they get to garden with you
and then listen to the album later. Who
wouldn't want to go to something like
that for their favorite artist? So if
you can figure out how to bring these
elements into your world, you can create
opportunities like that. And I just came
up with that on the fly. Which goes into
my next point. Use your music to build
leverage so you can eat from more than
one table. Now, I think the main ethos
of this video has been that if you are
an artist who's only chasing the
streaming game, right? Like the
traditional music industry path, it's
still viable, right? Like we see it
happen at least a couple times a year.
But once again, for the vast majority of
artists, I just don't think that this is
the way you guys should be moving.
Especially when we're starting to see
creators and multihyenate creators who
are outside of music really leverage the
power that social media has given us.
And you know, a lot of them aren't even
looking at their main thing as their
main source of income. But lo and
behold, when you pay attention to music,
music artists are the only creatives
that only want to make money off of
their music. But me personally, I'm a
believer that a check can come from
anywhere as long as you set it up and
you feel good about it. And here's the
thing, too, right? Like the hybrid model
isn't just like a concept or a vibe.
There's actually some structure to it.
Now, me personally, I like to break it
down into five pillars. Uh those five
pillars being visibility, personality,
community, distribution, and
monetization. Now, I didn't want to make
this video like 30 40 minutes long,
which is why I didn't touch on, you
know, each of them individually. So, we
can just go into that in another video.
So, if you want to build like a hybrid
and, you know, not just talk about it,
then make sure you subscribe, hit that
like button, share this with an artist
that needs a little bit of gain today,
and you both can catch the next video
where I'll actually break down all five
of these pillars. I'm Kore, and I'll see
you guys next time. Beef.