Wow what's up everybody once again his
brand man Shawn and today we're gonna
discuss the truth about branding
touching on topics like why it's hard
for artists to gain fans from live
performances and showcases what most
people have wrong about branding and
lastly the power of branding and how
strong brands can cause people to lie to
themselves and they kind of like it so
let's hop into this with two quick clips
let me introduce you my track pop out
there piece by piece
first the melody okay
[Music]
all right if you don't know the first
person that was performing his name was
Treme if you've probably seen the video
I've done on him and he's basically a
big deal I'm talking a double platinum
artist and he's performing extremely
popular songs in a time period where
those songs were literally lighting up
the charts now the second person is
Joshua Bell he's essentially a classical
music superstar I'm talking about but he
doesn't really lead a house for less
than $75,000 not only that but he was
playing on a Stradivarius violin now one
of my best friends is a classical
violinist and Stradivarius violins are
not cheap starting to thousands of
dollars the most expensive Stradivarius
violin was sold for 16 million dollars
this alone kind of speaks to why a lot
of newer artists who were just doing
showcases in live performances have a
hard time gaining fans from their
performances alone even these huge
performers could barely get people's
attention and this is what I call a
branding problem see marketing is about
creating awareness and people are aware
of them because they're walking by they
see then actually you know making music
but they aren't aware of who they are so
even if the people didn't necessarily
like that type of music like you didn't
like classical music
if these people knew who these people
were they would at least stop for it a
little bit there's a lot of times people
will accept the subpar or trash
performance from people that they
already know and like if they go to
their concert versus actually buying
into it becoming a fan of somebody that
they don't know just from a random
performance branding - leads to a
reputation that precedes you and people
actually rely on branding as a shortcut
to how they process information people
have to be told that something is worth
their time they have to be told that is
valuable if not that some things don't
happen naturally but in this world where
so many things are coming at us people
are always trying to figure out how to
decide what they spend their time on
they say pay attention because you're
paying in time when you give your
attention to something that we all know
the time is the most valuable asset
right so no matter what trash for
quality people do not get paid what
they're worth they're either underpaid
or overpaid underrated or overrated now
if you're overpaid and overrated
congratulations
that means your brand is doing its job
because
Brande is the reason that people overpay
for things now the problem a lot of
people have especially creatives when
they're trying to create a brand is they
think that branding is all about
aesthetic and visual type things the
logo the name things like that that's
really only a small piece of the pie so
what exactly is a brand a brand is to
perception and expectations that people
associate with the person or entity and
to translate that into something a
little bit more practical and
understanding the difference between
marketing and branding marketing is
about creating awareness and branding is
about creating value what you mean by
that brand man if there were two cars
and both of them looked exactly the same
one was a Toyota and one was a BMW which
one would you choose BMW you don't need
a second and think most people will
choose the BMW and this example is so
perfect because they both look the same
once again branding is not necessarily
all about visual but people have a set
of expectations of what it means to have
a BMW BMWs represent quality engineering
and luxury especially in comparison to a
Toyota and this is what I mean by
creating value in one of the best ways
to create value is to communicate values
and attract people who value your values
this is one of the reasons that
Chancellor wrapper fights off
accusations that he's not independent
Soviet merely not because being an
independent rapper
really even matters that much it's just
because of the fact that he's made it so
ingrained as a part of his values and
marketed that as a part of his brand but
bringing that value into question is a
direct attack at his brand it's like if
everybody found out that Toyota's were
being built in the exact same factory by
the exact same people of s BMW with the
exact same parts and engineers and all
that stuff behind it BMWs will be at
risk and losing a lot of value even
still BMWs branding has been set so
deeply into people's psychology at this
point that their actions will still
likely show preference towards BMW
regardless of if it was made in the same
way as Toyota or not perfect example
have you ever seen those blind drink
tests where people are drinking like
Pepsi at coca-cola and they don't know
which one and we all know coca-cola is
like number one by far but when they do
the blind drink test there has been
instances where people will be like oh
no
I like the Pepsi but they won't know if
they're female just say that one number
two you would think that that type of
experience will make a person say oh
snap and there's another life I'm just
started drinking Pepsi for now on but
you could take that same person never
tell them that they chose Pepsi before
and then put two sodas in front of them
and say that this one's coca-cola
that one's Pepsi and then they would
choose two coke that's because of the
branding I'm not gonna go super deep
into why but let's just say that
coca-cola has communicated the worth of
their brand very well over time and
don't get me wrong there's people who
have brand bias towards Pepsi and they
would have the same kind of illogical
results that's based on the brand versus
where they how much they actually like
the soda it was like the one pair of
Jordans that I had when I was a kid
Jordans are not the best basketball
shoes but when I got him and I played in
the game I really felt like I was gonna
fly there right there is 100% brand I
know it sucks with people but it's not
100% a quality conversations and
everybody likes to think that they're
all about quality but most people are
usually only about quality in the areas
that they choose to be experts at but
there's too much stuff out in the world
to be completely in to know about every
single product and experience that's why
going back to those two clips of the
artists I played at the beginning it was
all about branding people were aware of
them but they didn't know that these
people were worth paying attention to
once again marketing is about creating
awareness and branding is about creating
value and you can communicate your
values to create value and once you have
these values people have a set of
expectations when it comes to what the
experience of your brand is like and
that's it for now so you guys let me
know what you think in the comments
below and like this video and if you
liked it you might as well share it but
if you are not subscribed you know what
to do hit that subscribe button