Most artists want to blow up, but the
ones that actually do, they don't just
drop music and pray on it. They actually
build infrastructure. And in my opinion,
they master five pillars that help
separate real career artists from those
who are just having a good moment.
Pillars that make sure that people see
you, that they connect with you, that
they ride for you, and that they support
you in real ways. So, in today's video,
I'm going to break down these five
pillars and give some real world artist
examples so you can see how to work
through the blueprint. Now, for this
first example, I'm actually going to
lump together two of the pillars, right?
Those pillars being visibility and
distribution. And I want to start here
because let's be real here. If nobody
sees you, then the rest of these steps
don't even really matter. Now,
visibility is about making sure that
you're being seen and that people
discover you, right? They're discovering
your music. They're discovering your
personality. They're discovering your
brand. All those things that come with
your artist world and your artist
package. And distribution is about
making sure your message spreads and you
have access to the channels and the
means to make sure that these things
spread. Now, this is usually one of the
biggest differences between being
talented and being an artist who's
actually in the game. Cuz let's be real
here, you can make the best music in the
world, but if nobody sees it and nobody
knows about it, does it even matter? And
I think that right now, no artist
understands this better than Lar
Russell. Check this out. So, if you take
a look at your screen, this is a a a
screenshot of Lar Russell's Meta Ad
Manager, and he's posting that he spent
$120,000
on 64 ads in the last 90 days. Right?
And so, the caption says, "It takes
millions to become a successful artist,
even more when you're independent and
spending your own paper. This is not
easy or cheap. This is just 90 days of
advertising on one platform to make sure
our art is seen, heard, and felt
globally. This don't include seating,
clipping, YouTube, Spotify campaigns,
etc. If you're competing against a
machine, you have to build your own
machine. The reason I've been able to
get as big as some major artists is
because I treat and invest in myself
like a major artist. And this is why
it's important to to buy direct and
support your favorite artist, right? So,
he's giving us an insight into one of
the main channels of how he controls his
visibility and his distribution, which
is Meta Ads. Like, a lot of artists
start off building their systems through
some type of ad system. Meta is the most
popular, so it makes sense that he would
land where he lands. Now, what's cool
about this is that Lar Russell isn't
just sitting around waiting for
virality. He's buying visibility. He's
building a marketing infrastructure
around himself and his content. Now, you
don't need a h 100,000 a month or
100,000 a quarter to do this. It'll be a
good start, right? But you don't need
it. But you do need some kind of
machine, whether that be around
advertising or seating or collaborations
or playlisting, whatever that looks
like. You just need something that you
can repeat and put in place to make sure
that you're constantly growing. And this
is how you stop being invisible. You
don't wait to be discovered. You make
sure that you're everywhere and you're
being seen so that you can be
undeniable. Now, once people start to
see you, the next question naturally
becomes, will these people even actually
stick around? And that's where pillar
two comes in. Personality. This is the
pillar that builds its essence from who
you are. Your energy, your humor, your
presence, the way you speak, the way you
carry yourself. It's this authenticity
that one attracts people to you, and
then two makes people want to root for
you. Now, your music might be what
brings people in, but it's usually your
personality that makes them want to
stay. And I think that one of the best
artist examples right now of
personality, right? Like giving us who
they are real and raw is Glorilla. Check
this out.
>> Respond a lot on the internet. So I just
rather put it in my mercy.
>> What? What you just say? What you going
to put it in?
>> My mercy.
>> What it is? [laughter]
>> Who do people say you look like? Sway,
[laughter]
>> they're my twin.
>> All right, so I'm not going to play the
whole video, but you can see it. People
love Glorilla's personality, and people
love it because it feels like she's
always being herself. She's goofy. She's
unfiltered. She's real. She's not afraid
to to speak in her native accent. And it
worked out for her because her
personality became a huge part of her
brand. And you can see this over and
over and over. Artists who break tend to
have a personality that makes people
want to follow their journey. And this
doesn't have to be forced, right? Like
we can see this in your interviews. We
can see this in your live streams. We
can see this in your content or your
collaborations or your behindthe-scenes
moments. We just want to see you show up
as being you in all spaces that you show
up in. But once people start to like
you, then it's community that turns it
into something deeper. And that brings
us to our next pillar, community.
Because once again, followers aren't the
same things as fans. And community is
when people don't just like your music,
they feel connected to you and they like
what you represent. And this is what
creates real staying power. When you can
fill a room not because you're trending
at the moment or not because you're hot,
but because the people there feel
connected to you and just want to be
closer to you. And in the business, we
like to call that care, right? Like we
can see that people are feeling the room
because people care about you. And once
again, I think La Russell is probably a
perfect example of this. Check this out.
NOW, what's cool about this clip to me
is that this isn't Coachella. This is
just his backyard. But look at that
energy, right? Like, you couldn't tell
me that bro wasn't at a festival. If I
didn't personally know who he was,
right? Like, if I didn't know he was in
his backyard, I would have assumed that
he got booked out for some big private
event or something like that. But look
at how tapped in the people are in that
video. Look at how close they want to be
to the stage. Look at how they're
looking at him as he walks back and
forth. And that right there, ladies and
gentlemen, is community. Because people
don't just show up for the music,
they're actually showing up for Lar
Russell. And once again, what he
represents. Now, I actually got the
chance to go to one of Lar Russell's
backyard shows maybe like a year or two
ago. And now, I felt exactly like the
way it looks in that that clip, right? I
think that something that that clip
doesn't do enough justice of is how much
of a community it really felt like. Like
there were people from the local Bay
Area community selling up to show
things. He had like games for kids. You
know what I'm saying? Like he really
turned it into a familyfriendly event
where your mom, your uncle, and your
nephew could all come out to check out
the Russell and have some fun even when
he's not performing. And community can
be what turns a viral act into a real
movement. It can be built through shows.
It can be built through your Discord,
through group chats, through IG close
friends, through live streams, through
email list, through text list. It's all
about creating spaces where your fans
feel like they can belong. And once you
have the community, you unlock the final
pillar. Wait, quick pause because a lot
of you have been asking, "How can I work
with you guys one-on-one?" And yes, we
can run almost any type of marketing
campaign at this point. But honestly, we
prefer working with clients from a
consulting standpoint because we
actually get a chance to deep dive into
their music. We can work on their brand.
We can work on their content strategy.
We can tie it all together into a
marketing campaign. Basically, we can
give you a blueprint on how to grow,
monetize, and win. So, if you're an
artist that's serious about getting
their branding together, their content
strategy together, their marketing
together, then apply for a call with our
country brand agency arm using the link
in the description below. Serious
inquiries only, please guys. So, if this
sounds like something you need, once
again, hit that link in the description.
And if not, we still love you anyway.
All right, guys. Commercial break over.
Let's get back to the video. And once
you have the community, you unlock the
final pillar, the one that turns us all
into a real sustainable career. And that
pillar is monetization. This is where
artists are separated from being
hobbyists to being real business people.
Because when you build relationships
with your fans, you don't just sell
songs. You create offers, experiences,
and value that people actually want to
support. And these next two clips are
going to show you exactly what that
looks like. [laughter]
>> It works. Do you remember when these
came out in 2006? iPod Shuffle
generation 2 with the little clip so you
could literally wear them as you
listened or you could put it in your
hair as a barret. I mean, the options
were limitless with these guys. So, I've
been sourcing these all over eBay. I've
been bidding on them, making sure that
they are tested and that they work and
that they come with charging docks. Some
of them don't. So, I've been sourcing
charging docks. I've collected 20 of
them. And I'm releasing my debut album 1
month early only on the iPod Shuffle.
So, come with me as I find out what's on
this iPod Shuffle, who had it, maybe
make some assumptions about their life,
and restore it to put on a new playlist
of songs that I can't wait to share with
you. I made as much money as Tiger's
highest streaming song on his recent
album with only a,000 monthly listeners.
Tiger song did 3 million streams, which
is roughly $15,000. So, how was I able
to make three times that amount with
0.4% of his monthly listeners? And it's
by building a tightnit community, but
it's not as easy as that. I spent 2
years essentially doing Twitter spaces
every single day, building this
community, making people fall in love
with me for me rather than my music, if
that makes sense. I ended up prolonging
my ask and then after two years of
building this, I sold these collectibles
that represented my music to my audience
and then they bought it because they
liked me for me rather than just falling
in love with my music. This may be
backwards for a lot of artists because
people want to put their music first.
But if you look at yourself as a brand
and then music as just one branch of
that tree, I think you'll see a lot of
success. Now, you could do this with
merch, you could do this with stickers,
vinyls, and I did it as collectibles for
my music for people to buy. I hope this
helps someone. I think a lot of people
are playing like this. let me get so
many streams on Spotify game and I think
it's draining and burning a lot of
people out. So, I wanted to share the
story and of course I could talk a lot
more about it, but I'll stop it right
there, but happy to answer any
questions.
>> So, let's break those down, right? Jaden
Violet was able to make the same amount
of money as Tiger's biggest song with
like 0.00001%
of his total monthly listener and fan
base. And that was because he built his
community and then he made sure to sell
something unique to his brand and to his
music to his core audience. And Mariel,
the girl with the iPods, yeah, she
literally sold her fans a physical
product that doubled as a listening
experience. And this is the game, right?
Make music and content that makes people
love you. Collect those people and then
sell those people unique products and
experiences. You can still do the
traditional music stuff, right? You can
sell them tickets to shows, you can sell
them hats, t-shirts, hoodies. You can
still do all of that stuff. But what
starts to really define and separate
your community from other artist
community is when you can think of those
unique experiences and merch
opportunities that really only seem to
represent you, right? Like you're
creating something that I can only get
if I'm a fan of you and who you are
personally. And once again, this is the
game. When fans care, you can build a
business that doesn't depend on labels.
It doesn't depend on playlist. It
doesn't depend on the algorithm picking
you up and [\h__\h] with your release for
that month. And you don't need
gatekeepers, right? like nobody can
gatekeep you from your own audience that
you built up. And when you bring all of
the pillars together, right? Visibility,
distribution, personality, community,
and monetization. That's where the real
leverage lives. And once again, this is
what I'm talking about when I talk about
the artist creator hybrid. These are
artists who are not just waiting to be
discovered, but they're actually
building something that has the
potential to become so strong that it
can't be ignored. Not by the labels and
not by the artists who are coming up on
these artists and watching them grow.
Get seen on purpose. Let people build
with you where you are. Invest in that
community so they feel closer to you and
then sell them things so they can
support you directly. Now, this is the
foundation that most artists skip. But
you watching this video, you're not like
most artists. And you know that there's
work that you need to do. So guys, I
want to hear your thoughts. Which pillar
are you currently focusing on? Right?
Like which pillar do you feel like
you're the weakest in and you need the
most help with? I think once I get
enough comments kind of around these
things, maybe I can start to make
specific deep dive videos on the pillars
individually, right? Like we can tackle
how to build your personality or, you
know, how to actually collect these
people or how to come up with unique
experiences. I don't know. I want to see
what y'all having issues with and then
we can go from there. Other than that,
make sure you like this video,
subscribe, share it with an artist that
needs a little bit of gain today. Once
again, my name is Corey and I'll see
y'all next time. Peace.