[Music]
Wow what's up everybody once again it's
brain man Shawn and we got to talk about
how to change makes his music to things
that he focuses on and why that's
something that's really important that
other artists can use to increase the
engagement and awareness for their own
music so let's start with this clip
right here short albums versus longer
albums dreaming rules what is it what's
the number to fit 1,500 streams but I
don't know all that [\h__\h] it's confusing
to me do you understand it I do but I
don't I don't think about it I don't
make my music based on how many mean
okay let me let me rephrase that because
you're research-based I make my music
based on two things replay value and
share ability I do a lot of things off
those two things and that is something
that I personally do because I know a
lot of kids have social media and they
like to say yo you saying this [\h__\h]
pink car then we just [\h__\h] stood on
and broke whoever did you love [\h__\h]
alright so let's address that first
thing replay value a lot of people have
songs that other people don't want to
play again right you might hear it it
was cool
but I'm not gonna play that song back a
lot of times we've already talked about
the fact that you might play something
for your friends or whoever else and
they'll be like yo that was dope but
then they don't play it again or they're
not you know repeating their lyrics when
they walking around shopping at the
grocery store or doing their homework or
something like that if your music
doesn't have a replay value then you're
gonna have a hard time and need a lot of
money to have a lasting career because
you don't necessarily need a huge
fanbase if you can have a replay value
with a small subset of people because at
least those people can become strong
fans so that part's simple it makes a
lot of sense he wants replay value to
the people who get and understand what
does trying to provide but number two
shareability that's something that a lot
of people ignore right especially in a
social media air shareability is
something that makes you extremely viral
now we're not just talking about music
we're sharing because that's the
baseline when you listen to artists like
Daniel Caesar and her right a lot of
artists like them their music is so good
you might share with people who are
interested in that type of music I know
that's what I did but I believe 2 Chainz
focuses on that on a small level as well
so the macro is the actual song right
that being something worth sharing but
when a micro is punchlines funny bars
things like that he has quite a few of
those they might not be funny everybody
but he has some bars that are funny
interesting or just might all-around
throw you off Blueface the exact same
thing Drake has bars worth sharing as
well his aren't necessarily funny but a
lot of people share his bars because he
has quotables so the best way you can
say shareability is quotables when we're
talking about the micro within your
actual music then the macro is the song
itself which will also have replay value
if it's worth sharing so then you're
killing two birds with one stone but
then I love how he also talked about in
this pull up interview with Joe Budden
that he did the Trap House the pink trap
house that's something that isn't music
but it's also something that's obviously
worth sharing right when you do this
trap house campaign there were so many
people in Atlanta that were going down
to the pink trap house taking pictures
and making complete events out of just
going to the trap Alex come in from out
of town to see it take pictures just so
they can share with other people and say
that they did it that shareability
can you create things like that because
that's not just about you you're giving
something for other people to actually
brag about and show for themselves just
like how on a smaller scale when the
dreamville sessions happen earlier this
year they sent people digital invite
flyers for people to post all the people
that were involved they got to post that
on social media making other people
aware that this thing was happening but
it was a special invite thing but you
still had other people promote for you
and share for you because you gave them
something to brag
those two small concepts can go a long
way
replay value and share ability don't
underestimate them now
again this is one of my videos where I'm
commenting on another video right
something that's very interesting and I
would love to know other videos you guys
would like me to comment on I have a
form that I'm putting in the description
below please submit it at that link I'm
not necessarily going to just go through
all the comments submit that video a
link to that video in the time stamp at
the link below and those instructions
will be at the link in the description
below so you don't have to worry about
like rewinding it's a whole bunch of
times to understand it but I would love
to know what you guys think about this
video in general this whole discussion
join the discussion in the comment
section below and other than that be
like this video go a like button even
like it Mossville sharing if you're not
subscribed you know what to do here
subscribe
[Music]