Wow what's up everybody once again its
brand man Shawn and today it's Friday
which means I got to talk about some
music resource tool or strategy and
today we're talking all strategy how do
you get your very first music fans now
there's a lot of people who ask me this
question and there's a lot of ways to
come into the game there is no one way
there is no five ways to get into the
game there's a lot of ways to get into
the game and start building fan bases
per se but we're gonna narrow it down to
some things that could just matter for
people who have no resources and very
few or if none in terms of connections
now there's three of these but number
one is join a community and add value so
many people spend so much time trying to
build a following how can I build a
following how can I build a community
around me but they never think of simply
adding value to other communities and
that's how you build yourself and how
you build your brand now there's two
types right you can do the online or
physical world and both of them can work
for you obvious ones are like being in
college or high school and you have
these physical people around and
building your brand with these people
and transferring them to online follows
or you can join a fraternity if you're
in college right there's if you're at a
church there's so many types of physical
communities some kind of organization
you can build parties for some kind of
event series and brand yourself at the
center of that just as the person
involved in the community right now
we're just building who you are your
name and then later on you'll be
flipping that into your music but first
you have to get people to know you and
just add value to them in their lives
and that goals are the same for these
online forums people don't believe it
I've said it again and again you can
build your brand and get audiences from
online forums I'm glad to have an
interview coming up with a guy named
Malone he's basically done this these
guys him and his buddy Michael both of
them have basically said hey not only
are we going to join these forums and
contribute to these forums they're even
admins for some of these forums which
means if you guys have been involved in
forums before you know that the most
popular and powerful people in
the forums are the people who are the
admins because they can choose if
somebody's comment can be deleted or not
if it's approved or not but that's still
adding value and curating the community
positioning yourself and the most
important in all these or whether it's
online offline types of communities is
consistency I'm not gonna be able to say
this enough because I know a lot of
people will not believe it a lot of
people refuse to just do this but the
number one hack for building an audience
from scratch with very few resources is
simply being consistent and you cannot
transfer these people into followers of
you if you are not simply consistent
because you won't have a brand brands do
not exist without consistency so if you
think about branding take that concept
take the picture of having this medal
right and then putting it in the fire to
brand the cow so they could put the
symbol on the cows and show that they
own these cows so wherever the cow when
it took that brand that was burned into
its skin with it take that same concept
and think about your brand brands have
to be consistent because you're not
gonna literally burn a hole in
somebody's brain but you have to
constantly pound pound pound your brand
your existence until they can't forget
you or they remember you a lot more than
at least they originally did that's how
the brands exist and build up right I'm
not gonna forget Beyonce but I can
listen to an artist for three days
straight that I just discovered today
and give myself a year if I'd never hear
from them again
and never see their name again I just
might forget so if you do these they all
work whether that's just starting a
party series or whether that's just
being popular in school or just being
positioned in an online forum act value
add value but do this consistently I'm
telling you it works and I'm once again
I have an interview coming up with a guy
I actually discovered him in the forums
he never actually listened to his music
or anything like that I just saw him in
the forum click this page and then fell
into the rabbit hole just like anybody
else it works
number two hack attention and add value
in the white space now what exactly do I
mean by that it's similar to number one
except for joining a community
specifically what you're doing is
basically just hacking attention getting
in front of people and adding value in
some form of fashion boat is a perfect
example of this right he added value by
entertaining people he did the whole
boat gang thing and I guess he still
does it every once in a while but the
point is he got people's attention his
goal was to transfer it into a rap
career is that working
heck yeah I don't know but there's a lot
of people who will pack the tension a
lot of ways they've done it through
comedy they've done it through I don't
know kind of lessons or rap lessons
there's a lot of different ways just
finding some kind of unique talent that
you can provide to constantly get
people's attention some people just
start off blogging and they're blogging
or they're doing commentary or making
fun of people roasting people online and
figure out how to transfer that into a
rap career or at least having a certain
level of rap fans but again just like
number one you have to do this
consistently because you have to have
these people become fans of you and your
brand the brand is never gonna occur if
you are not doing it consistently and
you gotta build it it just is what it is
number three engage with people who are
likely to be your fans what's that mean
we're just talking about simply finding
the artist that's in your room that you
think would typically like your music
artist quit lying to yourselves for the
most part in saying that I'm completely
different than everybody else nobody
sounds like me we all have similarities
at the end of the day I'm very much like
my sister and brother but at the same
time I'm very different from them as
well it's not that big of a deal just
find somebody who has a similar audience
that you would like to be your fan base
that means if you're a lyrical rapper
find the lyrical rapper goes to them on
Instagram and then goes to all their
fans and engage with all their fans on
Instagram whether that's DM them whether
that's just liking their pictures and
making comments and do that one by one
if you don't have money you got to use
time you got to spend that time it takes
long it's a very tedious process but
we're just talking about building those
very first fans the work cannot be
avoided everybody's looking for some
hacks and only people who are moving and
getting ahead of them are the people who
are being consistent we're not talking
about having big
time connections here we're just talking
about building it from Ground Zero these
three ways of very simple ways that you
tell people most people are not gonna do
it I know post people are not gonna do
it consistently because it takes work
and it's tedious it's boring you do not
see the results immediately there's a
lot of other ways to grow your fan base
in terms of collaborations and paying to
get on certain outlets and things like
that but we're talking about number one
just beginning to get fan number one two
three four five through ten and keep
going from there don't start with these
one through three things if you have the
time and you're put in that work and you
have a solid quality of music doesn't
you have to be the best you will begin
to gain some fans and if you do number
one and two and for some reason your
music is just super trash and people
never want to listen to your music you
will still have a brand built with a
solid following that you can convert
into other things that you want to try
later on hope that was helpful for you
guys other than that if you like this
video go ahead hit that like button if
you like it might as well share it and
if you're not subscribed you know what
to do here dad subscribe but