bow what's up everybody once again it's
brand man Sean and today we're going
over five reasons to release an entire
project and this one will touch on a few
things that you probably never heard of
when it comes to releasing a project
number one quality control you can make
sure every single track is perfect dot
your eyes cross your teas and then
create a Sonic experience relating each
track to the other like you don't have
the opportunity to do if you just
released one song so you're controlling
the entire presentation to the world
which leads right into number two image
control you can make sure that
everything coordinates you can take the
time and go deep on creating an
aesthetic that goes along with that
story or experience for that project
check out this example of Anderson Pat
this man has these great beautiful
images and you scroll you scroll and
each image goes right into the next one
of the few people I've seen do that and
it's just a great aesthetic and image
control and then black if you look at
black I heard black like four years ago
and I was listening to his track like
all the time um he actually sampled it
pretty weather on his new um album and
ever since I have been following him
he's been creating this aesthetic this
black and white aesthetic you can not
only do it for your image as an artist
but you can do it for your image as a
project number three this is huge is
what I call the Netflix effect today the
way people consume content is they binge
most people binge I mentioned black
earlier when he first came out with this
project I was excited however I didn't
listen to it right away when I finally
got time to listen to to it I listen to
all of it at once right matter of fact I
did it once or twice so a big thing
about this when you have a project is
when people come to your music think
about the fact everybody has all these
distractions mom mother brother sister
dad family bills work uh the stuff they
want to do all that stuff is a
distraction so people are competing for
people's attention a single song could
be a oneoff but entire project
particularly if people like it you get
their attention for a long time and you
make a deeper connection which leads to
number four project referrals imagine
this scenario right quick you have a
song out it's a single and people say
hey go listen to this song that's cool
and all people might even love it
scenario two you listen to this project
and you say oh man yo man you got to
check this out this project is dope you
tell your homeboy the homeboy listens to
the entire project which is five to 10
songs and when that friend decides they
like it they tell somebody else about
that project which is 5 to 10 songs so
if you position your project correctly
people will be sharing five to 10 songs
at a time of yours as opposed to just
one song at a time but let's get a
little bit deeper check out this it's
her volume one if you haven't heard this
project it's super dope when you go on
YouTube now this is why YouTube so
amazing you go on YouTube you listen to
this one track on the song focus and
then bam now you get an automatic
project referral because when you click
on the song you're going to see that
there's other songs on the side you
don't even know that it's a project but
you hear that one song and then you say
oh snap it's five more tracks of this
and if you decided that you like the
first song then you want to hear the
rest of the songs so now not only do you
get the benefit of word to mouth
referral YouTube's algorithm is
basically set up to create and
facilitate its own Word of Mouth by just
putting things like minded next to each
other companies pay so much money for
[\h__\h] like this this ad this is one big
ad this entire album is taking up the
entire page at this point even me I took
this picture right here when I only had
like eight or nine videos that's how
long ago I actually thought about doing
this video right here is showing all my
stuff on the side without having to do
anything number five leave them wanting
more first of all you always want to
leave when people want to hear more of
you so you don't want to have a project
too long where people are like dang that
was like four or five songs too long I
wish it just stopped it at number eight
but on top of that when people hear a
project they get opportunity to connect
with you and there's a sense of finality
to a project right when it's finished
and if people are really rocking with it
they're like dang I hate that this is
over I need to hear more give me some
more but if it's a song people don't
really have that chance to really
connect with you as they would over a
full project that they really liking
because you get to immerse them in a
whole world of yours and then when the
Project's over they come back out
they're like damn I can't wait till they
come out with their next project or I
can't wait till they go on tour if
people are really really really really
rocking with your project so that's
about it I'll do some more music release
strategies in the future if some come to
mind um I already did that other one on
high volume music release strategies
other than that be cool you know what to
do hit that subscribe
button by