[Music]
what's up brandman network it's shawn
and i'm back with the very first video
of the music release strategy series now
the first three videos are going to be
touching on some principles that really
should guide the way
pretty much everybody approaches their
music release strategy these days
with that being said of course it's not
going to be as
custom and deep as the information is
going to be when it comes to your
personal music release strategy
which you'll develop in the gauntlet
remember that's that four
workshop series and the third one is
when we really get into building out
your personal marketing plan and music
really strategy series so definitely
check that out if you haven't yet
but for this video number one the
frequently asked question
really is projects or singles and
everybody should be doing singles we are
let me start here actually
we've been pushed this message of
quantity quantity quantity quantity and
that was correct
for a certain period of time when there
was new platforms and people hop on
these new platforms instagram's just
starting off
youtube when there was nowhere there
hasn't been too many of the newer
platforms everybody's flooded to in a
minute
so with that being said at that time
we're in a place where instead of the
advantage being in
quantity a lot of the advantage
particularly when it comes to the music
space
is more so invisibility we are in a
visibility era
not a quantity error that's why there's
so many people dropping
so much content so much content and it's
not getting seen
there's some truth to what you hear from
people like garyvee and things like that
when you talk about quantity
but at the end of the day artists should
be doing
one song and not just one song a week
not just one song a month it needs to be
one song that gets pushed
for a given period of time where you
have enough time to try
everything that you know marketing wise
build that system
around that song whatever you learn from
that song you apply it all to the next
song
and then whatever you learn from that
song you apply it all to the next song
even if you decide hey i want to drop a
album a ep
a project of some sort do not try to
market the entire
project as a whole this is for a newer
artist without a fan base by the way
especially for the when it comes to the
ep the what i'm about to talk about
don't try to just push it as a whole and
amp it up on everybody
push one song and now that you have five
songs you treat
each song like it's a single so you
market that one song
and then you market that next song then
you market that next song people will
find your ep
trust me if one of those songs is
something that they like when you market
those
so let me reel it back and just to
summarize and get a little bit more
specific as well
when you drop a song you should be
pushing that song probably
for a good two months most of these
people that
i talk to and realizing how long that
y'all actually push songs
you should be pushing it for probably at
least two months try that out just try
that out and try to
expand your mind and see what does that
mean what would i do for two months to
push a song
and it's going to force you to learn
some things but also change some of the
things and add on some other things
so once you're able to do that you'll be
able to bring
visibility to the next song and then
you'll be able to add on
to the next song because a lot of people
are dropping a lot of content
and the content is falling on deaf ears
once again we're no longer in that space
where you can just
drop music or content and expect people
to come organically
you have to push so you have to train
yourself
to push each one individually and learn
those things in that process
just do singles just do singles just do
singles maybe you only want to do one
single a month and you go hard for a
month but if you can stretch it to two
that number will be different for
everybody by the way and another thing
that i'll say for this particular video
is if you have
one song that you're pushing right and
then you push it you push it you push it
and you start to say yo this thing is
doing good do not
stop pushing it a lot of people stop
pushing their music before it hits that
certain threshold
you have to keep working that song
especially
if you've dropped a few songs and you
already built your system you know what
you're gonna do you do that same thing
that you did with other songs but for
whatever
reason this song is getting some better
results then you already know
hey i need to you know i need to double
down on this thing
so keep those thoughts in mind singles
are the way to go right now
not necessarily because of just how
consumers roll
receive it or worrying about people
getting tired you of any
or anything like that more importantly
is especially for aspiring artists or
just young teams coming up in the
industry
for y'all to get your marketing together
and to know how to bring visibility to
music
and if you just drop music every week
you drop music every day or one of those
kind of cool campaigns
you're not gonna actually have time to
spend on bringing more visibility to
your music
and that's the most important thing at
the end of the day let's get it
you