blowing up as an artist in your city
first is one of the most underrated
strategies in today's era now it doesn't
have to be your hometown it could be the
town that you're living in currently and
the key is blowing up without getting
stuck in the scene so in this video
right here we're going to talk about how
we've helped artists blow up in their
city but most importantly how you can do
it today I'm brand man Sean and I'm Cory
and this is yet another episode of No
Labels
necessary so let's just start right here
building your name in your City without
getting stuck in your scene I want to
map out the benefits first just so y'all
can understand why this is valuable
today because so many people had this
idea no my city isn't big my city isn't
an industry type City it's not worth it
etc etc you got all the excuses we're
going to go through the value how you
can do it no matter what city you're in
and then how again I have to keep
repeating this how you do it without
getting stuck in your scene benefits
being number one you build your
resources mhm all right cuz you get
certain connections and when I say
connections I'm not even talking about
industry just think about having the
leverage to say now I know some
videographers I know some photographers
photographers I know other types of
creatives that can help me put my vision
together a good example this by the way
if you all look at somebody like the
Russell yeah facts all right like most
of those people are from his area to my
understanding and he built his entire
team right and the fact is his city is
not a a Music City not Bay oh no I don't
well know I don't even know all the
specifics of the Bay Area Etc so I'm not
gonna even try to yeah I think it's fair
to say like that City isn't like
traditionally known as like a big like
they have music artist out of it but you
don't think of it as like a music scene
for exactly it's not thought of as its
own music scene City so you can think
about it like when the small business
comes to town and it's not too many
businesses to compete with that that
company whether it's cocacola or her
chees Etc becomes the job that
everybody's working at so it's actually
an advantage if you think about it that
way but you have to be willing to build
something worth people's time right now
also doing anything in real life is a
flex these days that's the that's the
flex we have and we probably should have
started here like the fact that
everybody's doing stuff online everybody
knows that um online can be manipulated
today and you see fewer people actually
doing things in the real world the more
you do in the real world they'll be like
oh you're actually doing this I see a
lot of people say they're doing things
online but he's different he's real and
that's what real social proof looks like
now it's not a bunch of followers it's
oh people are following him in real life
he must be worth it she must be worth
it this is interesting let me tag along
for the journey the other two things are
influence in general which I think we
kind of touch on when you think about
the resources and then how that
influence can translate from offline to
online when people see that you're doing
stuff in real life and the last thing is
cheaper to monetize because the sense
that is being in your area is different
than I got to travel you know across the
country just to do a show and monetize
my fans the fact I could do shows in my
city or whatever in my city to monetize
is a huge Advantage now let's get into
the details because again we've talked
about this isn't when we say my city it
doesn't have to be the city you're from
and I think people should think about it
completely different in terms of
leveraging your city that you live in is
not the same as I have to become like a
hero in that city where the whole city
even knows who I amh right and uh the
reason I say that is because we've
helped artists who have built things in
their city and launched it across the
country and taking artists I mean taking
their fans in the different parts of the
world literally
but in Atlanta which is a city that this
artist Works in uh or lives in this
artist isn't known as like a big city a
big name like people in the city don't
even in the scene might not know who who
she is but at the same
time there's fans who know who she is in
the city she can activate the city still
she can activate the city still right
and let's break it down for here
strategy so you have four
stakeholders you got industry Pros these
are the literally the professionals who
are in the industry you got music Talent
so music Talent is other artists who are
in your city number three is you have
creative talent in general that's the
visual artists the photographers the
videographers all these other people who
can become an extension of what you do
they might be people who have their own
merch Brands but it's in the same Vibe
as your aesthetic so it's worth knowing
them because you Valu to them you might
be a future sponsor or influencer that's
working for them or they might be the
people who design your merch right it
could go multiple ways but they're
building an audience that's similar to
your audience so you want to understand
and work with some of these small
businesses per se um that makes sense
for you and your Niche specifically
that's what you really want to think
about it as and then the next set of
people is in real life influence now
what do I mean by in real life influence
this is yo man jakori is good with the
ladies man so if I bring jakori I gonna
have a lot of ladies that come or it
could be Chiron is a gamer and he got
the whole Gaming Community on Lock and
whenever he pull up I if I wanted to
bring the gaming Community I got I could
invite Chante right it's it's whatever
the person has an influence
on that's what you that's what you tap
on their shoulder for right and
let's say if I specifically have some
type of event that needs a lot of women
then I might have to have for Gories who
have who are plugged in with the women
and then I might have to have these
other sets of women that bring all their
friends because I have my my my cute
best friend who got a whole bunch of
friends right you just understand the
real uh World influence like because you
want when whenever you want to mobilize
people you have to understand other
people that can mobilize people and how
many people that is so you might bring
four people with you you might bring
like a hundred people with you but that
four matters cuz one I'm curating the
vibe and two like it's not like I can't
hit everybody up right if I if I need
that many at that kind of moment so
that's what I think about real in real
life influence but if you want to have
any other like what do you think when
you think about in real life influence
yeah no I I think you pretty much hit a
spot on I think it's it's a little bit
harder to spot if you're not there in
the scene because it it is easy to go
into a local situation yeah with a
regular influencer brand right you're
not necessarily looking for the guy or
the girl with 100K followers or or 200k
followers local influence to me that's
strong is like they can bring out 20
plus people yeah to the off their word
right that could be to your point the
college student with 4,000 followers
that could be you know what I'm saying
the guy that owns the boutique in the
popular part of town and he ain't really
got no socias but everybody knows the
clothing store restaurant yeah knows the
stuff so I think I think that there's a
lot
more a lot more breathing room when you
think about a local a local influencer
campaign then when it comes to like a
traditional influencer campaign and this
is the space for you to kind of like
Bend those corners and rules that you
couldn't like really be your your mass
Market campaign so no I think I think
you hit the the nail on the head uh with
that it's the those are definitely the
most underutilized types of people but
basically think about it like hey Man
Without social media who can actually
give people people come out yeah that's
it it's not really that deep you don't
have to get too crazy in terms of
branding or how you think about these
other people it's literally hey man my
brother has five friends that he can
convince cool like that's
it no different than throwing a regular
party and then last category is fans do
you have fans in the city and if you're
starting from Ground Zero you might not
have fans yet to activate in the city
per se um so you're building fans as a
part of this process but those are the
people that you want to network with
right you want to start identifying each
of these categories and and build your
network what's up everybody I'm happy to
announce that if you're looking for
oneon-one help with your marketing your
branding your rollouts we are back open
for enrollment with our once a year
program where we work with artists
directly or their teams to help build
out strategies for the marketing we dig
into your branding we dig into to your
music we can listen to your music help
you with management situations if that's
something that you need contracts all of
those things but the Crux of this is we
want to take you to your next level many
of the biggest case studies that y'all
have heard of mentioned typically come
from this program where we're talking
about working with me Andor Corey
directly so if you want that Insight you
can check out the link below this video
you can also go to No Labels necessary.
comomo
or in the podcast description wherever
you're listening and make us an
additional part of your team so when you
look at that link you'll see the ability
to schedu a call immediately or if spots
for the calls already filled up you'll
have to hop on the wait list just to let
you know literally half of the spots are
already taken at the time I'm recording
this and that's your fault if you're not
on our email list so you're just now
finding out about this because we
usually hit our email list up first make
sure you hop on that in the future but
long story short if you want to work
with us directly oneone hit us up link
in the description this is the part that
most people don't get and this is where
artists messed up and using their own
City and they mess this up really in the
industry as a whole you got to put
people in an order right of priority and
for me especially if we're talking about
building in our own City my order is
basically is is this list backwards fans
matter the most yeah right because if
you can bring out if you have fans that
mean you can do something in the city
that now lets everybody else know that
hey this person can bring people out M
and once people see you can bring people
out they feel like you have influence
and now you can get other people
involved right so it becomes this
snowball you don't necessarily need to
have these stakeholders then this is why
you have some artists like some uh one
of the artists we just mentioned um or
alluded to who can activate a city for
them personally without having to be
known by the radio personalities or
other artists in that City it's not
about being in the scene at all most
artists when they think about oh I gotta
be in this uh I'm trying to work through
my city they go to the underground scene
the scene that does a bunch of shows and
all these other artists and you work
through that but and it's so easy to get
stuck and styi by the politics and many
of things that we'll touch on later
right yeah I think too like even to your
point A lot of times your fan base is
probably going to be your first group of
in real life influencers right cuz I
think about some of the early events I
put together yes there will always be
you know that one guy or girl there that
came to the last event that loved it so
much that they invited 20 people out
from their college or they got five of
their friends come out so a lot of times
your step one of in real life influence
could come from your fan base if to your
point if you already have a fan base and
then if you don't then yeah I agree
you're kind of like figuring out the
order of those first two things do I get
the fans first and then use that to get
the in in real life influencers to [\h__\h]
with me or do I get the in real life
influencers to [\h__\h] with me to help me
get more of the local fans you just got
me coining something bro it's coming to
my mind it's your Fran base or your fan
base oh man I like that hey that's what
it is man cuz that's exactly what they
are like you'll have your friends that
also are your fans they're supporting
you right and then so that's usually
going to be your let's just say if you
throwing an event that's your very first
yeah group of people yeah group of
people who are gonna come out because
it's your friends and then you leverage
them but then you got to create an
experience that's good enough for the
people that were removed by one or two
orders to then say I'mma come back to
the second event because I liked it it
was a good time so you got your fans
that M matter the most the in real life
influencers which can be your friends
right your friend base but also other
people that you can recognize throughout
the city who have a little bit of um
leveraging and bring people out then you
have third the talent which are the
creatives of different types who might
have certain Aesthetics and um they
might create visual art they might
create cookies they might create Edibles
different things that might make sense
for your particular brand though
remember it has to match for your brand
and the cool part about it with just
those three alone you really don't even
have to get into the industry stuff you
don't even have to touch other artists
and collab people get stuck usually
people get stuck in the scene in their
City when they deal with their City's
version of the industry which is usually
when there's if you're a city industry
person solely then you probably don't
really you probably can't take anybody
far anyway just to be real and if you're
an artist collabing early
on then obviously y'all are stuck with
the same problem right but if I got fans
I got real life influencers and I have
talent and small like creatives and
small business people I have everything
I need other Talent is going to want to
come like other music Talent they're
gonna want to be associated with me
anyway because they realize I have a
movement or they're gonna hate on me
right but
like I can do everything I want to
because check this out the let's say if
I have an edible
brand um that comes and then I have this
other brand that is a lady who creates
this real dope jwy that it's on brand
for me right she this is going to have
people who like her jury and she's going
to advertise that she's at this event
right and that's going to bring out her
friends cuz her are going to come out
and support so now you have an audience
that comes out that's not even from your
core audience or your friend base or
your fan base so you're barrowing her
Fran base and her fan base and his fan
base and her his uh fan base and now
this is why it's so important for those
people to be around your aesthetic and
in your your
category because if you do that the
people that they bring out their friends
will more than likely appreciate your
experience yeah yeah it's like the same
way your your friend base and your fan
base is there to experience something
new their fan base and fan Bas is
feeling the same way exactly exactly and
that's how you capture those people and
you absorb them and now they yours now
like they my friends now get out of here
I don't even got to have you here next
time and then you got artist
collaborations and then you got industry
people the industry people are always
gonna find you if you really doing what
you're supposed to do that's the last
out of this whole category just do your
thing they will find you trust me from
the grimy slimy to the ones who who who
mean the best and actually can do
something for you you will be found so
if you have fans then you have your
friends and just real life influencers
and then you have your talent of
creatives and small business that you
can work with you will have everything
you need right now how do you bring this
together is an event that's the best way
to bring this together is not even not
even close uh we'll go through a couple
of of uh of the benefits of doing this
and why you should if you are not
convinced on why you should do an event
we are going to tell you why
and I feel sorry if you don't get it if
you don't click that was my nice way I
had other words in my head but an event
just a couple of things is one this is a
way to bring people together where you
can get footage that you share online
when you're talking about showing the
online audience I'm doing this thing in
real life that's the easiest way to show
people whoa people came out for me they
came to my thing I'm doing something so
the people in your city are going to see
this recorded event the people who are
online in a completely different state
part of the world will see that you have
done this recorded experience and people
enjoyed it and look at all the different
types of people who are in there so
that's my um that's my favorite thing
about it I got a second favorite thing
technically it might be arguing my first
but I want to know what your favorite
benefit is of doing an event in the real
world man I think just the confident
confidence boost you get to see like all
the stuff coming together cuz to your
point that's and I say this as a digital
marketer right like it's very easy to
get wrapped up in online presence it's
very easy to get wrapped up in numbers
you know when you see that you know
you've been promoting this event for the
last month and you were sad because your
promo post couldn't crack 2,000 views
but then 400 people show up you start to
really learn like how much some of the
stuff you stress about as an artist
doesn't matter once you start coming to
the real world stuff or you get a better
understanding of just human nature when
it comes to how many people online going
to say they going to pop out and support
but then you know 2,000 people in the
comments said I wish I could go I'll be
there but then 400 people showed up
right but you but you need that
understanding as as an artist um that's
a good one that's a good one real
because it gives you full perspective my
other favorite personally is also The
Branding aspect aspect of it like I kind
of and I don't mean the side of hey I
get to record this and show the rest of
the world that part of The Branding is a
very real thing but I think doing some
type of event is the best way for an
artist if you do it right to start
building their world yes you know what I
mean like because you get used to what
it looks like we we so many artists want
to build a world and experience as they
get bigger they kind of have this big
Vision but you can have this small
microcosm that you say I'm G to have for
a day I'm G to pick what the colors are
on the wall the design of what the
tickets look like uh the seating and the
the the the show General the production
and by the way when we say event we
truly mean event as a general term most
people will think hey this means I
should do a show no a show is usually
the thing you want to do when you have
fan fans and you can just bring out a
hell of a lot of people you want to do
an experience I'm going to leave that
General that's valuable and encompasses
those talents that we said like make
sense for from a creative side and
business side where you can bring in
these other vendors of different sorts
right that's that's one way to think
about it you want to create some type of
experience that helps you show people an
extension of who you are beyond your
music yeah right yeah I think too it's a
good um I mean going back to your point
about
using the above parts of the strategy to
kind of work your way to other music
artists and Industry professionals indry
industry professionals love a story of
um you know self-reliance like yo you
were the person you and your team were
able to go pull these resources together
and make this happen with it without me
because then they see how what their
resources are could add to like what
you're already doing and it shows work
at it right like damn bro you busted
your ass for a month and a half to put
together this event yeah you only
brought out 200 people but like you know
99% of arti would have never even
attempted to do what you did so you you
just you showed me something that I'm
not used to seeing from from other
artists and we're working on building up
um to your point your your world we're
working on building up your branding
we're able to test out elements of Your
World building that you know you said
that you would think it would be cool if
we if we had you know a a a tattoo shop
you know what I'm saying uh built at
your event but hey bro that's kind of
pricey let's just get one or two cool
two ours in the city to come out and
you'll still get the same benefit you'll
still get the same look and if that
works now we know it's worth it to go
put more money into this part of the
experience that you want to build out so
I think it is a good way for you to say
hey I have this bigger Vision but before
I go drop all this bread before I go you
know bust my ass to make it happen let
me try it on a small scale and see how
it works out and if I'm right I scale it
if I'm wrong then I am able to make
those tweaks and changes but on a scale
where like people won't really see it
unless I tell them about it you just
touched on what I was going to say next
which is scale in general like because
now that you've created this thing this
infrastructure you know what you went
through the motions you went through the
artist development beyond the music
right the development of your world and
now you can scale your world it's easy
to scale your world people people can
see the vision and so it's easy to bring
other people in and say this is what it
looks like this is what I've done and
they know how to connect that for you
it's so much easier in so many ways we
can go back to like let's use somebody
like L Russell right he did his backyard
show the pergola um everything that's
going on there records it puts it out
visually but then when it's time to blow
up right it's basically bring that
experience that energy of him to
different places right and you know what
to expect from him the vibe people get
all of that right and people who
appreciate that Vibe and want to be a
part of that Vibe they might not
necessarily go to it I might be another
artist who is a like a way bigger name
than you but I respect what you're do
and I like what I see and it reminds me
of something that I would do or would
want to do so now we're connected on the
back end you know what I'm saying like
and I'm reaching out and you're building
a relationship it we are in the
era we can only say it a billion times
where real life is the flex yeah doing
stuff in real life trust me will
separate you will really really will
separate you and having an event will
also give you give you something to
bring people out to so you can look at
it multiple ways from a fan standpoint
they can make a pilgrimage to your city
to go to this event obviously at some
point you might do something similar or
just have shows and do something that
they can reach in their own City but it
gives them something that they can pull
up to eventually I want to go to one of
his events on the other end you have
have um the networking if I just meet
jakori today and I could be like oh yo
man I man I do this little show thing
you should come out and some people are
going to say yes and then they gonna
pull up and say oh snap like is f yeah
this is hard this is serious I'm
connected with somebody who actually has
influence and they do a dope experience
cuz you went through multiple iterations
of improving that
experience and now you can just do that
over and over again where a lot of times
it's like oh yeah man let's go for
coffee or Etc like where you might not
be able to have that deep of a
conversation with that person yet um or
it just might may not make sense for you
to talk to that person until you'reall
ready to do collab or when you're in
album mode no something that's light
work where you could build a Goodwill if
I invited this person out to they came
it was no pressure because y'all not
even sitting down talking one-on-one
they might even brought a couple friends
with them or whatever for a night I
ain't have nothing to do tonight anyway
I used to do that when I was doing event
see like you could see people people
like all right cool he needed place to
bring his girl you know what I mean and
like I gave him a good treatment and now
he felt like he was you know a special I
give you two drink tickets bro yeah you
know what I mean like all that like that
is what you give yourself the ability to
do once you build something up and and
get good at it and then I will say
outside of like collecting data info
like obviously that's um something we
want to do with everybody in general if
you do this the right way but the offer
having an offer just like you have
somebody something to bring people out
to but this is also you have something
to get people to pay for or just
transact in general like even if it was
free for people to have to opt into the
experience and give their time is still
a way bigger barrier than what liking a
photo you know commenting on a photo
even a stream it's just such a deeper
level of interaction that when you have
that for people to again buy with their
time or buy with their time and money
you can start building that relationship
of yeah I'm willing to invest in this
artist you know what I mean you have to
give people a way to do that or they
might get caught in a groove of oh yeah
when I tap into this artist the only way
I tap in is I go stream them you're not
giving me another way and now I'm in the
habit of yeah that's just my preferred
way to tap in with you you know where
this other artist yeah I might go to his
show or this other artist I might buy
her her music like and then now you mad
it's like hey but but I stream you more
more than I stream anybody else I try to
tell people the artist that I've spent
the most with are not the artists I
stream the most
personally it sounds backwards but
people got to understand that that's a
good point man I a think my phone real
quick people got to think about it like
because one you have to have an offer in
the first place and I gotta be able to
find out about this offer right and I'll
spend some money with you and when I
spend with an artist I'm going to spend
usually a decent amount just out of
support and Out of Love
and that's not necessarily the artist
that I stream the most now you're right
man I'm looking at my my last 20 most
stream songs and I ain't been to nothing
for none of these artists I a't I ain't
bought nothing I ain't been to anything
it's a completely different game it's a
completely different game you know but
but then to your point most of it is
their fault they haven't given me
anything they haven't given you
something to buy you have to have an
offer man you have to have an offer the
more offers you have the the more people
will buy that's one of the things that
we talk about consistently that's one of
the things that we use uh you know
forever fan for so you can grab people's
information make certain offers Etc um
but like in
general I think
that it's funny how how many artists M
uh complain or managers and people
complain about like not making a certain
amount of money where they actually
people don't give people opportunities
to giving money yeah that's the big
unlock about um Pay What You Want by the
way or what what's the other term proud
to pay or like all these different
things right those terms because there
are people who want to spend money with
you and they want to give to you and
sometimes they just need a way to give
to you like you might they might buy a
shirt that they really don't care about
that much but they're not just about to
donate to you like it's Church
collection you know what I'm saying but
you gave me a shirt and you said I can
you know pay whatever I want know what I
really the way my life is set up I don't
even have time I just want to show you I
appreciate you I'mma give you $100 right
now for this shirt obviously it's not
worth $100 but now I just gave you my
yearly donation in this one thing like
it's almost like a convenience thing you
know versus some other people can't pay
as much but they can pay you something
right so they can pay that smaller
amount Etc like those are all like
there's many benefits I'll break down I
feel like a full video or something one
day um on like the proud to pay and why
it works in so many ways but yeah people
just don't have offers for people and
events are I tell you when when it gets
rolling it's one of the easiest offers
the best offers so with these two things
in in in mind strategy is primarily your
networking and thr some type of real
world event right and again this isn't
about the scene please go back through
the strategy section of how we talked
about it like this is isn't about
getting deep in your scene we didn't
even mention hey go find all the people
in the underground scene and be around
them and collab with a bunch of artists
you don't have to do any of that however
if you have your ducks in a row you can
partake and then get the benefits of
that and pull them up but uh we should
get to the avoidance section because I
was about to mention something the fun
part yeah we were about to avoid these
things so number one we talk about
avoiding Hometown scene in general
getting caught up in the scene but avoid
doing too many showcases is the first
thing we have it's a big one easy cuz it
feel makes you feel like you're doing
something you feel cheap man and now
people see you all the time it's good to
do it from a for a sense of practice for
performance but never do a showcase and
think you're doing anything valuable for
the growth of your brand all right the
anything valuable for the growth of your
actual fan base that's not what it's
about go out where you might have a
relationship with somebody and you might
be doing them a favor or something so
that might make sense or you're just
developing giving yourself another rep
from a performance standpoint yeah I
would argue like unless you know it's a
it's a big showcase like it's something
well branded you know I don't know sound
cloud is doing a Showcase in your city
oh yeah or you're using it for a Content
moment you know we talked about it
earlier well on a different episode
maybe right sometimes you can use these
showcases to get some good production
content you know what I'm saying for
cheap on the fly if it's not not one of
those two situations I would argue you
shouldn't be doing more than like two to
three showcases a quarter you know what
I'm saying like no more than that you
know what I'm saying and again that
showcase like you said for Content
that's another example of showing your
fans and people online that you're doing
this in real life yeah a strateg to it
it's not you're not just popping out
just because to your point the homie you
know what I'm saying club promoter asked
you to come out it's like uh now I have
a vision here I wanted to show this
message I need a venue to help me show
this message so cool I'll go do this
showcase versus like oh I'm just doing a
bunch of showcases cuz I think that this
is the way you know what I'm saying that
that'll cheapen your brand 100% easy
then next we have local politics man
avoid the local politics avoid the local
politics whatever that looks like in
your city man every city got local
politics every city got people that went
to high school together that don't like
each other and that bleeds over into the
work that they do every city got it man
we can't go too in depth because that
looks different for every place but
whatever that is for you and your city
avoid it and if you don't dabble too
much in your scene you know you kind of
stay out you do you do stay out um then
also don't have too many artists at your
personal event yeah right so a lot of
people just think oh I'm G to have a
bunch of artists and then that means
they're gonna bring all their friends
and and and their fans and then I'll
have a big event one your events are not
about being big when you're trying to
build like it's about quality and then
you get bigger through doing quality
reps and people love it and the Brand
Build and of it of in and of itself but
if you just try to bring a lot of big
people uh bring a lot of people out out
the gate trust me it's not the move but
if you just bring out a bunch of artists
performing artists other music artists
it's just G to feel like a showcase yeah
exactly and you're probably being lazy
because you're not actually building out
an experience beyond that you should
always think about
your experience that you want the fans
to have from a brand standpoint insert
yourself and then insert other artists
and how they can fit into that
experience when we're talking about
music artist yeah I agree I agree it
definitely shouldn't be just because
they have a
following yep the biggest killer of it
to me is the homie artist you know you
got to put your boys on or put your your
homie you also no you don't you know
what I'm saying make bro G be a ticket
know the guy clipping tickets at the
door bro he can help in other ways but
to your point it's like I look at it
like if you have amount of slots that
you feel like you can give out for
Creative Talent OR music artist
performance most of the good ones in my
opinion really only need like one or two
other artists that aesthetically tied to
the event cuz to your point yes the way
I would look at it if I was if I was
them is if I wasn't a one putting this
event together would I have came here
you know what I'm saying and and most of
the instances what artists put on just a
bunch of artist if you would have asked
them like yo would you have went to
something like this if it wasn't your
event 99% of them would say no you know
what I'm saying you ask him why why why
would you why would you go man there too
many artists bro I don't know all these
[\h__\h] like [\h__\h] get boring and it's
like so why did you do it bro like why
did you do the same thing and you know
as and I think it also speaks to like
sometimes how little artists think about
the consumer standpoint right for the
artist is like oh this is far I want to
put all my homies on everybody F you
know what I'm saying everybody we gonna
trick everybody to to coming into this
room and watching us and watching us
exactly it's like it awkward but it's
like to me that shortterm thinking right
cuz you know like said you've done
events I've done EV and I know like one
of the big things we will always talk
about is okay I would rather there be 50
people in the room that witness
something amazing yes then there'll be
500 people in the room that witness
something mediocre because the 50 people
that witness something amazing they're
going to make sure the next event has
200 people or 300 people the 500 people
that saw something mediocre are going to
be the reason why your next event only
has 50 people left you know what I'm
saying cuz they're going to be the ones
like oh yeah I saw it event last time
that [\h__\h] was kind of whack bro he just
had like eight artists come out on stage
and like there was like a ice cream guy
in the corner that was kind of cool but
like you know he ran out you know what
I'm saying 30 minutes into the show and
like I end up leaving like 30 minutes in
but it wasn't really worth it
so you just accelerating your demise I
want to bring as many witnesses to this
bad show this [\h__\h] yeah exactly
bro and give them the task of telling
the rest of the world never come see me
again that is what you're doing and and
too man I'll say this it's not true for
all artists but when you were the one
putting together an event and this is I
think I do think every artist should put
together in EV event to understand how
they act to other people cuz then you
get you start saying like how much ARS
be tripping when it comes to stuff like
this bro like over little [\h__\h] like just
stuff that don't make sense and from my
experience the smaller and more local
the artist is the more difficult they
are to work with you know what I'm
saying got zero followers got a whole
writer yeah got a whole writer
everything that you need I need public
sandwiches not with turkey not I want 20
people on stage like man yeah so you
know you get see um you get to see the
dark sides of artistry that you don't
get to see when you are the artist and
that also helps you to understand like
yo let me not be like that when I go
talk to other people facts and then
here's a big one avoid not doing things
outside of the scene yeah in general
especially if you for some reason start
to interact and get caught up in the
scene and that looks like um many
opportunities the most obvious is if I
go to another state and do something
like you mentioned if I did a show in
New York and I'm in Atlanta all the
people that see me in New York in
Atlanta are like oh man he's like
approved in other places he has
connections so that lets them know
psychologically he doesn't need me
completely all right so I'm you build
more respect for yourself as an
individual entity which kind of takes
you away from some of the Politics as
well locally because they know they
can't give the idea the only reason
people come to his event is me right and
then things like that yeah yeah all like
there's a lot of things yeah when you
open that so just make sure you're doing
things but it also can be other stuff in
your own city that is outside of your
scene you're interacting with people
with and I don't again you don't have to
be in the scene but just bring in people
and do things where it's like I was able
to bring out people and I didn't engage
anybody in this particular scene but I'm
doing this event that that now that
they're somehow hearing about or I uh
worked with this organization in the
city that has nothing to do with whoever
these people are that might be
considered your scen so the more that
you do in other places no different than
when people say oh man my city isn't
going to respect me until I blow up some
other place first it's the same thing
when we're talking about dealing with
your scene whether you're blowing up on
the other side of your city in terms of
you know um more professional
organizations or bringing out fans
without being involved or when you build
out in another city all together yeah
and I would add that too you know you
know of course you should be doing stuff
outside like you said build that
validation in your scene by proving to
them like hey I am making momentum and
some of that too also I think does have
to do with the artist like social media
presence right like like when that when
that local rapper looks at your
Instagram and he see those Nigerian
Flags in your comments you know I'm
saying that says something to bro you
know what I'm saying like when he when
he uh can go look at your Tik Tok and
see you yeah reposting fan videos you
know from the the the kid in Nebraska
that likes you or something like that
that says something so it's like you
should also be doing all of the things
that people like us say to do to grow as
an artist in general while doing these
things because then you will stand out
in the scene like cuz that to me is
usually where the stigma of the
underground scene comes from it's not
necessarily like small artists in the
city at least to me I think that's how I
generally looked at to me I look at it
as small artist in a city who refuse to
move like artist should currently be
moving cuz usually like the scene is
like very stok on like how things used
to work you know what I'm saying
Atlanta's a huge one bro Atlanta used to
be one of those cities where you could
come back in the day do a couple
showcases and have a have a name in the
city you know what I'm saying it don't
it don't really work that way no more
you know what I'm saying like you know
um but I think that if you modernizing
yourself as a artist in terms of how you
move how you're gaining fans um you know
so you're applying some of the The
General broad stroke stuff and you're
doing this stuff then yeah when you step
in these showcases or I mean you step
into your events or you step into your
local scene it's
almost I want to say it's like a
blessing but it's almost like they start
to feel like yo we see you doing so much
like it's almost an honor that you would
even put together something like this
here because and we know how much of
music is just perception like building
and maintaining certain perceptions so
like you might have went to that show in
New York and there could have been like
10 people there you know what I'm saying
you angled the camera right that [\h__\h]
look fun they seen you posting the fly
when you get home they going be like man
bro we see you making moves man we see
you really out here taking this [\h__\h]
together your next event let me XYZ you
know what I'm saying let's make sure you
blah blah blah blah blah for your next
showcase and then that stuff starts to
like build up and then yeah to your
earlier point now you have these
resources and um the knoow to build a
prototype of Your World to be able to
sell to your fans and to the potential
investors that you want to buy in and
make it bigger
exactly exactly man and that to me like
goes straight into the idea of expanding
your Marketing in general so we went
through multiple things of like what you
should do networking um how you
categorize that we went through having
an event but the next level of this is
now marketing to your city you made a
couple of connections whatever that
looks like um and then you have your
event but all right how do I look bigger
even bigger to my city how do I look
like I'm doing more outside the scene so
you might pay for an influencer right M
that influencer has to be a regional
influencer we don't talk we don't talk a
lot about Regional influencers at all we
don't we use them but we never really
hear other people talk about them but a
regional influencer is somebody who blew
up from a certain region they're from a
certain region and they have impact on
their region they might have a global
audience at one point but because of
where they were from
they have an audience that skews in that
area or they have a lot of respect for
people in that area the way you can find
these people because I know a lot of
people are going to ask is just think
about artist that you oh no not
necessarily artist any type of
influencer that you know that is from
your area and you know a lot of people
in your area know who they are MH that's
all you really need to know you don't
need to necessarily go into their social
media stats and look like no just if a
lot of people in your area know who they
are and you know they happen to be in
that area and kind of like claim or
openly let it be known then you already
know that there's a good chance that
this is that type of person then you
also have City Publications like every
city you well a lot of cities have um
magazines yeah magazines covering the
city whether it's a IG page or a real
life magazine but you stick you figure
that out yourself for your own City and
then we got in real life Regional
influencers so we talked about in real
life influence like hey Cory can bring
out four girls or something like that
well what does that look like in other
cities and other connections you know
that you can make in real life that are
just again not necessarily music
industry people just people that you
know who can who can bring people out
and now you start connecting with them
and getting the word out about yourself
in other cities around you last but not
least meta ads you want to go deep on
The Meta ads thing or yeah I mean I
think really all the ads could probably
apply but I think I would say meta ads
if you're looking for more
so what am I trying to say like if
you're if if conversion amount matters
for you you know what I'm saying if it's
not if it's a I personally like if it's
purely a brand awareness play probably
YouTube ad do really great yeah in a
sense if you if you care about conver I
want to Market in my city and I want to
collect the email or I want to get a
stream you know and I want to get a
follower meta if it's just like I just
want a bunch of people to see me in the
space and I don't care yeah what they do
after that probably YouTube ad but um
but I would say out of all of these
things of all the marketing strategies
ads are for sure the easiest to start
because you don't have to go look for
nobody there's you know no real research
other than the research to how to run a
good ad um and it's budget friendly
right you know we know meta ads um
YouTube ads too I believe are very
budget friendly you can work with almost
any dollar amount and the great thing
about running ads to a specific region
versus when you're doing more of your
general campaigns is that um you don't
need to spend as much necessarily cuz
you're targeting a smaller pool of
people and the organic from it can
happen a lot faster I might be paying $2
a click to push to Atlanta whereas I pay
50 cents a click when I push to the
whole us but I can feel the influence of
the that click in Atlanta kind of moving
a lot faster so it's it's a little bit
of like I would say it takes a little
bit of like marketing maturity to know
how to read the ass situations and not
completely like compare them to like
your other marketing situations that
won't look nothing like bro we going to
make that a thing marketing maturity is
a real thing marketing maturity good
Lord cuz you know but you need the
marketing maturity to go like man I'm
running ad to Atlanta these [\h__\h] suck
because they're doing $2 where my last
ad was doing 30 cents but then your last
ad was running to Brazil and you spent
$1,000 on it you know what I'm saying
it's like bro what you expect bro like
you know but that that's a whole
different ation but but ads are to me
the easiest way to start meta YouTube
ads are a great start if you have
experience in a Twitter or a Snapchat or
whatever your preferred ad platform is
all of them at this point can regionally
Target places but meta YouTube are
probably the most budget friendly and
easiest to start with but and this is
another episode of No Labels necessary
I'm Rand man Sean and I'm Cory we out
peace