branding yourself as a mysterious artist
today is not the same way you would do
it back in the day you have to think
completely differently in your approach
and is mysterious branding even worth it
that's what we're going to talk about
today let's get it what's up I'm
Brandman Sean and my agency has helped
over 100 artists grow their fan base and
get millions of streams that's not to
sell you anything but to let you know
who you're getting the information from
let's get into this video branding
yourself as a mysterious artist today is
not the same as it was yesterday and if
you don't understand these few key
things that we're gonna go over in this
video and try to make yourself a
mysterious brand you will fail so to
start the first thing you have to
understand is the spectrum of mystery
right you have mystery you have known
and you have saturated and there's some
segments in between this right right you
have known you got it well known but
then you have saturated and actually you
have something above that which is over
saturated right and everybody is so
afraid of over saturating problem is
most people worry about that before they
even are even known right why are you
worried about being oversaturated when
people don't even know who you are yet
which brings me to the dangerous part of
worrying too much about mystery when you
are in fact
on
unknown
all right when you're unknown
that's actually a different path very
similar effects and impacts that feel
but a lot of people don't quite
understand the difference right yes you
know oh people know me or not but you
don't know where you are on your path
because a lot of times people think
they're playing with some mystery but
really they're impacting them being
known in the first place and mystery
looks like this right
they have to at least get up to known
right and then they can come back down
to mystery right you could go up to
saturation and come down to mystery but
you have to at least hit known first why
is that
if I don't know you how can I find you
mysterious mystery is a seduction dance
of wanting more and not getting more I
have to want to know your name before I
find you mysterious right I have to have
a curiosity about where you're from
right what was the idea behind this song
What was the concept behind the music
video I have to be curious about that
and not get that information until I
find before before I can find you
mysterious if I don't watch the music
video
then I don't care about the behind the
scenes I don't want to know more about
the artist right mysterious is when
people want to know more and they're not
getting that right and how can they have
that without this right here knowing
being aware so first you gotta Escape
unknown right now with that being said
there's a massive risk in today's
Marketplace when it comes to this social
media era in trying to remain completely
mysterious
traditional mystery does not work
anymore why because people want to know
about you they want to have a certain
amount of information right to be
connected to you if they aren't
connected to you to a certain extent
then they'll just go to the next option
there's another artist that they love
right you don't have to be over
saturated but there's a middle ground
between
known and mystery on this path on the
way back what is that called
that is called
hopefully you can read this
this is called Mystique that's m y s t i
q u e
Mystique right now what's the difference
between mystery and Mystique mystery
maybe just follow the path it's deeper
right than a Mystique Mystique is that
middle ground and it allows you to exist
in today's era of be where people need
more than they used to but you still can
have oh and it allows you to exist in
today's era people need a little bit
more than they used to have while still
having much of the impact of mystery
because mystery has always been a
dangerous game right if you look at an
artist like Prince back in the day he
had a Mystique about him right he could
only be mysterious but for so long for
people to wonder but you have to give
and take and give them just enough for
them to then feel like they've connected
to remind them that you exist right over
a long period of time you can't just
stay completely mysterious because
people you start to fall back into
unknown or even worse right because
mystery can go this path you might not
even see that Arrow but indifference
people just don't care they're no longer
wondering there's not enough connection
so Mystique has always been a thing but
it's even more apparent now not to even
fall deep enough into the mystery side
of things so you can maintain the
potency in terms of your relationship
with your audience so let me use this as
an example when YouTube came out the
internet started popping Prince didn't
want his music on the internet he owned
his music right he's well known for
getting that ownership of his music and
then wanting control of everything and
what it wanted it to be monetized
correctly right well
with it not being on YouTube for a
significant period of time that
prevented the newer generation from even
being able to know him that prevented
many of the people who already knew and
loved him from being able to connect
with him the same way especially the the
younger Generations that were in that
bridge they knew of them but they didn't
fully like fan out on them just yet
because they weren't those older adults
who I don't need the internet to connect
with him I've I've made all my
significant connections with artists
right so he was in a dangerous part of
time where he had mystery right because
now you're wondering you want to hear
more of his music but you can't connect
with it and life is passing by for these
young folks who have all the options in
the world right now so what are some
examples modern wise now you have her
her she came out mysterious it's a very
expensive strategy by the way if you
want to come out the gate mysterious and
especially in this day and age but her
was able to do it because resources and
capital all of these things
if you pay attention though right over
time she couldn't maintain that mystery
because it will become novel that's
another problem with mystery mystery has
a novelty to it and it wears off right
it's cool to do it first oh man nobody
knows who it is it creates conversation
that's great but after a certain period
of time if you don't have any value
beyond that it doesn't matter right and
the stakes become higher and higher the
more your mystery becomes a pick
conversation for you to be able to match
something that validates that level of
conversation and interest so mystery
becomes a high high risk game to play
where people begin to even just turn on
you have you ever seen when a song takes
too long to roll out and people start to
turn on the artist and say yo fine we're
just going to move on like you're taking
I'm tired of it you keep giving me this
roll out you keep saying it's going to
come out you keep pushing the album back
or the song long back
I'm just gonna move on with life I've
already heard enough
that's it right that's the same effect
of waiting too long to give more beyond
your mystery so her she started to
connect beyond that by giving a little
bit of her face here and there small
moments it wasn't like yo I'm a
completely different artist now and now
I'm going to saturate you and go the
traditional route but it was like okay
I'm gonna remove some of this mystery in
a traditional sense and open myself up
more to connect that way that isn't a
novel thing that I I seem to be relying
on now it's just like weekend cutting
off his hair right he cut off his hair
so he wasn't as reliant on it right he
stopped being as mysterious and started
to show his face like unlike what he was
doing in the beginning because he wasn't
relying on the novelty of the mystery
because that easily goes away and
there's far more benefits to actually
being known and being recognizable than
there is to being this complete
mysterious character right so you want
to be in that Middle Ground Mystique
Mystique Mystique you look at Playboy
cardi right he's known by his fans and
his Niche right and he doesn't always
put himself out there all the time but
he comes out just enough for you to
still feel like okay I know what he
likes I know his style right he's just
in certain places right you're not going
to see me everywhere but you're gonna
see me some places you're going to have
enough information about me to feel like
you can connect with me relate with me
feel like you can follow my style and
how I move and mimic that yourself so
you can buy into this lifestyle those
things you can't get when someone's
completely mysterious there's a lack of
connection that exists there so Mystique
Works far far better now whatever a
couple strategies that you can utilize
to make sure that you're an artist that
has Mystique well the main concept at
the core of Mystique marketing is
you're not the person who's promoting
yourself self-promotion you can see that
all across the board so many artists
posting their own stuff right heavily uh
talking about what they're doing a lot
of radio interviews or other types of
interviews but the Mystique marketing
push looks a little different instead of
you talking and your face being out
there as much it's more so other people
talking about you you have to generate
that conversation through others right
whether that's a publication a YouTube
page an Instagram page you have to have
people talking about you versus you
talking about yourself remember
mystery where people get wrong right
about this mysterious thing and Mystique
is they think oh
I'm just not gonna do as much and that's
going to make it happen no the reality
is the same amount of activity has to
happen right funny enough
you still have to hit this threshold
known right it looks a little different
though right they have to know that
you're dropping a project they have to
know who you are in the first place they
have to know that you're working on a
rollout all of that same amount of
activity and energy has to be put out
there but it's just coming from a
different Source right it's not coming
from you so that can be more expensive
that's why I referenced earlier that
being a mysterious artist can be more
expensive especially when you're
launching right from the beginning
Beyonce or somebody who already has a
following right can drop something out
of nowhere and immediately social media
takes off and all this marketing happens
for them organically because they've
built that brand Equity where people are
waiting on them people care but a brand
new artist doesn't have that so you now
have to pay people do all types of
favors to appear on these Pages since
you can't rely on your own when you're
doing mysterious brand and continue to
make that investment everything single
time you want to generate some type of
awareness right I can't just talk about
my project 50 times on my own page I
have to pay for 50 posts right and only
talk about it three times on my page
because like you still can have some
outward promotion but it looks a little
different it can't look forced right you
have to make it feel like the world's
talking about you and you're just doing
your part dropping some water in a
bucket versus creating the bucket or
filling the bucket up yourself right
slightly different Nuance but again
Mystique is what last all right mystery
especially in today's era
that can quickly become indifference
right it can quickly become we don't
care so you're not trying to be
mysterious what you're trying to do is
have a mistake where people care about
you right you can think about Frank
Ocean there's so many artists that have
a Mystique and they they unknowingly
right mischaracterize it as mystery when
truly it's people care about this person
that person can be strategic and do
whatever they want
but at the same time fans don't fault
them for it the media still cares
whenever they do whatever they want if I
fall back right it's cool but when I
come out there's a meaning assigned to
what I'm putting out right there's
impact associated with what I'm putting
out all right so these are some of the
things that you want to think about when
it comes to being a mysterious artist
right which is number one today you
don't want to be mysterious you want to
have a Mystique that gives you the
freedom it allows you to move and do
everything that you want to do from
Brand collaborations your face can be
out there you can do a show but you
don't have to do it Ad nauseam like so
many other artists who are everywhere
all the time having to move a shake
having to go to Every club or having to
do every single radio interview
that is what most artists don't desire
right creating that feeling of annoying
people and being oversaturated always
having to be in them their faces that is
what artists are trying to avoid
Mystique doesn't have any of those
effects but they don't have the risk of
people not caring at all like mystery
and you can't afford to take that risk
today especially if you don't have a
massive budget to force people into
caring again all right so that's mystery
those are some of the things you should
think about we have a lot of videos on
mystery you can check them out over here
or over there wherever we put the video
right but we've got a entire playlist on
mystery check it out and break it down