you know thousand dollars a week good
100 four weeks times 52 weeks that's
fifty two thousand dollars that's a
starting salary at a nice consulting job
so hey I'm all the way to the good what
I learned very quickly about projections
is that we often believe that the market
will be more receptive to our offering
than in reality it is Oh what's up
everybody once again his brand man Shawn
and today I got a special guest for you
guys none other than Ryan Leslie now we
talk about things from his early
beginnings all the way into hacking his
way into Harvard at 15 years old and at
one point living in the basement to him
breaking into the nth music industry and
tricking Peabody into thinking his song
was a hit before it really was a hit and
of course it's a Superfund which has
been used by so many artists from cardi
B Rory and a lot of other artists you
wouldn't even expect and then we end
with Ryan Leslie telling you how to text
them because it wouldn't be Ryan Leslie
if he did now let's hop into it is I
know it couldn't have always been that
easy alright so you see smart guy this
guy went to Harvard you see he's been
through the industry and he now he's in
this tech thing he keeps winning how did
it start off started off seriously my
parents my parents are musicians so god
my dad actually started a band so that
he could get my mom to come rehearse for
him and with him and I mean I believe
that when you're talking about
relationships relationships are really
built on two main elements one is
frequency of contact - is proximity so
even before I had super phone my father
already had figured this out with my mom
and said look I need to be in contact
yeah
I need to figure out a system or
structure in which we'll be in contact
frequently and we'll be close together
we spend a lot of time so he started a
band and made her the lead singer and
primary game yeah and I think honestly
they were they being in the Salvation
Army also
administrators and officers in the
Salvation are beating the Salvation Army
they wanted myself and my sister to have
a different life path mmm and not that
they weren't advocates of a service
career mm-hmm they just knew that but
for generating wealth right yes you can
be in the service business the
non-profit service business is
antithetical to generating wealth per se
so which is why you find a lot of folks
they make a lot of money and then they
become philanthropists afterwards and so
even though the Salvation Army generates
I think four billion dollars a year in
donations that revenue the the thesis
and the spirit of Salvation Army is
sacrificed yourself in the service of
others so every Christmas every
Thanksgiving before we even ate we
always serve the community so yeah I
mean that means that I basically grew up
eating government cheese and having the
same meals that that were provided to
the people that the Salvation Army
served yeah and we made it happen you
know my parents actually you know oh I
think you're right a lot of folks don't
actually know the backstory right my
parents made it happen raised a family
of four on the equivalent of you know
about $800 a month and so for folks that
are out there struggling and folks that
are out there that are counting their
money in penny-pinching I know what it
means to make ends meet with a very very
limited budget and so my father wanted a
different life for me and so he believed
as many parents did that education was
going to be the way to get us there
right and when I say us I'm talking
about myself and my sister so my sister
has her master's degree she went to UC
Berkeley myself applied very early to
Harvard
that in finished yeah yeah 50 year old
get into Harvard listen anything is
possible
any any goal is possible his own you set
your mind to it and I think my father
had had a really really specific compass
and direction
for me and so anytime I come you know
I'm done with my homework he would say
well I got this SAT practice test you
can do and one of the well I guess in
reading and researching the SATs he
realized that standardized tests are
mostly a function of how familiar you
are with the test as opposed to how
smart you are and so the more practice
tests you take the more familiar you are
with the actual test or and what they
found is that folks that are more
familiar with the kinds of questions
perform better on standardized tests and
so I took a lot of practice tests I
score very well and yeah got into
Harvard very early yeah and my parents
were kind of devastated when I told him
I wanted to do music and I looked at
them I said well you know I was born out
of music you your romance was kindled on
the foundation of this musical seminary
and they said well you know music is a
hot meat man you know music it came
really easy for us as as parents my
mother is a classically classically
trained pianist and so they you know
especially in the Caribbean island
everybody does music they play whatever
they play brass instruments etcetera so
I really looked at it as a hobby and I
think also most parents if you're
listening now and you have this idea
that you know people don't understand
your dream of wanting to do music or be
an entrepreneur or create most parents
they just have an innate instinct to
protect you from the personal risk of
trying to do a career that's highly
competitive and music as you know I mean
you talk about this on your show all the
time the independent grind deciding to
do music is very very it's a challenge
and it's a challenge that you know it
takes a certain mentality to want to be
able to do that kind of work so speaking
about mentality then like how do you
take graduating from Harvard like this
everybody's already looking at you as
like some kind of big motor they're
praising you at that moment right you're
young and you graduated from a school
like this and you're going the complete
opposite direction most of those guys
Sultan's lawyers things like that how do
you kind of take up the the gravitas to
actually say no I'm gonna go this
completely different paths like that's
big for anybody but you're only 19 at
that yeah
listen up I believe that you should when
you're young mm-hmm take the biggest
risks take the biggest risk when you're
young did you think like that while you
were young though well I gave the
Harvard oration when I when I graduated
so the way that works is Harvard at the
time and I don't know if it's changed
since there is no valedictorian at
Harvard so if you want to give the
speech the Harvard oration where you
actually speak to your classmates you
just have to compete and win a speech
competition whoever has the best beach
wins and so I wrote this speech and my
speech was really about doing what you
believe in believe in what you do and
really was was written specifically to I
mean almost coach myself and coax myself
to overcome the apprehension that I had
about striking out on my own and saying
I wanted to do music versus the more
traditional pathway that education would
have taken me so what was the first step
BAM once you are you graduated now
you're out here you haven't been
spending time really training for this
field I do be in building connections
what was the first thing you did maybe
in the industry man I really I think
looking back I really thought that the
music business because my favorite
artists were multi-instrumentalist so
Princeton Stevie Wonder okay yeah and
also when you think about the
songwriting process of Michael Jackson I
I believe that and and just the dancing
talent and the and the vocals of Michael
Jackson I believe that music was a
meritocracy so what I meant
we're just what I mean yes flow down
from you who don't understand
meritocracy yeah that's just basically
saying that it's all about talents yes
yes wins yeah and it's not that yeah
well that's what I believed and so you
ask me what my what my steps where my
steps were become the greatest music
producer that I could possibly
without a teacher so and this was even
pre I mean right now I mean if you think
about when how I started and how I
started to communicate my art to the
world it really started to take off when
YouTube began right and YouTube began I
was able to actually film my studio
sessions and put them online so when I
was coming up these are the kinds of
videos I wish I could have seen I was
learning how to produce music by just
listening to my favorite producers
Timbaland Jermaine Dupri my favorite
records musher records etc and these are
guys that were same age as me and we're
already killing in the music industry
like Usher
uh sure nos a major so seeing somebody
like that and listening to the sound
that Jermaine Dupri had crafted for him
was really to me very very inspirational
and I wanted to be able to emulate that
sound and so I really believed that
listen if you were good enough to make
that sound you would just make it and so
that was that was for me the the the
guiding principle in my mind and that
really I had to I had to learn some hard
lessons about just being great as a
musician you know it's it's when you're
just great as a musician when that is
disconnected from networking like your
first question was a yeah where you are
a networking having connections yeah I
believe that there's now a more
prevalent understanding that in order to
be successful you need to really be
intentional about your relationships and
your relationship building back then as
a as a you know late team early 20 year
old I really truly believe that it was
just all about skill and talent and that
someone would just plug me out of
obscurity and give me a chance and it
would work that way man so how did you I
guess how did you say you would learn
that listening who was that person who
really did finally bring you in and did
you just wake up one day and say oh I
need to go this isn't working I got to
do something else yeah I uh I made a I
made a very crude business plan and the
crude business plan was I was gonna sell
beats for two-letter dollars
a pop and the projection that I had was
I could sell five beats a week she made
me a thousand dollars a week and back
that we talked about late 90s early 2000
man you know a thousand dollars a week
good - four weeks times 52 weeks that's
fifty two thousand dollars that's a
starting salary at a nice consulting job
so hey I'm all the way to the good what
I learned very quickly about projections
is that we often believe that the market
will be more receptive to our offering
than in reality it is and so I really
was more selling a couple beats per
month and the economics were upside down
and I found myself just hanging out on
my dad's couch I mean first of all I was
moonlighting in the Harvard dorm after I
graduated you know cuz my key card still
worked in Italy basically it illegally
in the basement of one of the Harvard
dorms and using the studio and sneaked
it upstairs to use the showers and still
have my key card for the laundry just
trying to figure it out and I believed
that it was gonna happen and so now
thinking back I want a competition with
with one of my good friends from Berklee
College of Music his name is Latif Corey
light 'if he got signed to Motown and
really it was directly correlated to
relationships so that competition got us
in front of a bunch of record executives
at the Apollo Theater Corey performed
killed the performance and there were a
lot of interested parties and had I
known then what I know now I think that
the trajectory would have been greatly
accelerated and I wouldn't change
anything at all because I believe that
that pathway was was was requisite for
me to actually have the knowledge and
the learnings that I have now and the
ability to actually productize it now so
that a whole nother generation of
musicians and entrepreneurs can learn
from my story and actually accelerate
their success reduce the
a dependency on luck in their success
trajectory and I believe in that I
believe that you can create your own
luck as long as you're intentional about
the relationships and so I think that is
great in this interview that your first
question in terms of how someone
achieved success is who are you
networking with because it is really
success a happens at the speed of
communication and is directly correlated
to who you know and not only who you
know but how well you're communicating
with those people interesting so I mean
I guess that leans towards why you're
basically focusing currently on super
phone right sure everything Center for
super phone is relationship relationship
relationship
let's keep in contact with people yes
describe super phone from your
perspective yeah the mind said they got
you into creating it yeah yeah and this
is a super phone for me was just based
on the idea that social connections a
week I started with YouTube in MySpace
and then all of a sudden when everyone
migrated away from MySpace where were
all my friends
that all these myspace friends and then
I started to build on Facebook and then
Facebook caps you at 5,000 friends and
if you have more than 5,000 friends you
have to get a page and then then there
was the advent of Twitter and Instagram
and I had all these social connections
more than a million followers across all
these platforms that I felt ridiculously
disconnected from all of these social
connections and when you really think
about the activity of liking a picture
or maybe leaving a comment the expected
response time is really low so if you
left a comment on dj khaled or you left
a comment for Drake or you liked the
Chris Brown picture do you really expect
a response and what I found is that you
know because my fans didn't expect the
response the actual relationship was
very very weak and so when I decided hey
you know check out my latest video check
out my latest song check out my latest
project the response yeah maybe I got
some lights and comments I felt like I
was very
disconnected with the people that really
wanted to be connected and so I started
giving my phone number out because I
just wanted I feel like the phone number
is overlooked as one of the greatest
most powerful social handles and what I
mean by that is once you get someone's
number and I mean that's why when you
know when you first start dating you go
out you know it's all about y'all got
her number that's you know and nowadays
I mean I I guess some people will say yo
you know let me get your gram they
following the grass exactly is that
right because you're not making phone
calls over Instagram yeah so for me it
was really just about I want to be able
to have that kind of relationship at
scale with all the people that wanted to
support me and I needed to be able to
build some automation and and leverage
technology to be able to have that kind
of personal one-on-one touch at scale
and when I say at scale I mean across
thousands and tens of thousands so today
in in this phone right now my
conversation feed I have over 76,000
active conversations with people who
have ever texted me and if Instagram
shuts down tomorrow if Twitter shuts
down tomorrow Facebook shuts down
tomorrow I can literally spend the rest
of my life just calling every single fan
thanking them and I could also if I
wanted to if I wanted to just press a
button and send a thank-you text to
everyone that's ever supported me
because I know the difference between
people who bought my album and who have
it so that's where it started but with
that being said because I think it's a
very loose idea sounds cool for anybody
just hearing it from outside but kind of
what we do like a scenario because when
I first already had a perception I was
used to see our ends and things like
that but when you show me something back
in gonna lose my mind to a whole other
level
example of you going you can see what
city they're in yes and if they were
working at Starbucks they yeah that
walked it well what people through what
it's like the super fun experiences yeah
well I mean this interview is is
directly correlated to super fun right
so I'll say this I I checked my messages
every morning just like anyone else you
know and someone you know asked me one
day like hey Brian I want to sign up for
super fun I said well how'd you hear
well I heard about for brandish on so
then I the the the beauty of that is
that I could then just go look up that
we had met whether it was ace 8 3 C or
wherever we had met we the exchange
information I could shoot you a text I
mean it's very very powerful when you
have a direct phone number on people
because Europe you're able to to make
that success happen very accelerated and
so the super phone experience is very
simple
people text you your phone knows who is
already in your phonebook and who's new
for everyone that's new your phone
automatically says hey let me get some
more info what's your name your email
your city and then at that point I can
also integrate my e-commerce so I have
MGR t.com where I sell all my
experiences and merchandise and
everything and it will tell me how much
every single person in my phone has
spent and I also have a have the ability
that to apply tags to people into
conversation so I can if I wanted to
right now I could say hey these are the
312 people that are investors that I
know these are the 125 people I know who
are photographers and videographers
these are the 60 people I know who are
journalists these are the 85 people I
know who are DJs and as I was doing this
for myself I started to realize that
most people just don't have this kind of
organization to the conversations in
their life period and so I wanted to and
it really ignited a passion within me to
build a product that was easy to use
that was already taken advantage of back
to our daily activity probably our most
important daily activity is our
communication yeah we have to eat we
have to breathe okay we have to we use a
restroom we have to sleep and then aside
from all of those human necessities our
most important daily activity I believe
is communication and the fact that most
people's communication is totally
disorganized there's no fault of our own
but most people's communication is
totally disorganized and also the fact
that most people that we meet jump into
our phones we exchanged
take information and those contacts just
fall asleep in our phones was a very
very curious challenge for me because
when I sit down and I talk to young
people or anyone for that matter that
wants to be successful the number one
interchangeable reason for why they feel
like they have a barrier to success is
either money or they feel like they
don't know the right people and I firmly
believe that if you know the right
people you can get to the money you can
get to errors or you can get to your
customers you can get to business
development etc so it's really really
100% about people and so if you're a
young person you're watching this right
now and you're thinking like okay why am
i watching this what am I gonna get out
of this the most important gem that I
can leave for you is the fact that your
relationship with people is going to
shape your entire life experience and
you should treat every single person
that you meet every single person that
has the honor of being in your phone you
should treat those people with the kind
of respect that you would want to be
treated as a human being as someone that
is valuable to the world and so you know
most people I'll sit down well I mean we
could run this experiment right now how
many contacts do you have in your phone
let's take a look all right let's take a
look let's take a look we gotta check it
out so just does the Android I see you
got the new si you know how do you
actually tell how many contacts you have
you could just go to your contact to
scroll all the way down update let me
see 643 643 contacts yeah how many of
those contacts did you actually talk to
you there today yeah sure maybe like
three four right yeah so that would mean
that one percent of those contacts would
be if you talked to six of them yeah so
you talked to half of one percent of the
people in your phone
the idea behind super phone is that we
found that eighty to ninety percent of
the people that are in your phone
friends family loved ones exes new
romance whatever it is investors Mentors
90% of those people are just sleeping in
your phone and if there was a way for
you to wake up those conversations and
be able to extract the value of a great
collaboration hmm
even just 10% more of those
conversations 10% of your phone would be
60 people today if you were having 60
conversations today that's six that's
that 60 chances for you to be invited to
something that could enrich your life
right okay well see I'm thinking from an
artists perspective right and then I
think of almost a social perspective
sure my artists perspective especially
what you showed me on the backend it's
like all right so I can go to a city I'm
just stopping by
sure let's just say Atlanta yeah right
I'm on the way to Atlanta and then I
could look up all of my phone my fans in
Atlanta
sure that I have in my phone not only
that I could say I want to look up the
fans that are spent $50 yes with me in
the last three months
yeah and I can text all those fans and
just say yo I'm gonna be here this time
let's do a quick meetup I would love to
meet you yes something like that
absolutely and we have you know we have
folks that do that you know so one of my
lord homies from Atlanta's name is Rory
because in the woods uses a phone number
to actually distribute the location for
its concert all right and so it's it's
really I mean I can't tell you how
really simple of a concept it is and it
may seem foreign and the reason I know
that it seems foreign is because when
people think about their cell phone
numbers they really think about it as
some personal sacred important guarded
treasure in their life hey they never
want to change their number and B they
don't want to really give their number
out and also in hip-hop
we're always taught like no new friends
okay my number don't speak to me
directly talk to my manager talk to my
agent and in many ways there are there
are situations where that's important if
you want to be very very focused because
like I'm saying your communication has
to be intentional so you don't want to
have a bunch of folks that are coming
into your life and into your
conversation thread
bring in your phone that are distracting
you from being the successful the most
successful best version of yourself you
can bring at the same time though when
you got six hundred those 634 people
even make it into your phone at some
point in time in your life you thought
that it was important enough for you
guys to exchange information yeah
and so for me when we talk about it in
the fan standpoint it is important for
me to exchange information because what
I found is that because people follow so
many other profiles on social it's very
possible that I could have a concert in
Atlanta or DC or LA or San Francisco and
people wouldn't hear about it until they
see every one of their friends oh yeah
you have to wait long I mean you have
this organic reach that's being
suppressed right there's a lot of yeah
there's a lot of posts that people do
not see right I know that from marketing
all the time so what I mean with our one
thing when it comes to super phone do
you know anybody who's used it for more
let's just say trivial reasons like oh I
got all my X's and this list
yeah or I got or just to keep better
contact with you know whoever yeah yeah
yeah so there there are so many great
use cases here of that and I mean you
could think of if you're a start-up
founder ah so let's just say you have a
you have a great idea I just came from
CES and there's so many great companies
there are new technologies that are
being built I know for me personally
when I started super phone I was very
much happy using it as a tool and a
secret weapon for myself and it was
because of a conversation I had and in
exchange I had with Tristan Walker who
is an entrepreneur in residence at a big
venture capital right
he sent me it's like to say hey Ryan you
should meet my friend Ben and Ben really
was the guy to say you should privatize
this and me being a self-made
entrepreneur someone who always
bootstrapped I didn't even have a single
investor in my phone that's number one
and number two I didn't even have any
idea how I could actually accept money
from someone else and be a good steward
of their investment so for me
the utility of super foam began to pivot
at that moment because for the first
time now I had a category of people that
I could start tracking and so that
category of people and I knew what
success meant for me success for me for
superphone at that moment beyond making
the millions of dollars that I had made
as an independent artist now it was how
do I raise millions of dollars from a
much much much much much smaller and
more focused group of people so to get
to 2 million dollars in revenue as an
independent artist it took me about
40,000 tickets 40,000 tickets was
probably bought by about 15 or 20,000
people
right because everyone that came to the
concert brought a friend about 3 or 4
tickets
yeah 40,000 tickets at 40 euros a ticket
is 1.6 million euros add that to the
17,000 records
add that to merch add that to
experiences coming to the studio my New
Year's Eve party you're talking about a
two million dollar album cycle no label
no manager no music videos no PR
straight off of the phone the difference
with raising millions of dollars from a
venture standpoint is that there are
very few startups unless they've
crowdfunded their fun they're there
their investment that have 40,000
investors and even for me I've been 68
investors on my cap table a lot of
people in it and folks will look at me
and say man as so many people because in
venture you want to have the most
engaged focused directed group of
investors because it takes a lot of time
to deal with a lot of people right
that's your phone there we go
the phone is going on I see so so for me
you're asking about a case outside of
the music industry or a case for me
outside of the music industry was very
specifically to find investors and that
was my metric of success I wanted to
find success I wanted to be successful
finding investors and being
so finding investors has now led me to
312 investors that are tagged in my
phone 68 of which have invested more
than four point seven million dollars in
each superphone congratulations on that
right there man yeah thank you whoo I
want to do one pivot really really quick
quickly because super bone is intriguing
in itself but just back to the article I
know a lot of artists watch this the
hustle that you had when you first
started off yeah like I remember that CN
P Diddy talked about that he had never
seen an artist really going out building
their own fan base specifically in
Europe going straight global well what I
learned is that a lot of a lot of
international artists would go over to
Europe and feel very entitled so I'm
already a big star in the United States
everyone should treat me like I'm a big
star and I was always very very
respectful and thankful and grateful for
the appreciation that I would get in
different countries well really the
appreciate I would get anywhere but the
appreciate I would get in different
countries and I would always make sure
that I did every request I would always
make sure that my set length was longer
than other American artists that came
over so I could differentiate myself and
maybe kind of for the first time I
started to see that the skill level of
being a multi-instrumentalist being
proficient on many different instruments
breaking records down instead of just
performing over my tracks these kinds of
elements I found that people really
appreciate it and so I understood but
first based on data and second based on
being in the field and actually being on
stage over there and sometimes playing
four and a half hour sets that people
actually cared and appreciated and man I
mean the Internet is a very very
powerful tool to a communicate to large
numbers of people I mean you can through
one YouTube channel you're a perfect
example literally have a an
international an internationally
accessible global content channel and
it's your responsibility to make sure
that content is happening on a
consistent basis and so for me start
down in the game
it was every single day for a year
running around New York City working
with Cassie filming everything all my
own then setting up a camera on a tripod
just like you have here speaking into
the camera cutting it up it was called
NS for life some of those clips might
still be on my youtube channel and it
was every single day for a year
understanding that fast furious
frequency of consistent content was
going to be the way that I could not
only build but also retain an audience
right and then I could look at the
inside so you can look at the insights
on YouTube you can look at the insides
on Spotify you can look at the insights
on Facebook you can know where your
audience is actually developing and then
it's your responsibility to eight be
able to communicate with that audience
directly and be play to the geographical
locations where your audience is
building and that's what I that's what
our levers in the beginning of my career
was crazy about that is the biggest age
out of all that that you said kind of
relates to some of the theme of super
bunker bone which is just treating
people like they're human yes you
respected them and you treated them
better than the other artists who might
have bigger names yes more money backing
yeah you just say I want to treat y'all
so you had that heck I mean you uh
another story I heard was uh he did he
said what you said I think you paid
somebody off wherever he went yeah you
were paid for your song to be played
yeah so for him I always talked to
everybody on the channel about the idea
of targeted omnipresence which is being
everywhere to a target amount of fans
you did it to one person yes
whoever P Diddy when he heard your song
yes unknowingly that you were paying for
me yeah yeah yeah yeah well who would
give you like in the mindset of this
hustle that you're constantly listening
a lot of this trial and error man a lot
of this trial and error and also I think
so many people talk about trial and
error and very few people talk about
trial and success people always look at
trial success in a Monday Morning
Quarterback and they say oh okay well I
was successful because X Y Z I
understand that for every number of
trial and errors that you have there
will be also an
of trial and success man to get to
success especially in in verticals where
you're you have to be a trailblazer and
really in the myspace days between
myself my my my partner and one of my
best friends Rasheed Richmond we were
trailblazers in that myspace era how do
you take an artist from relative
obscurity a a burgeoning modeling career
from New London Connecticut and leverage
a social platform that was new but
nascent and vibrant and growing and take
that artists take her dream make it come
true on a platform that was emerging
being a trailblazer to be 100% truthful
and honest it took a lot of trial and
error and there were those moments where
we had trial and success and so I mean
it was rich it was rich dollars actually
risk dollar was was was working on on on
a bad boy street team a bad boy radio
team and man he was really you know I
listened as much as I could you know
being young and having success early you
could definitely have your your share of
of arrogance and there were moments
where I just said look you know it's
gonna be a lot better for me to just
listen and if I listen to someone that's
willing to work with me then I'm gonna
accelerate faster and so he was really
the guy that had the idea look we in the
mix she'll win the clubs and since I'm
on the bad boy street team everywhere
puff is going already know where he's
gonna be so Ryan I just need that budget
you know and we'll make sure that the
DJ's are spinning it and that's that's
that's not that's how we're down yeah
yeah okay well I have just two more
questions short one when I look at your
career and even the things you said
about your upbringing you were in a
foreign country for a period you were
early like you went to college early and
you were young right um you do this
music thing they independent mm-hmm
super phone yeah my question when I look
at your career especially
when I said earlier on you're like smart
guy musicmusic guy successful it's hard
for some people to relate just from what
they see as far as the narrative right
just seems like this guy especially
without knowing two things about the
parents and things like that right but
you haven't seemed to overwork in trying
to communicate that you had such humble
beginnings are you comfortable or do you
even find find comfort in being an
outsider yeah absolutely I mean listen I
think anyone that's made an incredible
impact on humanity has been an outsider
I mean look at Prince right look just
look at the purple of it or look at
Eminem or look at a Twain or look at
easy now look at young thug I mean the
folks that are having this kind of this
kind of impact on society or the people
who are brave enough to take on the
messaging and take on the communication
that most would be apprehensive and
communicate the message that most will
be apprehensive to communicate and I
think now more than ever in a world
where we are so connected where we have
so much access to data where we have so
much access to tools that can make us
smarter about the decisions we make it's
important for us as that next youthful
generation I mean I never wanted to be
someone that took flight and didn't
teach others how to fly and for me my
life is an open book my stories are you
know very very clearly can be
transparently communicated yeah and I
really wish that more folks I wish more
people would would have the courage and
the honesty to really just say like look
you know I wasn't necessarily self-made
I don't think really anybody is well
self-made back right and I think so what
makes that just so interesting though
just because
you're so transparent but again the the
public is so unknown and a lot of these
things that are occurring so always like
wonder if you might have ever take it
upon yourself to say let me push my
narrative out there more because Kanye
was one of he mentioned you as I'm in
the video I did on you right he
mentioned you and will.i.am as far as
people who are product focus and care
another right you actually learned Koloa
successful rapper producers gonna learn
Cole you know create a product he
mentioned you right but when I look at
the difference between you and Kanye is
almost like the difference between
Thomas Edison and Nikola Tesla right
both geniuses in their own right hmm but
Edison was a better PR it's the person
so and you being inspirational you being
a person of color especially always have
wondered what that ever like where you
want to take it upon yourself to say
right now let me push it out your do it
movie or I don't know in any form of
fashion yeah yeah I mean yeah I think I
think I think a it's about timing right
and B it's about impact right so am i
interested in this for me or am i
interested in this in terms of how it
will impact the world and when I have
interviews like this one and I deal with
the young team super talented young team
that we're dealing with that superphone
and and the idea is put forward that my
story can be a catalyst to inspiring
young people to really achieve the
success that I believe that this next
generation is going to be able to
achieve then it becomes more
crystallized and more of a priority for
me to actually tell that story so yeah I
mean listen let's listen but if we can
look into a crystal ball is there a book
on the horizon because there a movie on
a horizon I think I think I think that I
think that's all I think it's all within
the realm of possibility don't so I
guess that leaves perfectly into the
last question what would you want your
legacy to be as Ryan laser
sure I mean my legacy oh I I actually
just went to celebrate the life of a
pretty pivotal character in my career in
the music business his name was ed woods
he was a music manager attorney music
executive author and I believe that
everyone's legacy is just a culmination
of how you impact people while you're
alive and every day I live my life that
way I live my life in such a way that
the people around me
I want to make sure that anyone that's
within the range of my voice that I am
planting seeds that whether those seeds
become fertilized at the moment I plant
them or they bear fruit later on in life
I want to make sure that I'm planting
the seeds that build the kind of
intelligent decision-making that helped
to accelerate success because I believe
that when we accelerate success we as
humans we innately want to share that
success and so I was actually just
watching them I think I was watching I
think was Antoine Walker I was watching
and he had made 108 million dollars in
the NBA and then you know yeah yeah yeah
and I think he has a documentary about
it one of the one of the caveat said
that came from from listening to his
interview he said man I wanted to share
my success with my with the people who
came up with me and so when I went on
trips I want everybody going trips and
so what I'm interested in doing is it is
changing that just a little bit so that
everyone in the crew was successful in
their own right so I don't have to pay
for everyone they could pay for
themselves if I say hey let's go you
know take two weeks in the South of
France and get a got in Sardinia and you
know just enjoy the Sun and and think
about what our next idea is gonna be
it's totally different when people can
come to the table with the kind of
success that's equal
because we can elevate each other and
I'm interested in from a diversity
standpoint from a youth perspective I'm
interested in just being as
inspirational as possible and not just
inspirational in terms of talk but
inspirational in terms of delivering the
world of utility that they can actually
use a tool that can actually give them
the insights and be a compass for them
so they can achieve success in whatever
way the success means to them Wow though
man that was a very elegant answer they
appreciate you once again they say to
guys man
I haven't really benefited from this
interviewer Ryan Leslie yeah I had so
many gems that he dropped throughout
this we're definitely gonna have to talk
about this in the comment section you
already know so um hey you guys follow
Ryan Leslie at where do you want to
Tech's Ryan com just leave me your
number see I mean you can follow me if
you'd like but Tech's ride , I know a
lot of folks might have some questions
based on this interview so just shoot me
just just leaving your number at tetra
line.com and I'll back a text and yeah
woo I'm interested in seeing the kind of
success that is achieved after uh up to
this point in your life though alright
I'm back and I hope you guys got as much
value out of that interview as I did it
was very interesting to see how Ryan
went from being a producer in his room
thinking it was all about being the best
producer in the world and then all of a
sudden had that light switch to say hey
I need to start getting people to know
me I need to start networking I hope you
guys have taken notes let me know what
you guys think in the comments below and
of course hit Ryan up he said hit him up
you have his number text Ryan let him
know what you thought about the
interview at the very least and as
always if you like this video hit that
like button if you liked it you might as
well share it and if you're not
subscribed you know what to do hit that
subscribe but