[Music]
what's up everybody once again it's
brand man Sean and we got to go over
four types of deals that every artist
should know and this question was
inspired by one of the questions in the
comments they were asking about record
deals versus distribution deals we're
going to get into all of that as a
matter of fact starting with number one
dis distribution deals one of the more
popular deals that you are hearing about
today so what exactly is a distribution
deal well let's just talk about
Distributing your music getting it out
there through different channels that's
Apple music Spotify Target the radio
those are different routes of getting
your music out there so what
distribution deals really handle is
really getting your music out there
right and helping promote that music
when you think about a distribution deal
traditionally it's also known as as a
pnd pressing and distribution deal so if
you can recall back in them days where
people really really listened to CDs
they were pressing CDs Distributing
those out to the retail stores well now
we have digital so even though you can
use T cord and some of these other
people to distribute your music that's
why they're called Distributors these
distribution deals still entail those
but you still get the benefits of retail
and radio like I mentioned before but it
can also cover additional types of
promotion right like posters and even
videos of some sorts now what are the
cons of distribution deals if you're
somebody who's looking for a lot of
money upfront distribution deals rarely
have money for you up front there is no
cash advance which means a distribution
deal is pretty much useless to somebody
who does not already have some sense of
an established fan base and also a well
planned strategy to promote that music
and get it out to that fan base now
there are quite a few artists who are
signing distribution deals earlier and
you know the landscape is changing so
I'm not saying it's completely 100%
useless for you but it's not going to be
a game changer like you might think not
immediately at least now number two the
traditional record deals the traditional
major label deals that so many artists
think about and so many artists have
dreamed about are actually broken down
like this one you often times do not
maintain your Masters two you are given
a nice cash advance and they try to
boost your presence up out of the gate
but you don't really see those kind of
these days with an artist that is you
know just straight from the dirt but
with all that being said they give you
all that money they want that money back
that money is not yours to have it is a
loan major labels in terms of these
deals should be looked at as a bank they
want their money back and that's why
they get some royalties that's why they
also look to have Masters often times so
they can use that as a bit of an
insurance just in case maybe even your
immediate royalties doesn't bring them
the money they want it's musical real
estate number three the production deal
now this is you being signed by a
producer if you're an artist so what you
see often times in this kind of
agreement is a major label or a label of
some sort gives a producer a deal for
them to develop artists under an
umbrella so if you're a producer and you
know you got skills and you have a good
eye for talent and people really have
faith that you can develop this talent
and make some hits with them that's what
these deals are for now when you think
about it from an artist perspective what
I've heard or even just seen online and
blog and things like that is it's pretty
common to have a 50/50 split between the
producer but with that being said the
money that gets made is at first a 50/50
split between the producer's company and
the label so let's just say there's $100
the label gets $50 and then the
producers company is distributed another
$50 and then you and that producer might
split that $50 into 2525 but of course
it's really going to depend on what gets
negotiated between you and the producer
what that split looks like and there's
occasions when that producer or whoever
that company owner is in that sort of
deal might also own the Masters that
could be wholly or partially once again
up to negotiation now for number four
we're talking 360 deals y'all have heard
quite a bit about 360 deal so I'm not
going to go super deep into them but is
once again that idea that the label also
gets to profit from pretty much every
place that you profit from not just
music sales album sales you know you
know all that good stuff your merch your
touring I don't know maybe even TV
appearances all that good stuff a lot of
artists do not like that especially
older artists because they weren't used
to hearing something like that what I'm
making all this money I can't believe
that record labels are stealing from
these new artists by taking this other
money that we never had to pay them
that's cool I get it but just to bring a
little bit of logic into that situation
it was really created in a time where
record labels were having a hard time
finding how to make money because the
music industry was changing dramatically
at that time so in some ways it was just
Risk insurance I'm not saying you should
sign a 360 deals but from a business
standpoint there are some things that I
can understand especially if the artist
has no buzz whatsoever particularly
within that time period I think 360
deals will continue to evolve actually
not evolve really kind of go extinct
because as the industry evolves and
people are coming up with more
innovative ways right these Boutique
labels these marketing labels all these
other types of business models is not
going to be as necessary and just to be
frank it's had a bad rep 360 deals have
a bad brand so even if people would like
to get a 360 deal they might not just
because there's a negative connation and
they feel like they shouldn't so they're
just going to have to Rebrand the
product just like they did with those
variable rate mortgages that kind of
helped cause the recession but anyway
that's a a whole another conversation if
you like this video go ahead hit the
like button if you like it might as well
share it and if you're not subscribed
you know what to do hit that
subscribe button
[Music]