One of the funniest things about today
is that it's starting to feel like every
artist wants fans, right? But nobody
wants to actually deal with their fans.
And sure, artists will say, "I want a
real community." But the moment that
community starts to feel too real, they
start to panic a little bit. And I get
it because being close to fans in this
new music industry is very complicated
because it really can build you up or
make people start to treat you a little
bit too regular. And I think that nobody
explains that in a funnier way than DDG.
>> I don't want to meet you because once
you meet me, you going to feel like you
ain't really got to support me no more.
Yeah,
>> that's the problem. That's why a lot of
artists that win, a lot of artists that
win um in the industry because they
don't even interact with their
supporters. We in a different type of
ball game where you know we streaming,
we you know we YouTubing all this other
stuff. So they see us all the time, but
when you don't see somebody, it makes
you want to support them even more. Like
put it like this. You don't know who
made gallery department, but if let's
say the Shay gave you his merch, you
gonna pick up this before you pick up
the Shay shirt. When you giving them
free promo,
>> right?
>> You giving Chrome Hart free promo. It's
cuz you don't see them. Now, if you met
Chromeart, you met the [\h__\h] that made
gallery department, y'all go out to eat,
y'all go out to the club together, y'all
kicking it, he giving you free clothes,
but you ain't wearing it like that no
more. That's the problem, bro. Like,
that's why, you know, I'm telling myself
this, too. like it needs to be a
separation in between because when you
too when you get too close to somebody
that idolize you, it it makes them not
idolize you no more.
>> Now, I do think DDG makes a really fair
point in this new era of the music
industry where artists are being pushed
to be closer to their fans more than any
other era of music artists. We do have
to acknowledge that the fanto artist
relationship has changed. So, let's
start with what happens when fans feel
too close to you to the point where they
start writing your life story for you. I
didn't make that [\h__\h] One of them weird
ass dumbass [\h__\h] ass fan page made that
[\h__\h] just so they could get engagement,
[\h__\h] And I DM'd them like, "What the
[\h__\h] is up, bro?" And then they made a
post like, "Sorry, we took it down."
Like, I don't like that [\h__\h] I a make
no I ain't make that [\h__\h] post. Like,
I don't even talk like that, [\h__\h]
>> I knew it wasn't real, but I knew it was
moving around,
>> bro. And they do that [\h__\h] for
engagement. I don't like that [\h__\h] bro.
Don't Don't do They love doing that
[\h__\h] And then you get called, "Oh, if I
was real, like I hit [\h__\h] like, "Bro,
why you do that?" When [\h__\h] always say
some [\h__\h] like that, I'm like, "Yo, take
that down. Like, I ain't say that. I
don't want to blow the spot up like that
to bring more attention, but don't do
that." And then if you do say something,
[\h__\h] be on some like, "Bro, if I was
rich, I wouldn't be engaging in that
shit." Like, bro, you mean it's every
day thousands of folks saying some [\h__\h]
making oblig, and you expect me as a
human being to not want to defend myself
because I'm rich?
>> So, in that clip, Tyler the Creator is
calling out a fan camp who created a
fake tweet trying to incite some beef
between Tyler the Creator and Frank
Ocean. And I think that this is one of
the real dangers of parasocial
closeness. Fans start to feel like, hey,
I don't just have to watch his life, I
could impact his life, right? Like I
could edit his life. So if fans are
bored or they feel like there hasn't
been enough drama around you recently,
then yeah, they might go and create it.
And honestly, I think that's when things
stop being supportive and start being
possessive. And sometimes it doesn't
just stay online. Sometimes fans treat
their favorite artists like a literal
gang they're affiliated with.
>> Ain't no [\h__\h] What? What you say?
>> He said what?
>> Young boy [\h__\h] your boy. Did I ask?
>> You going to punch me or something?
>> Is you pain or is you for real?
>> What you What you going to do something
about it?
>> Is you pain or is he for real?
>> You going to do something about it?
>> I'm from if you touch me, I'm really
going to do something to you. I'm really
going to do Come on now.
>> You stick up.
>> I'm going to grab a switch on your ass
right now.
>> So then why you here for my [\h__\h] Right
across the street. You going to grab a
switch on your ass right now. You slide
your butt like that. Like that. For
real. But [\h__\h] don't even know. Real
>> [\h__\h] don't know y'all. Bro, stop
following me cuz real talk. Stop. Real
talk. You good?
>> Real talk. Stop following me.
>> I get over right here. Come on, girl.
Stop playing. Don't lose your life over
over Young Boy. Come on, girl. [\h__\h]
going to lose his life over Young Boy.
That [\h__\h] crazy.
>> So, two random dudes almost about to
fight in public over a guy that doesn't
even know they exist. At that point,
that's not just fandom. That's identity.
And identity without boundaries can get
very dangerous. Kasette actually broke
this down perfectly in a conversation
with Lil Yachti. And I think that this
is one of the best explanations of
parasocial fan behavior that you'll
actually see. Check this out.
>> Like, do you feel like you're an open
book almost?
>> Yeah. Um, so like it happens with every
streamers, bro. It it's this thing with
with their like um audience to where
they feel like very parasocial. It gets
it gets actually scary.
>> Explain parasocial.
>> Um it's just like when you think you
just know like when you're so invested
into somebody's life like as if like you
know them and you really think like
y'all friends on the line start to get
blur, right?
>> Yeah. Like it starts to get like okay
bro like you wilding, bro. So it's like
um so like with that is like since I'm
in front of the camera 247 and people um
and people know me 247 a lot of you
>> yeah like it got worse after my subathon
especially because my cameras are on
24/7. They watch me sleep, eat, take
showers, do whatever. You feel what I'm
saying? So they literally thought that
they were like roommates for me for like
30 days. It's not it's not certain
people but like it's like that that that
small majority of people that really
think they know you. Now, obviously, the
fan relationship is a little bit
different for streamers because they're
giving so much more access to themselves
than artists typically do. But I think
the general makeup of how the fan thinks
is pretty much exactly the same. And
I've been saying this for years. Fans
are people who want to feel like if they
met you in real life, y'all will become
best friends, right? Like, they want to
think that, hey, this artist whose music
I love, if I met them, they would be
such a cool guy or girl, and we would
get along so well, and we could like
hang out and chill and get drinks
together and talk. Like that's where the
typical fan mentality is. And I do think
Kai said it best, right? Fans may feel
like they love you, but what they really
love is a version of you that they've
built up in their head because of what
you've given them access to. And the
tricky thing is once they attach to that
version, they may start to expect things
from the real you that you never signed
up for. But I don't think it all has to
be scary, right? Like I don't think that
all fan interactions are toxic or scary
interactions. In fact, some of the most
human, beautiful, emotional moments
starts to come from once a fan feels
connected.
>> Yeah, bro. What's up, bro? YEAH. YEAH.
>> WHAT ARE you
doing? DUKE RIGHT HERE. DUKE RIGHT HERE.
HE WATCHING. DUKE WATCHING.
>> DUKE. [screaming]
>> NOW, that was a pure moment, right? And
I think that this is what artists are
hoping for when they think about being
connected with their fans. a moment
where a person who loves your music and
loves your world so much that they get
excited just for being seen by you. And
I think as much as the negative fan
interactions, you know, go viral or
spark the conversations within the
industry, there are a lot of really good
positive examples of what long-term
fandom looks like.
>> Let me tell y'all something. I think it
was 2016 after the Trayvon Martin Travis
or sorry catastrophe happened. Um, I
made a brand called Stay Wolf, Stay
Black to show my activism [cheering]
against racism.
And I was in high school. That was my
first company that I ever built.
[cheering] And it was to promote black
love, black creativity, and fight
against racism. And you have that hoodie
[cheering] that means so much to me. You
are so beautiful. Thank you so
[cheering] much.
I love you more. So from that clip, we
can tell that that DOI fan is a noob.
And DOI said it herself, just from this
item that you have, I can tell that
you've been paying attention to me since
I was in high school. So when we think
about that fan interacting with her
today, right, like Doi in her new
superstar era, then we have to realize
that that's loyalty that's been built
over years. And sometimes that
connection blossoms into something
really beautiful, advocacy. And I think
Tiso Touchdown is a perfect example of
that.
>> What's the deal?
>> Yo, my I came here with my cousin, too.
trying to get a picture. We was like
right there. Hey, you did that [\h__\h]
>> Yo, appreciate it. Yeah, I don't like
taking pictures while Travis is on stage
cuz I feel like, man, this is Travis
Scott. You know what I'm saying? You got
to watch that show, man.
>> You feel me?
>> But no, and then also, bro, I love the
album. The album was great, bro.
>> Thank you, man.
>> I be I be like I be promoting for you
and everything. I'm like, "Ya check this
out right now."
>> Yeah. Hey, man. You early, man. Your
cousin is very early and I really
appreciate that, man. I appreciate you
sharing this, man.
>> And like, bro, what was that one? What
you call? You ever going to release a
strike that Adidas commercial song?
>> Um, no. It's just a commercial, so it it
lives in the commercial.
>> All right. I was I just had to ask. I
just had to ask.
>> I feel I feel I appreciate it, bro.
>> No, thank you. I appreciate you, man.
I'm glad y'all enjoyed your time and the
album, man. Yo, you got my number, man.
Hit me up anytime. Even next time I'm in
uh Denver, man. Pull up.
>> All right, I will.
>> Now, that fan said it himself. He's not
just listening to Tiso Touchdown. He's
actually out here marketing him trying
to put people on to his music and his
new album. And that right there is the
power of emotional connection because
when fans start to feel a type of way
about you, your music, your world, your
art, then they start to feel like they
have to tell more people so they can
join them in it. And at the end of the
day, I think that's really what every
artist is looking for. So, by now you
might be thinking, Kobe, what's the
right move? Should artists be super
close? Should I be distant? And to be
real, I think the real answer is
neither. You need control access, not
oversharing, but also not disappearing.
And I think a really good current artist
example of this is Lar Russell. And fun
fact, we were actually at one of his
backyard shows that ended up going
viral. And I can't even lie, it was a
very good vibe.
>> I wasn't expecting this. I thought it
was going to be like, you know, a
professional backyard. This a real
backyard.
>> IT'S LIKE A FAMILY.
>> IT'S A FAMILY GATHERING, [\h__\h] THIS
AIN'T NO SHOW. I'M SURPRISED ALL Y'ALL
REALLY HERE, [\h__\h] I THOUGHT IT WAS
GOING TO be me and Russell and like five
people.
I thought WE WAS GOING TO HAVE A LAUGH
CONTEST, [\h__\h] BEVER.
Y'all [\h__\h] really standing up here for
a real show.
>> Oh, that's S BABY. WHAT'S UP WITH IT?
Today is a special day.
>> We got a few birthdays today. There's
one in particular, man. I reached out
>> to this dude
>> probably about what 2 3 months ago
>> and I was like, "Bro, I [\h__\h] with you. I
want you to come work for me. you down
to leave your job? That [\h__\h] said,
I'mma put my two weeks in. I hit him and
I was like, uh, I'm f to do this
tomorrow. What you on? He said, all
right, I'm quitting today. And he pulled
up and he ain't even had to work yet.
And he's been really helping me build
this [\h__\h] vlog and everything. Can y'all
make some noise for Splash, man?
[cheering]
>> So, I do think in real time, Lar Russell
is proving that fans can have access
without chaos. I mean, fans are
literally in his dad's backyard, but the
boundaries are still respected. It's not
about his personal life. It's about this
world that he built, the culture, the
mission of it. And I don't think that
fans are necessarily obsessed with Lar
Russell, but I do think that they're
invested in what he represents. But then
again, we do have to acknowledge the
artists who don't need to give their
fans access at all because the world
they built is so strong and so engaging
that it does all the talking for them.
And a lot of those artists are not
rocking with the idea of accessibility.
I think people are so brainwashed. You
get up in the morning, you click on the
computer, you see all these pictures and
it's all you think of is the picture and
the image that you see all day every day
and you don't see the human form. And I
I think when Nina Simone put out music,
you loved her voice. That's what she
wanted you to love. That's what that was
her instrument. But you didn't get
brainwashed by her day-to-day life and
what her child is wearing and who she's
dating and you know all the things that
really it's not your business, you know,
and it shouldn't influence the way you
listen to the voice and the art, but it
does.
>> Now, what Beyonce is opting for is the
opposite strategy, and that's extreme
mystique. And you know, when I hear
artists talk about this, it's like, I
feel you. I hear you. We should live in
a world where music artists are being
judged for their music, right, and their
musicality. But I honestly can't think
of any era of the music industry where
fans did not care about what the artist
had going on in their real life. Maybe
like pre-radio, but I can imagine that
there were probably like rumors floating
around and people were still talking
about things. And for a long time, we
have gotten to see plenty of really good
examples of artists who were very
mysterious and held their mystique. But
the thing is that really only works when
your art and your music and your world
building are strong enough to support
that level of distance. So, here's the
real answer. How close to their fans
should artists be? And the answer is it
depends on the world you build. So, rule
one is going to be build a world that
fans can enter. You want to try to give
fans something to be a part of, not
necessarily all of your personal
details. And I know it's hard for
artists to figure out what parts of
themselves to give away to grow the
world versus what to kind of keep close
to themselves. But it's a very important
decision and I think every artist needs
to think long and hard about it because
you really don't need to be as
accessible as some artist may make you
guys feel like you need to be. Rule two,
give your fans controlled access
moments. This could be through your
Discord. This could be through live
streams, meet and greets, curated
events. Basically, give your fans spaces
where you can express more about
yourself and your background and your
life and your lore without feeling like
you're having people cross your
boundaries or get into things that you
may not feel comfortable with. Once
again, this is your world. You can build
your world on your terms. Rule three,
set your boundaries out loud because
clarity is better than mystery. Once
fans know what you won't tolerate, what
type of culture you expect within your
world, and within the spaces you're
you're allowing people to enter when
they come into your world, then you
magically start to attract the type of
people that respect those types of
spaces. Versus if you're silent and you
let everybody in, no matter if they
believe in what you believe or they're
for or against the things that you're
building, then yeah, you're probably
inviting some issues into your space.
And trust me, it's much better to just
nip a fan problem in the bud as soon as
it starts, right? Because the worst
thing that could happen is that it
travels, it becomes a part of your fan
culture, and then you're just stuck with
this disrespectful group of fans.
Basically, don't let fans feel like they
can bully you. You know, stick up for
yourself. And rule four, know what lane
your art fits into. And know what type
of people your art attracts. Some fans
need closeness. Like, I can't describe
it to you, but some artists make the
type of music that attract people that,
yeah, they really want to be close to
you and they want to know every little
thing. Some artists attract fans that
really are more attracted to the
Mystique, and they may not want to know
every little detail about their favorite
artist. But I think what's fair to say
about artists who fall on either side is
your fans probably really just need a
balance. Because I do think it's fair to
say that fans still want someone to
believe in. But as artists, you guys got
to think about does that belief come
with expected ownership. And the closer
you get to fans, the more you need
boundaries, but not walls. And if you're
an artist watching this and you need
help building the world that makes those
boundaries easy, our team actually puts
together full world building guides that
walks artists through their identity,
their visuals, their brand, their
storytelling. Basically everything that
you need to have brand clarity and world
clarity. So, that's something that
you're interested in, then the link is
in the description below. But now, I
want to hear from y'all. How close to
fans do you think artists should be? Do
you think fans need more access? Do you
think artists need more mystique? Or do
you think it's fair to say that they
really need a little bit of both? Drop
your take in the comment section below.
I'm really curious to see how y'all feel
about this. But other than that, if you
like this video, make sure you hit that
like button, subscribe, share this with
an artist that needs a little bit of
gain today. My name is Corey and I'll
see y'all next