hey what's up it's sean and in this
video we're going to go over something
extremely important what are the pieces
that you need in your team to get
yourself from ground zero to moving and
considered official in this industry
where everybody is starting to recognize
you now
there's a difference right between
old days and two day i'm going to go
over old days first so you can
understand the context and how that
works in today's marketplace right back
in the day a marketer right a manager
and a bank which was essentially a label
right now if you think about somebody
like jay-z jay-z
he was the artist right
business savvy but he was the artist he
played that role dame dash was the
manager and then biggs was the marketer
type guy also played bankroll when they
end up having to go indy until he got to
def jam finally and then the bank became
the label as most traditional
relationships back then you need all of
those aspects right it's extremely
important to have it however today that
doesn't quite add up because
most people don't want to be your
manager
marketer because marketing costs money
unless you get yourself to a certain
level back in the days where people were
going to labels and being plucked from
obscurity you're just you know you hear
those stories oh i was just walking down
the hall or humming in the grocery store
and this guy ended up being a manager
and now i'm assigned to a deal and and
now you know i'm a superstar like that
was an old story that was common it was
it was a very real thing people could
just be somewhere and the next thing you
know be signed because someone
discovered talent people don't
necessarily want to discover you right
at this time
that today they want you to reach their
radar which is a difference right so no
one wants you down here you got to get
yourself up here so now before you even
get to this level of a relationship
which often times a manager and marketer
work hand in hand for a lot of people
even though they'll be like a week
they'll be weak on one end
before you get to a level where you
start seeing these things more
traditionally and people care you're
able to get signed and all of a sudden
you have fans that you can monetize
you actually have to
start with a team right a lean team that
can get you to that level so what does
that look like today
all right
it's broken down into multiple
categories all right
marketer right
had a little drop
graphics
videographer
two primary things and then artist i'll
get into that in a second all right
somebody who can do your graphics just
make sure your brand looks good
somebody who can get make some videos
for you that could be you you might have
that skill set or you have to find
somebody you can even call them a
creative director especially if you have
them doing both or if you find that
talent that's always good to find
next
artist and it's actually slash
influencers this is something that a lot
of artists are still having trouble with
because they don't understand the value
of connecting with other artists it's
it's it blows my mind that they don't
get it but if you have other people
trying to move in the same direction
that you're doing they're learning
things right so now you can borrow their
knowledge and the things that they learn
you can borrow their connections and all
their assets and then even borrow their
audience because you've built that
relationship if you go on tick-tock
right if you go on on instagram how many
influencers do you see in each other's
videos creating videos together how many
artists do you see that seem to either
um make a lot of videos together or you
just find out oh man they've known each
other for a while they were in the
studio back in the day and met at a
writer's camp or or something like that
well that's because these people the
ones that you see are that are winning
they have
the artist and influencer connections
they're doing that right and you should
do that don't try to reach up reach to
people on your side because trust me it
comes back right it comes back you got a
filter there's some people who aren't
serious and all that stuff but but
getting gain from other artists
is is look it helps right i see it in a
network all the time other artists
putting each other artists on game now
this one
right here a marketing advisor
and a management right advisor now a
marketing advisor a lot of artists
especially at ground zero you cannot
afford a true marketer right and that's
you know that comes from here too all
right it's because they're almost hand
in hand when we talk about marketing and
management advising all right if i'm a
manager
most artists are not worth it right day
one i have to see
something developing that's the
mentality of how managers think today
remember you have to get on their radar
they don't want to discover you they
need to see something proven because
people have to eat right so they need to
think to and that they're investing in a
person right that's also going to give
them a return on their investment which
is their time especially a manager who
they win when you win
real legitimate marketers right
yes you might pay somebody and you feel
like oh man well i got i didn't get my
money's worth for or they or
i still not where i want to but that
marketer got paid that sounds good but
the best marketers want to have a client
that can continue to win continue to win
continue to win so they can continue to
get paid they get the
the the um
acknowledgement for being associated
with that artist so when you're talking
about these quality people you probably
cannot afford them to be on your team
you're probably not in a
position where you're another enough of
an asset right to truly even take on
um that much of their attention
especially if you aren't paying them
money because these people are expensive
right yeah managers technically a lot of
times 10 to 20 no matter what level you
are but it's expensive right in terms of
you got to get in position they're not
just about to be anybody's manager right
now with that being said
what does marketing advising look like
marketing advising and even management
advising you can just go pay somebody
who has that experience whether you're
paying for a one-off consultation right
whether you're um getting a connection
that can give you some you know advice
for free because that person really
really is putting you on game a lot of
people are using youtube and courses to
actually get some of that right you
can't get all of it though until you get
like specific advice you get what i'm
saying like yes there's so much we have
a youtube channel brandman network check
it out on youtube so much free
information however
i can't tell you specific advice for you
through a video right now here's the
difference between a youtube video and
marketing advising and management
advising there's a i'll put like a
screenshot below this video or maybe pop
it up on this video there's a member
in brandman network and
he reached out to me about somebody who
wanted to do marketing from them they
were they they had the conversations
last thing they were sending over a 600
contract which for him that was a lot of
money right and he just wanted to be
sure he was like i'm not completely sure
about it and i looked at it and
everything and i was like yo bro this is
a scam leave these folks alone this this
this is not it right
bam saved him 600
just from me being able to advise him
from not going with a scam now
on the other side and people are doing a
pretty decent job of of seeming official
i just have a certain knowledge about
you know certain people and connections
at labels and knew that they could not
have been a certain representative and
um
with that being said then he reaches out
again later on is like yo man that
meeting i had with y'all where y'all
gave me a plan through the network
i now have
three thousand i think he had three
thousand more followers and he said he
had a video that had a hundred a
thousand plus views at that point right
so what happened from marketing advising
and management management advising a
little bit of mix of both
well he saved six hundred dollars right
and then he gained
three thousand followers
a hundred thousand views
it's all decision making that's what
this is about the advising and most
artists don't understand what you do not
know all right so you're thinking oh man
i don't want to pay for this i don't
want to pay for that or or i just feel
like i can learn everything by myself
trust me you save yourself so much time
so much decisions by getting this
advising right and this is what helps
you get to this level until you can have
a manager manager so you can have a
marketer or a full marketing team
whether it's in-house right or again
like just an agency that you build a
relationship with whatever that looks
like but these things are what people
are using to get there faster all right
they might even just have a um
you know a family member who has a a
homie that was in the industry and
pretty successful so that person acts as
an advisor to them having conversations
here and here and there with them so
they don't necessarily act as a manager
but at least that connection allows them
to get some legitimate information the
information is half the game
understanding how to think through the
game make certain decisions
the advisor do not sleep on advisors
again back to the artist that i just
mentioned right he saved 600
and then he got
plus 3 000 views and pl no plus 3 000
followers and over 100 000 views
by the way that plan did not cost him
any money to apply he didn't go spend a
lot of money to get 3 000 um
followers off of ads it was just a
content strategy plan that we had put
him on to and bam so he not only saved
six hundred dollars he got results for
no money right but this is what a
marketing advisor management advisor
type can do for you being able to apply
the advice to to you specifically that's
completely different right then a
youtube video reading some articles
trying to get some social media tips and
things is never going to do as much for
you if it's not specific to you because
all these plans don't apply to everybody
i know a lot of people um
by my analysis i realize yo they get
confused i have to tell people all the
time yo when i have a youtube video it
doesn't necessarily apply to you yes
it's a strategy that works but it might
not be the strategy for you so that's a
danger of taking in so much information
without having people to give you
information specific to you now what's
happening here
where's the bank
where's the bank where's the money
coming from if i'm not
at a label well
the new bank today
last part of your team
most artists
are getting a job right or staying with
their job and using that extra money to
go towards their career now i know that
might not be the ideal answer all right
that you hear you're hoping there's some
other finesse there are entirely uh
different frameworks for for uh built
fundraising it's a real thing
and that's just a whole other
conversation for another day but
check this out why is this how did this
become well back in the day it wasn't
even possible it was too expensive all
right the average artist
doesn't matter if they saved a whole
year's salary legitimately like that 50
000 wouldn't have did anything for them
back in the you know 80s 90s like it
really wouldn't have all right now
today 50 000 can take you far all right
today
5 000
can take you pretty far if you have
these people three thousand dollars can
take it you very far if you have these
people even
free right can give you legitimate
progress in the same way we told buddy
yo just do this and he got plus 3 000
followers and
100k plus views
why all right
he didn't have to spend money
he had advising that's why everything
starts to fall on this advising
connections with your own peer group you
got to get about your own way right stop
being up in your ego and thinking these
people aren't worth it these other
artists and these other influencers
right build with them as well
and we've seen that value in the network
the artists who do that
build and grow even faster and this
right here
this is about giving people something to
to cling on to so when we talk about
graphics and videographer right
this is your brand like put it that way
right that simply this is your brand
creating that world that image that
people actually care about all right of
course you can do a lot of things
yourself just creating videos on tick
tock just creating the uh content on
instagram but
this is going to allow you to elevate it
into a vision that's a little different
something that looks more thought out
right so
um don't sleep on the yet again other
people creativity but these three roles
have now been split into one two three
four five six rolls and i know it sounds
like man that's that sounds even harder
well we're talking about getting to a
point where you're really on these
people's radar this is ground zero
people don't care until you're at level
three and four no longer gonna pick you
up from level zero i'm not even trying
to do music or level one hey i wanna do
this but
i don't have a fan base you need these
to get you there right you can try
without any one of these but you're
going to suffer most likely of course
there's always a story of someone who
did it without right marketing someone
who did it without graphics because the
song just blew up randomly it got placed
somewhere somebody who didn't have any
management advising marketing advising
or
a job i guess right any money at all
but
you want to put yourself in the best
position to win
so you're not going to put yourself in
the best position to win with everything
in your control by
hoping that you're a special case that
happens one in a hundred thousand one in
a million whatever whatever whatever and
even if the special case happens to you
if you have these things you're going to
be able to capitalize it
even like way way better than somebody
who doesn't have those things in place
that's a whole nother story but
capitalization most artists who don't
have these especially
the ones who take off go viral and you
don't have those in place you're now an
alliance then and everybody you're
talking to
right
doesn't necessarily have your best
interest in mind because now people are
trying to sign like you don't have
anybody to trust it helps to build this
trustworthy relationship
before you start getting
in that like that part of the atmosphere
right when you get to that level okay so
that's it take these things to heart
these six positions are extremely
important if you do these right if you
find
those people right some of them you can
combine in one some of them you might
have to have split and they just be that
if you find those though they will make
your career so much easier give you so
much less to think about especially
these two people because they can just
hey say go that way and tell you why
that will allow you to focus on your
artist the artistry right allow you to
get a more profitable career faster and
most importantly right
the dream get closer to the dream that
you are looking to live all right
that's it for this video peace