So, I want to start this video with what
I think is one of the most accurate
depictions of what it must feel like to
be an artist in 2025. Because, as we all
know, it's not about the music anymore.
It's about a whole lot of other things.
>> Nobody ever talks about how embarrassing
it is to be a musician. So, you start
posting your music, right? The music
actually does kind of okay cuz your
music is better than most people. You
can put on a Spotify playlist. You start
getting the attention of labels. The
labels say, "Oh, we'd love to sign you,
but first you have to make a lot more
music videos and have a lot more X, Y,
and Z." Like, you have to build up your
resume of being a musician. Oh, and you
need to post stuff on Tik Tok and on
Instagram. You need to be a influencer
for your music. So, you make an account
on Tik Tok. Um, and you start
experimenting. You post some really cool
videos that you like that are really
serious and only focus on the music and
they get little to no traction and then
you're like, damn it. Like, why aren't
people watching this? So, you decide to
experiment a little more and you post a
video that's very gimmicky and all the
sudden it does super good even though
you think the video is cringe. Then
everybody around you is like, "Yes,
that's good. Keep doing that. Keep doing
that." So, you keep doing it and then
eventually all the people in your real
life start calling you cringe. One time
I was at a bar with a group of my
friends and there was another group of
people that I like adjacently knew like
playing pool next to us and they all
walked up to greet me and they were
like, "Yo, what's up, Matia? It's good
to see you." And then there's like this
other girl in the group that's like
extremely drunk and she goes, "You're
the the cringe girl on Instagram." And
her friends are like, "Shut the [\h__\h] up,
dude." And then I'm like, "Yeah, I I
know I'm kind of cringe." And then she's
like, "No, you're like really cringe."
And then it's like, you sit there and
it's like you're viewing yourself in
third person. You're just like in the
ceiling of this bar looking down and
you're like, I am a joke.
>> Now, that video went on to list out some
of her other complaints, but I think her
core complaints were pretty valid. A lot
of artists are feeling like, "Hey, I
have to be an influencer for my own
music." And not only do I have to be an
influencer for my own music, I'll be
judged for it. And not only am I judged
by strangers, but possibly by the people
around me who know me and who love me.
Now, I think it's safe to say that a lot
of artists feel this way. And it's not
necessarily because they're lazy or
because they're introverted. I think a
lot of artists just don't like feeling
like their personality has to be altered
or curated to fit an algorithm or an
aesthetic. But see me, my marketer brain
clicks and I start to think streaming
could actually solve a lot of these
problems for artists. And I know that
there are artists out there who would
absolutely disagree with me.
>> Stream is like I was just explaining
earlier like it's not in a rapper's best
interest to stream.
>> Thank you.
>> Giving too much of yourself. Why that
mysterious rapper that [\h__\h] done?
>> They want to know where you sleeping.
They want TO KNOW WHO YOU TALKING TO.
>> I DON'T EXPECT y'all to understand. He
going to understand though when I break
it down to him. You can't give them too
much cuz then after a while it becomes
what you want to see now what I'm going
to do a back flip off the top stairs.
>> You're going to be more connected to
your your your audience. You're going to
be more connected to the community.
Whatever you do, they going to [\h__\h] with
you 10 times more.
>> It's not in the best interest for artist
though. You know, once we do this, it's
like hours and hours and hours. You
can't give them that many hours, gang.
>> Why? But you can give them hour.
>> You can give my hour. If I'm going to do
it, I want the match. And that's what
that's when you got to go crazy. Like,
you know, 24-hour stream. You got to do
it. That's that's how you going to win,
you know. But there's only certain
people that rappers I feel like can do
this [\h__\h] I feel like
>> you wanted a personal lie, bro. I think
I think it's that because I'm popping in
and out. I think if I actually sat here,
bro, it wouldn't trust me, it wouldn't
hit the same game.
>> Personality.
>> Now, the Shay is me when I'm talking to
most artists, right? I'm always making
those same talking points. You can
connect with your fans. You can build
and get closer with them. But I think
that Blue Face's concerns are actually
pretty valid. And he brings up a really
big point that I'm sure that a lot of
artists are thinking about. He believes
that artists should only be seen in
rare, controlled, filtered moments and
that the more you show yourself, the
less valuable you become to your fan
base. And as much as I personally
disagree with him, I know that he's not
the only artist of that caliber who
thinks that way.
>> I was one of the first rappers to
stream. I was streaming in 2017. I was
before the wave completely.
>> So why'd you stop?
>> I became too accessible as an artist.
>> You think that it impacts like the way
people like consume your music?
>> I don't want you to think I'm a streamer
of a rapper. It's just about what you
love to do as a person. Like, bro, I'm
an artist. My artist integrity is at
100. I need you to understand that and
respect that, you know, and I love
playing games. But also, I'm going tell
you, when you do these things, right,
like, you know, when you do these
YouTube videos and you show the world
your everyday life and you're twitching
every day at 6:30 and you're on
Instagram live, people treat you like
the on the street.
>> So, let's break down what they're both
saying, right? If fans see me too much,
I stop feeling like a celebrity. That's
basically what they're both saying.
Their biggest complaint is that
streaming makes you look normal. And
yes, I can understand how the fear of
being perceived as normal is a real
thing for artists of that caliber and
that size, but it's something that most
artists probably aren't even thinking
about or are concerned with. But I do
think that Blueface adds another really
interesting layer to that argument.
>> So, if I was to stream, right, I'll
probably stream something like me
working out. No, I'll do something like
where I don't have to interact like
where you guys just watching the
interaction part. Listen, just listen to
me. the interaction part, bro. You gonna
do some lame [\h__\h] bro. Bro, you know
you done did some lame [\h__\h] on accident
>> unintentionally, right? You You know you
done did some unintentionally. And I'm
saying as an artist, you can't you can't
like you don't get that many chances to
do lame [\h__\h] unintentionally, you know?
>> And and when you do that, you're putting
yourself at risk all the time. You know
what I'm saying? Soon as the stream go
down, now I'm doing this, you know, like
I'm doing lame [\h__\h]
>> Oh, you just did it. Big click. Cool.
So, I was watching these clips and I was
thinking, what does Mataya Blueface and
Lil Yachty all have in common? And it
clicked for me. It's about the lack of
control over the perception that
potential fans or just viewers of their
content may have and how it may project
into spaces and things that they don't
want people to believe. Right? Because
in that clip, Blueface is literally
saying, "Hey, the more that we as
artists stream, the more opportunities
that we have to look lame. And we can
only be lame so many times before our
brand starts to spiral out of control.
And I think what makes that clip even
funnier, right, is the fact that DDG is
obviously trolling him when he says, "Oh
man, you just did it. You only got two
more of those." And now we're seeing
this clip everywhere and we're all
moving past whatever the stupid thing is
that he may feel like he did. And that
really is the internet in a nutshell,
right? Artists have to realize that fans
do not care as much about these moments
as you may think they do. And I get it,
right? Like artists are scared to be
seen without control of their art and
control of their brand and their world.
But here's the problem. Some of the
biggest artists in the world are doing
the exact opposite.
>> So this week Justin Bieber did a really
interesting move and he basically
launched a streaming channel. Justin
Bieber like playing basketball,
skateboarding, playing pool. So he he
created this like $20 million warehouse.
There's like a 100 foot screen where you
can like see all this live stream
comments. It's like he's like living in
like the Truman Show. like it's like
everyone can just watch him live his
life. But in the back of the warehouse,
they have a full set so he can perform
music live on this streaming channel.
And what I think is really interesting
about where I think this is going is
this is how he's going to monetize his
music in an age of where music streaming
is making no money. Listen to this. In
2021, Bieber broke Spotify's record for
most all-time monthly listeners ever
with a whopping 83.3
million streams. While those numbers are
obviously impressive, Spotify reportedly
pays 0.004
per stream. So for 83.3 million
individual song streams, Bieber would
only pocket $333,000.
So what it shows you is the current
model, the only way to maintain the
money that he's used to making is to
tour.
>> Yeah.
>> And he doesn't want to tour. And I think
what Justin Bieber has figured out
because of how big streaming has become,
he will start to stream music and
showcase music to drive more album sales
or whatever.
>> He's literally not that interesting. Me
watching him play basketball. Okay,
good. You you got a three-pointer. Like
snore. People don't have enough time in
the day to pay attention to that. He's
got to double down on concerts. He's got
to go hang out with Taylor Swift and
say, "I know this is tough, but making
money is tough. It's not about just
playing in your warehouse. That's not
interesting."
>> I think you're right on the it's boring.
You got to do the hard work. Making
money is hard. All of those points was a
mic drop moment. Where I think you're
wrong is how big streaming is becoming
and how much money streamers are making
by doing something that doesn't make
sense to us. This is for the next gen.
like the next generation is like really
spending a ton of money and time on
these streaming platforms. I think it's
interesting for brands to start tapping
into this. Like I think that there is
something interesting about having this
view into what happens at a brand, how
to do it in a way that is less on 24
hours a day. I think the brands that do
this first will break out.
>> So I mean look at Justin Bieber living
life. Yes, slightly curated, but still
not mysterious and not acting larger
than life in the traditional artist
ways. Now, will anybody here argue that
doing these streams has made Justin
Bieber any less of a superstar? Of
course not. And I think that Justin
Bieber's stream actually taps into
something that Lil Yachty brought up
during his point. He mentioned that, you
know, in his own pursuit of streaming
and content, he felt like there was an
issue with showing things that made him
feel connected to the art and connected
to the music. And I hear that concern a
lot from artists. And I think that the
big phobia around streaming is how do I
stream without having to be a streamer,
right? How do I stream and do these
things and take advantage of it without
me feeling like I'm giving up my
artistic integrity or people actually
thinking that I'm an influencer or a
streamer first and a music artist second
or third. And I think that Justin
Bieber's stream shows a really good
mixture of all that stuff, right? like
I'm watching him be human and be, you
know, whatever regular person Justin
Bieber is, but I'm also watching him
have a jam session and work on music and
write out songs and I'm getting to see
the real artist side of Justin Bieber.
So, I would say if anything, that stream
has made Justin Bieber fans feel way
more connected to him and his artistry.
Now, here's the part that I think a lot
of artists don't understand, but it's
something that Justin Bieber's team and
label 100% understand, and it's that
streaming doesn't just build connection
with your fan base and your audience. It
also builds a content bank. Wait, quick
pause because a lot of you have been
asking, "How can I work with you guys
one-on-one?" And yes, we can run almost
any type of marketing campaign at this
point, but honestly, we prefer working
with clients from a consulting
standpoint because we actually get a
chance to deep dive into their music. We
can work on their brand. We can work on
their content strategy. We can tie it
all together into a marketing campaign.
Basically, we can give you a blueprint
on how to grow, monetize, and win. So,
if you're an artist that's serious about
getting their branding together, their
content strategy together, their
marketing together, then apply for a
call with our country brand agency arm
using the link in the description below.
Serious inquiries only, please, guys.
So, if this sounds like something you
need, once again, hit that link in the
description. And if not, we still love
you anyway. All right, guys. Commercial
break over. Let's get back to the video.
Now, here's the part that a lot of
artists don't understand. Streaming not
only builds connection with your fan
base, it actually builds a pretty
healthy content bank. And you can do so
by using this little known trick that
streamers have been using to get press
attention since the dawn of time.
>> This phrase clip farming, which is
something I see frequently on the
internet now. Uh it seems like it's an
attempt of people to say things that are
kind of like outlandish because they
know that they will then get clipped. Is
that how clip farming works?
>> Well, it's not necessarily outlandish,
but it's it's like purposely being
funny. I think I'm one of the funniest
people on earth. Like if Kevin Hart
didn't exist, I would be Kevin Hart.
Literally like I think if me and Kevin
Hart did one-on-one stand up, I'm on one
stage, he on the other stage, I had a
bigger crowd.
>> Is that clip forming right there?
>> That was definitely clip.
>> That was it.
>> So I mean DDG is being funny, but he
definitely gave you guys the blueprint
to go viral from posting. Now streamers
often clip form to get salacious or
crazy or out there takes that they can
use to then get posted by the blog pages
and the meme page. And now look, I do
think that artists can take a page out
of that playbook, right? If you're that
type of artist and you don't mind that
type of attention and backlash around
yourself, then yeah, do some streams
where you say, you know what I'm saying,
and give some crazy takes and there's a
very high chance that you can get an
organic piece of content because you
will probably create something that will
start a conversation within your fan
base. But I do also think that there are
artistic ways to clip form, right? Like
you can do things centered around your
music that are so salacious and so out
there, whether that be creatively or
visually or, you know, you're doing a
stunt, right? Like imagine somebody
playing a piano. Please don't do this.
But imagine somebody playing a piano
while like jumping out of a plane or
something, bro. That's basically clip
forming. They're for sure going viral.
And I think that in the best best case
scenario, you end up creating a moment
that helps you go viral and helps you
start conversation. Worst best case
scenario, you got some on camera
practice. And if you're thinking to
yourself, man, Coby, I think it's crazy
that I have to think about streaming
just to add more pieces of content. I
already make a lot of content. I do my
cool performance videos. you know, I I
got this one coming up in front of this
real chill church location I have. I
don't need to add content to my bank. I
would start by saying one, you and I
both know that's not true. And two, if
you think that's wild, wait until you
learn how labels are using streaming
content to help build this next part of
their marketing engine.
>> Record labels are posing as fans online
and creating fan pages to further
promote the artists they work with.
Although this might sound like a
conspiracy theory to someone who hasn't
heard it before, who's outside of the
music business, this is talked about
very freely in music right now. In fact,
I would say it is the go-to digital
marketing strategy right now. Almost
every artist that I've ever heard of
who's in album cycle within the last
year has done it. But as anyone who's
ever run a fan page before knows, it
takes a lot of time and effort to run
one of these. Often this involves
posting somewhere between one to five
times a day and also gathering the right
material so that you have good stuff to
post. In a story I put out yesterday for
Billboard discussed one very important
source of material that labels will use
in their fan page strategy. So here's
the story. I found that music marketers
are turning increasingly towards unique
in-person, often intimate events in
order to help their digital marketing
strategy. By hosting something super
special in person, it often encourages
fans to create user generated videos,
which then amplifies the event from
something that was probably only held
for like 50 to 200 people into something
that can be consumed by millions of
people all around the world. All
American Rejects House Party Tour is a
perfect example of this. I didn't get to
go. I saw so many clips online that I
almost felt like I did. Is another great
example. I also didn't get to go to that
because I don't live in Brooklyn, but
all my friends who live in Brooklyn were
posting all these photos and live
streams of it and I was able to watch it
from across the country. So anyways, how
does this relate to the fan page
strategy? Well, just because music
marketers are turning increasingly
towards in-person events again, that
doesn't mean that they're ignoring
digital marketing strategies. One of my
experts for this story, Jamie Skinner,
told me that in fact hosting cool
in-person events really helps with the
fan page thing. He said arguably
gathering this UGC is actually essential
for running the fan pages right now
because again you have to post one to
five times a day. Where are you going to
get that content? The fans you're really
scaling how far each piece of content
can go. Skinner says then on top of that
we're doing micro influencer campaigns
too and we can just ask these micro
influencers to go to these events to
capture moments. Many of them are happy
to just go to the show, capture a
specific moment that we briefed them on,
get them to post and then send us the
high-res files. It's great. So, that's
another digital marketing trend that has
been happening even longer than the fan
pages. Hiring creators big and small to
post about a song or go to a concert and
talk about how great it was in order to
encourage the sale of tickets or
increase streams of the song. Jaime is
saying here, he's able to do the creator
strategy, he's able to do the fan page
strategy, and he's able to do the
inperson strategy all in one. Like, why
not invite a creator to a small intimate
set? The only thing that they have to do
in return for getting that access is to
post a very specific moment that you
brief them on beforehand. Then once they
turn in the high-res files, the
marketers have it on hand and they can
just start reposting it over and over
again on these fake fan pages. Maybe if
you've never heard of this, this fan
page strategy might freak you out.
That's valid. But I think marketers
would tell you that the main point of
doing all that is to combat the
saturation of the internet. It's harder
and harder to break through every day.
And also, this alleviates the stress
that's often put on artists to post more
on TikTok all the time. So, it's good
for the artist, too. But anyways, let me
know what you think of this.
>> Yeah, you see the play now. You see the
play now, don't you? Artists stream.
They stream to create moments that they
can then give to these fan pages that
can then post the content and help them
break through the noise of the internet.
And you heard it here yourself. Labels
are pretending to be fan pages not
because they think it's cute or just
because they think it's fun. No, it's
because they know they need to post a
lot of content about you and all of that
content isn't about to come from your
main account. And also, it might be a
lot of content that you just don't want
to make. Now, she talked about it in
relation to labels having their artists
do events to be able to use those events
to get content to feed the fan pages.
But if we boil it down, all she really
said is that labels make moments so they
can market it later. And you can be very
meticulous and strategic about your
streams to make sure that you're doing
it in the same way to give yourself the
room to be able to stream for the sake
of getting content and not because
you're necessarily trying to become the
next kasinat or a show speed. And bonus
points if you got fans that watch you
already because streaming is going to
give you a lot of these clips
automatically. You stream, fans record
you, fans clip up their favorite moment,
they repost it, and all you got to do is
scroll later on and pick the moments
that you want to use later for your ad
campaigns or your seeding campaigns. But
once again, even if you don't have a
crazy fan base built up or you're in
about, you know, a mid-tier system where
maybe you do have fans that watch you,
but it's not a crazy amount. they're not
super clipping you or anything like
that, then you have to be strategic and
you have to make sure that these boxes
are getting ticked, right? I'm going
into this stream to create XYZ pieces of
content that help me execute XYZ
narratives and XYZ goal so I can
continue pushing forward with my other
more artistic artist content. Basically,
you're creating a media team for
yourself. Now, I already mentioned it
earlier, but you're not streaming to try
to become a streamer. Unless you are,
then hey, hats off to you. but you're
streaming for other future marketing
initiatives that you are either in the
process of trying or may want to try out
down the line. You may even be using it
to cover holes that you couldn't get
covered by traditional press or
influencer campaigns, right? Like
streaming can really help you guys save
a lot of money. Let's say, for example,
you stream so you can have some extra
UGC to post. You stream so you can show
your artistry and find these different
micro ways to prove to people how
talented of an artist you really are.
And you stream so your brand can coexist
in the real world and on paper and on
camera and not just in your head. And if
you want to use streaming the right way
as an artist to help you build out that
sweet sweet content engine, then here's
how you start. Number one, start small.
You don't need super long streams. Once
again, you're not trying to be Kenat.
You're not trying to be a show speed.
You can start really small by streaming
for one to two hours two to three times
a week. And in these streams, remember,
you're not chasing viewers. You're just
looking to build your on camera presence
and creating moments that you can clip
and use later. Number two is treat your
stream like a production. Don't just go
live. Plan three to five specific or key
things that you want to do during that
stream so you can get those moments that
you can use later for your marketing.
This could be a listening session. This
could be you breaking down the
inspiration of a song. This could be you
recording yourself or engineering a
session. This could be you reacting to
music or a video or something. something
that gives you a particular piece of
content for you to hit a particular goal
within your marketing and branding
campaigns. So remember, you're not
randomly streaming. You're streaming to
create moments and create scenes that
you can live through. And number three
is create a fan page for yourself. And
yes, you heard me. Now, I've said this
in the video, as a matter of fact, you
should check it out, me ranking music
marketing strategies, where I do talk a
little bit deeper about uh the fan page
strategy and things like that. But if
you are a bigger artist, let's say
someone that's sitting at over a 100,000
monthly listeners, I would say you can
comfortably get away with one to maybe
three fan pages. If you're in the
millions, you can get away with way more
than that. If you're less than that
100K, do one. You know what I'm saying?
Don't get greedy. Don't get too out
there. Do one page. But you're going to
treat that fan page like a content lab.
Let that be the page where you post
majority of your stream clips. Even the
ones that you may feel like don't 100%
represent you and your artist brand,
right? If you feel cringey about it, if
you feel weird about it, throw it on the
fan page. If you feel really good about
it, maybe it goes on your main feed and
your fan page. But either way, that fan
page is going to be the place where you
experiment with edits, you test
reactions, you you you try out once
again things that you may feel weird
about or or not have the greatest gut
feeling about in a controlled
environment where if it works, you
benefit from the clip going viral or the
clip doing well. And if it doesn't work,
then you post past it and you keep it
pushing with whatever other artistic
content you have coming out on your main
account. So your main page gets to stay
curated and on brand and on world and
all that cool stuff. and your fan page
gets to play. It gets to test and
possibly go viral. So, here's the truth
that I think I learned today, right? And
I think that artists aren't necessarily
scared of creating content or streaming.
They're scared of being seen as regular
by their fan base or seen as corny or
whatever by even the people around them.
But being regular is exactly how most of
your fan bases fall in love with you in
the first place, right? Being corny or
being cringe is how a lot of you guys
get attention. Because the people that
don't want to be corny and don't want to
be cringe, I'm doing really strong air
quotes. Those are the people we very
rarely see. And I'm not saying you have
to do something that you don't feel good
about or you don't feel proud about to
build yourself and grow your your artist
brand, but we should not be listening to
people who don't have entertainment
goals on what looks corny and what
doesn't look corny. I think that's
crazy. And I think what's even better is
that you guys don't have to stream to
become a streamer, but you can stream to
build a world and to document pieces
that help you map it out as meticulously
and as strategically as you need to. And
as a matter of fact, I didn't even get
into clipping in this video, right? Like
that's the trifecta here. Stream, get a
lot of content, post that content on the
fan pages, get the clippers to go crazy.
But that might have to be a whole
separate video in itself. At the very
least, I hope you walk away from this
video not necessarily feeling like, hey,
I need more content, but more so I need
more of a structure to create moments
around myself so I have interesting
content. That really, I think, is what
is the big point of the video that I
wanted to make. So guys, let me know
what you think. Do you think that
streaming is a cheat code to getting
content? And can you see how this could
help you 2x, 3x, 4x, 5x, 10x your
content output? Or do you think that
this is another nuisance? You know what
I'm saying? On an artist plate and
you're pretty good at the content output
that you're at. Let me know your
thoughts in the comments section below.
Other than that, if you like this video,
make sure you hit the like button,
subscribe, share this with an artist
that needs a little bit of gain today.
My name is Corey and I'll see you guys
next time. Beast.