Hey everybody, it's Sean Taylor and I'm
back with more ways to build and blow up
as an artist. Today we're going to go
over seven steps to build a fan base
like Chance the Rapper. And I should say
a fanatical fan base because Chance the
Rapper has probably the realest fan base
there is. And I mean fan base, not just
I like their music so it gets the most
plays. I'm talking about really
mobilizing people. He's has the realest
fan base. You'll see what I'm talking
about in hip-hop right now in terms of a
young artist, especially for being
independent. So, let's start as as it
grew. My dad is like, you know, he was a
campaign manager. He put people in in
office, put showed people to the people,
you know what I'm saying? Um, and my dad
at a certain point kind of campaign
managed me and and showed me how to
like, you know, print flyers and and
move on foot and work organically with
the people to like my base. He was a
political activist kind of. He was out
there. I'm for the people, right? So,
this is what to think about. How can you
campaign like Chance? Because he learned
from his dad and his dad was a campaign
manager. So, what do campaign managers
campaign like? This is what we're going
to go over in this video.
But I'm I'm a an artist of sorts and uh
from Chicago and for the people. So in
this clip, Chance said he's for the
people. In the last clip, he said he's
for the people and he put his fist up.
And that's number one when it comes
to campaign management. Know who you
are. It sounds kind of weird. It sounds
kind of corny, but know who you are
because you have to have a clear
understanding of who you are to know how
you want to communicate with the people.
Everyone who doesn't know who don't know
Chance a Rapper, you don't sell your
music. No, it's free. Yeah. Um, do you
know do you know you can't
How do you How do you make money? Uh,
yeah. Well, I'm I'm on tour right now.
I'm a touring artist. uh as uh music
grows there there's always new ways of
releasing and you know there's visual
albums and you know full concerts and
and big Broadway
musicals. Rule number
two, know your audience. So what does
that really mean? Right? First you have
to know who you are. Then you have to
know your audience because you have to
know how to communicate, interact with
that audience. Chance doesn't sell
records. his audience, the young
audience. People don't want to hear that
[\h__\h] these days. They don't want to hear
anybody crying about how, oh, I don't
make enough money or people should start
paying for stuff. They don't want to
hear that. That's dead. So, not only
does he resonate even stronger with his
audience by
not actually selling his music, but he
also even goes on to speak of these
creative ways that he could make money
anyway. And that kind of stuff just
makes you like him even more, right?
because the ways he thought of was give
more content, Broadway shows and
touring, actually giving more to the
audience, to his fans, as opposed to
just trying to figure out some kind of
sneaky business ways. And I want to go
back and re see how he um the audience
reacts once again when he says he
doesn't sell music. Everyone who doesn't
know who don't know Chance a Rapper, you
don't sell your music. No, it's free.
Yeah. Um do you know do you know you
can't
see that speaking to his audience and
knowing how to get them and move them.
But let's move on from there. We can go
into that
later. Have a story to tell. This is
huge part of any campaign management.
This how you move people. You can think
civil rights, how people had this
entire movement, this backstory of
slavery and things like that to move
people on. Well, look how Chance with
10day had a complete story around it.
I'm going to let him tell it himself.
Explain the concept of 10day. 10day was
uh recorded while I was on uh 10day
suspension from high school. What you
do? Why you get suspended? Weed. I have
Yeah, I have marijuana. I don't know
what the rules are for FM radio. I was
saying I had weed. Not really a lot of
weed, but like on on school property, I
guess. Or like a half a zip. A zip. No,
like like a like a maybe maybe a
quarter. Maybe a quarter. Were you
selling or smoking? I was smoking, but
they were trying to say I had intent to
sell, but I didn't. I had it in one bag.
It was for me. It doesn't matter. I just
I'm a user. I wasn't really trying to
say nothing to him. I didn't know what
was incriminating, what was not. So, I
was chilling.
So, when you hear Chance tell this
story, this makes people relate to him,
particularly in that age range. This was
his very first drop. You have a story.
There's a whole concept, but it's not
even all this. It's not so abstract.
It's 10 days. Okay, 10 days suspension.
A lot of people can relate to
suspension. I was suspended twice. Then
you have this concept of the weed.
People can relate to the weed. There's
so many ways and things people could
relate to a story. And people will
always pull what they can relate to most
out of that story because it resonates
with them and it gives them a visual of
who the person is. And people are always
trying to figure out who is this artist.
They're trying to figure out ways to get
closer.
When you even look at acid rap, acid rap
had a story in itself. Just the whole
idea of acid rap, it creates a story of
who you think Chance is, what you expect
from the music. And now, even if you
didn't have any kind of name from the
music, now you're thinking, okay, what
made him think of that? He must have
been on acid, right? And even coloring
book, the last project, that had a story
in itself. It was a lot less
straightforward than the first two
projects, but when you have such a
strong fan base and following at that
point, people are going to be listening
for some kind of concept and creating
themselves. And what you could probably
get out of that album is just the fact
that he's um in a better place in life.
And that's kind of the constant theme
throughout that whole project. He's in a
better place. Um thank God he, you know,
is having having a child and with his
girl, all that kind of stuff. But it's
constantly constantly implementing
stories to give your crowd or to and
people something to resonate and move
with because when people can relate to
you, they feel closer to you. When they
feel closer to you, they will do more
for you. And as an artist, that's how
you have f power. And we'll get to that
later
on. So look at this. Chance is just
making a tweet. Chicago Bulls. So, not
only is he staying strong with his local
folks, but that's just a small little
interaction. That's how a lot of people
use Twitter. And then you look at this
tweet. He tweeted these cute little
babies. Look at the babies. It's
Halloween. People got their babies
dresses. Chance the rapper. Once again,
it's how strong. It's showing how strong
his fan base is. People have babies
dressed like this dude. And this is
young in his career. Think about it. And
then look, baby, baby, baby. Look at
these cute ass babies. That is a strong
strong engagement with his audience. He
stays engaged with his audience. When
you constantly engage with your
audience, you become more real to your
audience. People love you even more. And
a lot of people, they don't necessarily,
well, a lot of artists, I mean, they
want this whole mysterious thing. And if
that's the thing you're going for, you
know, that whole prince thing, that's a
different type of story. That's a
different strategy. But this is for
those people who want really strong
engaged audiences that will do damn near
anything for you. And that's what Chance
has and he's been developing. Uh not
that many years ago, I was, you know,
still trying to pass out my mixtape. I'm
still trying to pass out my mixtapes. Do
you guys know how hard it is to make
everybody know your music? Like even
when people feel like, you know, you
can't get much bigger or your music's
played everywhere, like when you're an
artist, your sole, you know, purpose is
to like share your music with
everybody. This is a key. I'm for two
reasons really. I just can't escape.
Every single time I have a video, I'm
not going to make it a core strategy
because it's obvious and everybody
should do it to the max. Get attention.
It shows that he understands this. Even
as big as he is, he's still passing out
resources. But that's only a small tip
of the iceberg to also touch about the
fact that he's galvanizing his
resources. He even recognizes himself as
a resource and still to this day passes
out mixtapz when he gets a chance. But
I'm going to show a even stronger
version of galvanizing resources at the
end. So check this out. If you guys
don't know about Chance the rapper,
Buddy in the middle, Donnie Trumpet, and
the Social Experiment, that's all these
guys around him, he constantly works
with these guys in various ways. But
they even had a social experiment
project. Collaboration is a key. It's a
strong key when it comes to campaigning,
that whole campaign management style,
because you want to strengthen the
relationships. It's all about
relationships. If you notice, everything
that is I've talked about and that he's
done is all about creating strong bonds
at scale with a lot of people. It's hard
to create bonds with a lot of people and
make them strong, but if you can, then
you can move mountains. That's that
Martin Luther King type stuff. And also,
you got to have a team. I just put that
in parenthesis down there. So, some of
these people, these friends are also his
his team in various projects in various
ways as well. We'll have a whole another
video um about just team in general if
it's necessary and enough people want to
hear about that though. Also,
collaboration. I don't know if you guys
even understand how huge of a deal for
independent artists, especially hip-hop,
to be on Ellen. It's [\h__\h] ridiculous.
It doesn't happen at all. Prince Chance,
call him Prince. Chance might have
broken barrier. So now more people might
be in that window now. He's broken
through. But like Ellen is the hugest is
it doesn't make sense. But look at this
collaboration. Look at some more
collaboration. Everybody knows probably
already that's two chain little Wayne.
Sorry. Skrilix is over here in the
background with him on Steven Cobear.
Another mind-blowing the fact that he
was on there. And then if you check this
out, I think this was on Jimmy Fallon
collaboration with Anthony Hamilton.
Todd dollaran Rory to the far right.
Obviously, he's the guy that's kind of
darkening out right there. You don't see
collaborations like these and all. This
was one of the most super interesting
collaborations I've seen. The fact that
he was smart enough to do something like
this cuz they weren't on the regular
track at least well probably on some
kind of vocal course, but to actually
bring them out unheard of, but it shows
how he
constantly builds abnormal relationships
and makes them very strong.
mobilize. Now, we're getting to the
sweet stuff. I just had to put this one
on front street because when you have a
culmination of all those things that
we've talked about so far, right?
Mobilize is number seven. You really
have power when I say you can do more
and move mountains to do something like
this. Right? Chance the rapper had a
parade to
vote this election. Obviously, Donald
Trump won, but he had all these people
come out around him. He had a free
concert, then had people walk with him
to vote. You see Richard Branson
tweeting this. I don't know if you guys
understand how huge that is. This dude's
a billionaire for him even know who
Chance is. And there's so much I can say
about that, but it really shows how
Chance is really creating a movement.
And you can create a powerful movement,
too, if you follow these seven
strategies. It takes time. It takes
some, you know, some smarts. But then
there are also other strategies. Like I
said that once again, I'll go over more
if people want to hear different
strategies. I just need to get that
feedback and those views. Share this
with your friends. Um if if you think
they'll be interested, if they're just
trying to campaign or if they want to be
rappers and campaign that way to create
a following. Also, I'll just drop it
off. If you really want to have that
following, once again, I can't reiterate
enough. You can follow these steps and
you can end up possibly looking like
this.
[Music]
Hope to hear from you guys. Subscribe.
I'm dropping something next week.