being a mysterious artist has its pros
and cons but nobody ever talks about it
in this video we're going to talk about
not only the pros and cons of being a
mysterious artist but how do you
implement those strategies and more
importantly when what's up I'm Brandman
Sean and my agency has helped over 100
artists grow their fan base and do
millions of streams and I don't say that
to sell anything to you but to let you
know where this information is coming
from let's get into this video all right
so one of the biggest problems that most
people have when it comes to mysterious
branding and branding in general is not
understanding that branding can change
your brand can change over time and when
they think you have to be stuck as a
mysterious artist stuck as an artist
that has all this visibility and you're
over saturating the marketplace they
don't understand branding you're always
only one or two moves away from
rebranding yourself into something
completely different there's been
artists who have done it time and time
again and we're going to talk about the
entire stepladder that you can go
through and what moves to make when so
this brings me back to the white board
where we map out mystery known saturated
but that starting point that so many
artists begin at right everybody unknown
right unknown unknown unknown so when we
go through the levels we're going to
talk about a beginning artist an
established artist a superstar artist
and a legacy act there's these levels
and even though you might already be on
one level acknowledging and
understanding each level will help you
understand everything so even if you're
like a beginning artist you haven't even
got popping yet it's worth watching the
entire Spectrum so you can think ahead
plan ahead and if you're somewhere else
you know your head looking at other
parts of it will just help you
understand where you are a little bit
more so let's talk about the unknown
artist you're trying to get popping you
cannot try to be mysterious no way no
way no way almost said no way Jose which
I've never said in my life but there we
go I just said it unknown
artists have to get known that's all you
need to be focused on getting on getting
on getting on now in a way that's corny
to you right everybody has a different
definition of corny but you have to
figure out how you can get known you
can't worry about being mysterious just
yet right because it's just two
different gears you can't put your foot
on the brake and the gas at the same
time you can but the results ain't
necessarily going to do anything for you
right probably more damaging than
anything and that's what a lot of
artists go through that's what you're
trying to accomplish so what does this
mean get known now the pros of being
mysterious as a new artist I'm not even
gonna write anything on the board it's
basically nothing unless you have a
budget and resources so let's separate
from an indie artist and an artist with
a hell of a lot of resources maybe at a
major label or something like that and
Indie artist you have no career that's
the result of trying to be mysterious at
the beginning which means you're not
going to have a career in the first
place but the pros if you happen to be
an artist who is at some type of label
situation or you just have resources for
whatever reason the benefit of immediate
mystery at the moment that people begin
to find out about you is conversation
generation right you get conversations
generated really quickly we can go back
to her right she came on the scene she
had the label I think it was RCA right
they put the budget you start seeing
this artist and there's this silhouette
you don't even see whose project this is
literally her first project the cover
was a silhouette and you don't know who
her is that's like a name that no one
can really associate with anybody in
particular at that time mystery who is
this who is this who is this this
person's dope do you know who this is
everybody's trying to figure out who
that is right that's a great part about
it it generates conversation that
becomes viral and it begins to work for
you but the problem is that it's very
short-lived you can capture that
lightning in a bottle but you have to
move on as a new artist because people
still don't care enough yet right
knowing and caring
it's a dance it's a dance the music
being great enough like her situation
that makes people care a lot more but
still the lasting value they have to
continue to care and I've talked about
before it's hard to uphold that level of
caring that violates the mystery right
now so you move on to the next part and
let's just say you get known all right
once people know you can you be
mysterious
yeah you can start to add some mystery
right
what happens is you begin to go down
this direction though right
and the con of the moment you start to
get known and you pull back and start
generating mystery is
you begin to lose the momentum of
saturating the market right I'm not even
talking about over saturating I'm
talking about getting on my more and
more people you cut off a certain set of
moves when you decide to slow down in
that way and ultimately what happens
then means you stunt your growth you
can't take advantages of certain as many
opportunities and now you are basically
settling in with this size of a fan base
whatever that is right it's relative but
like if this is your size of fan base
even if you continue in career in most
cases you're probably only going to grow
incrementally versus killing that
momentum and growing exponentially in
that short period of time so mystery
oftentimes is a pullback that creates a
plateau right if you try to pull back
now this can be good for a niche artist
who honestly doesn't desire to be super
saturated known by every single person
in the world or to make the type of
music or moves that that requires right
I mentioned Playboy cardi in the video
he's somebody who matches that mode
where his Niche loves the hell out of
him but there's a lot of people who
don't listen to his music don't even
know who he is right but his Niche he's
a legend in his Niche right mystery
especially when you're only at a known
level and you're doing it within a niche
can make you a legend it's one of the
easiest ways to become a legend in a
niche in particular right because you
still only have those people who know
you who almost value being ahead of the
game and no one else knowing you so they
get to maintain that inside Inner Circle
feeling forever all right now with that
being said
doesn't mean you can't ever get a big
look right it just means it won't come
at the same amount and overall you won't
have as many opportunities as the
artists who have continued to saturate
the market right now
saturation over saturation all that
great stuff
let's say you become a superstar like
everybody knows your name right where
everybody knows your name I can't
remember where that's from I think it's
cheers or something the pros of mystery
and Mystique in this particular case is
when you have Superstar level of
saturation anything between known and
Superstar right you've saturated at
least
when you have that level of saturation
in the marketplace
people know you people Beyond know you
and there's people who know you that
don't even care so you have everything
you need to then create mystery right
people who care care people who don't
care at all they hate you they're mad
they even know you
all you have to do is pull back right
and keep going
the problem is a lot of people don't
know what to do when they get there
right there's different ways and moves
that you can make but pulling back
actually is a part of survival creating
some level of Mystique is actually a
part of survival once you hit that place
if you just if you don't if you don't
get strategic about the moves you make
you'll just fall into known right which
is kind of purposeless when you are
coming down right and you come up it's
purposeful right there's an intent you
you're driving upwards you're getting
known there's a buzz being created about
you but once you hit that point and then
you don't have strategic moves you fall
into this lull and it's just whatever
the public begins to think you're loose
and that's those Brands where we know
that person who's a one-hit wonder or
they had a nice run but people don't
really care beyond that the next
Generations don't have as big of a
connection with them or you don't even
have as big of a connection with them
they were just reflecting that period of
your life but not one of those artists
you continue to follow and continue to
Value right so
what do you want to be the period party
artist or do you want to be that artist
that you know is has a legacy with
whatever your fan base has that's kind
of the difference of that right now why
do I say survival because no one can
maintain over saturation for an extended
period of time even like decent
saturation for an extended period of
time because even when you're at
saturation and not over saturation the
people who already know you and actually
do care about you inevitably are
becoming oversaturated right so you're
not not even thinking about the people
who don't care about you and that you
get forced on that level the people who
already know and like you are following
you so it becomes easy for them to be
over saturated with you right so you
pull back your activity then you fall
into Mystique right that's what you want
to be
me
stick not mystery
hopefully you can read that all right
Mystique because mystery
it's hard to maintain you fall into
mystery for a moment as a pullback
possibly right where you just disappear
and people don't know for where you are
for just a little you know period of
time but then you have to pop up
strategically and be a part of certain
things whether that's letting them know
about what you're doing right
um and again this is oftentimes for
third parties in this period right can't
be from you directly it might just be oh
that person's working on this particular
project and it's about to come out right
oh this is Jay-Z in the studio oh this
is Jay-Z did some business deals so
you're still hearing about the person
but they're not outwardly trying to
promote themselves it doesn't appear
that way because be aware that all that
stuff is is known by you because they
put that information out there and
that's what you would be doing at that
level you will be putting information
out there right so people can be aware
of you you stay on their minds but right
it's not coming directly from you it's
not self-promotion
and that's what allows you to have this
Mystique so it becomes survival once
you're at that level a legacy act right
it's the same thing all right it allows
you to have survival for people to care
over time what you're doing right when
someone has Mystique
when you step out people think there's a
purpose to what you're doing they know
that you're not out all the time if I'm
just saying you all the time oh I just
saw you another day right but if I
decided to fall back you don't see me
for a while and next thing you know I
show up you're like why are you here he
must be here because this event is
important he must be here because he
actually has something to say so now you
capture their attention this is what
Kendrick Lamar does so so so well right
he captures people's attention by simply
pulling back enough and then coming back
and now people are listening to what he
says trying to decode what he says even
if he's saying something really basic
because they figure the fact that he's
out it can't be for no reason right
everything he does there has to be
something to it and of course he does
reward people with those type of Easter
eggs where he is saying more than the
service level thing but
again even if he wasn't people would
assume and they're always going to find
something anyway that's the beauty about
having Mystique people care but again
mystery
it's too deep of a game if you haven't
seen my other video talking about the
value of mystery being depleted in this
particular time then watch that as well
I will put that in the description but
just know mystery is something that you
want to fall into for moments of time
and create Mysteries something that they
desire something that they want that
they don't have enough of
but don't stay in the mystery box you
really want to stay in the Mystique area
for extended periods of time mystery you
dip in you dip out you dip in of over
saturation and then you dip out right
I'm marking the hell out of this project
and then I pull back all right I'm
marking the hell out of this project I'm
going on tour I'm doing interviews I'm
pulling up to some random YouTubers page
and and I'm on this page and now it's
news that I got enough fighting and
whatever whatever happened I cut my hair
and then I pull back I step away right
like this is why you see the ABS and
flows of so many celebrities that have
lasted for so long right you look at
Beyonce I'm dropping a documentary on my
my life and I'm letting you know my kids
names I'm dropping a project and I'm
going on tour with my husband and then
bam don't hear for a second all right
and then come back with something else
right that is the ab and the flow and
this is why I try to make people
understand that
one brand does not have to exist at all
time all of these things are actually
devices once you get past unknown right
unknown you can't really use that too
heavily outside of the element of
surprise while you're there that's the
one pro that you like completely have on
your side it's harder to do after on
like an extended career but all of these
are devices to use you can be saturated
over saturated and it's the dance
between this and moving on this spectrum
that creates your overall brand nobody
stays here stays here or stays there all
right that's it for this video if you
want to know more about mystery branding
and how you can apply it to yourself
check out this next video right here
peace