byow what's up everybody once again it's
brand man Sean and today's video is
brought to you by so L because soie was
watching the XXX tasson seven tips for
Success video and said this leave
something to be desired can you do a
video on the seventh tip it contradicts
the high relase strategy a little bit
true that's the very reason why you do
not make strategies because if you make
strategies then you don't have a
strategy but that boy so's question did
make me think about the fact that there
is another part to that question that I
haven't discussed yet so here it is yes
it does contradict don't do that the
second answer is eh it doesn't
necessarily contradict itself here's an
extreme case the weekend dropped the
trilogy which was a lot of people's
first introduction to dude that's 30
songs but we all know how mysterious the
weekend was when he first came out
mystery is leaving something to be
desired to the Max and 30 songs dropped
at once is High release volume strategy
to the max how was the weekend able to
do that well I'm kind of about to tell
you chill there's technically three
brands that artists have you have in
front of the curtain you have behind the
curtain and then you have life or
personal whichever one you want to call
it in front of the curtain is basically
artist right it's that first phase when
that superficial level that most people
see of artists you see their
performances right think literally in
front of a curtain the performance think
about the music think about uh any athe
or maybe movies that they're in all of
that in front of the curtain giving
product usually you can Define it by
being the product or a part of the
product and then you have behind the
curtain think about behind the curtain
almost as a job behind the curtain is
the professional version of the artist
how they deal with other professionals
maybe how they collaborate with other
artists how they move throughout the
industry and all of that behind the
scenes stuff just work getting done the
production being made for in front of
the curtains and of course now you have
personal SL life that means the actual
person who who is this person not the
artist who is the actual person what do
they like how do they move what are
their interests and even in the age of
social media this is the least seen side
of artists especially since we still
kind of curate what we show people on
social media but people like trans the
rapper and so many other people in
general is just not chance actually show
hey my kids and me just chilling with my
kid all that stuff is just personal my
life so why does the fact that there are
these three brands matter because each
one can have its own own strategy of
sorts while the weekend is dropping a
high volume release of Music he can
still curate a very mysterious personal
brand because he's not high volume
released in his front-facing personality
two different
boxes I think I left a side off of that
one he wasn't doing a lot of interviews
right so he had a lot of music and
people really got acclimated to him and
his brand but his actual personality
he's not really showing that there's no
high volume release where there's some
artists who are always on social jumping
around you know just trying to get
attention or just letting people into
their world and I'll get to which ones
are most important in a second but I
want to First emphasize that it's very
important that you're at least aware of
these boxes remember when Beyonce
introduce Sasha Fierce to the world she
clearly stated that Sasha Fierce was
somebody that she always had or saw
herself as that box for in front of the
curtain because when she gets on stage
she becomes this different woman that is
not Beyonce so she just actually bring
that front side is somebody separate
which could be pretty important mentally
literally for someone who is actually
going by their real name at all times
and to ask which ones are most important
well technically fans care about number
one and number three the most that's
your in front of the curtains and your
personal life that's what people really
care about they're not really thinking
too much about that behind the scenes
production type so that's what people
pretty much spend a lot of times
branding or deciding how they want to
handle but number two is actually
actually extremely important as well but
it's just a long-term thing that just
can't really be controlled per se
because of the fact that number two is
really your brand with your peers for
the most part that means whoever you're
collaborating with whether that's a
videographer an artist another rapper
you can't really push that brand and
promote it in one way but what makes
that even more potent than the other two
is because then you can create
testimonials cuz if you handle yourself
really great professionally you have
other artists which are other credible
people in the fans eyes talk about you
in whatever way that professional ran is
important case in point think about how
many people talk about Tupac's work
ethic everybody knows that guy had a
crazy work ethic because people who were
with him are always telling stories of
his work ethic whatever brand you
establish there does have a potential to
make a strong impact on your brand
overall but just think of number two
behind the curtains as the long-term
brand Legacy impact because because
that's what turns people into Legends
after you die or just after some years
in your career when people are really
talking about you and giving that that
dirty stuff what it really happened that
fans or nobody ever really knew about
that's when you really just get
solidified that stamp and because of
so's question that sparked this video I
want to end with the last word
contradictions almost never exist past
the surface what we're usually
experiencing is a lack of understanding
or context funny part about that is
because a lot of people are actually too
lazy to think past the surface
contradictions are one of the most
commonly used devices to distract the
public so you can control what they're
thinking or get a different agenda done
anyway please share this guys if you
think other people will find this
helpful and you know what to
do hit that subscribe button