I thought my sound was trash I thought
my stuff was not perfect I like this
ain't this don't sound like no Drake
this don't sound no Teddy but all along
I was creating my own sound and Missy
was telling me a you got a sound I know
yay is a frequency guy so when I went in
there I just know that when he said
something about Sexy Back drums and the
hit I knew exactly what he was talking
about feel like when I did a Le when I
went to the a shoe store and this girl
was like yo yeah he work with a li oh he
got to do the beat
beats is fire I felt like I was
responsible for maybe even putting beats
on the map build your business as you be
an artist don't wait for to go always go
get a deal be the deal you are a deal
you got to structure yourself oh I want
this okay well I need to go get this go
to a bank versus go to a labor even
about you want to call it with AI I
don't call it that I call it a second
opinion I am going to run a Muk and if
you don't run with me you going to be
looking down the street sitting at the
goddam water like damn up to us the same
way y'all [\h__\h] got on autotune but
everybody tried to hate on it but now
you can't live without it
[Music]
Bingo all right what's up Tim oh that's
how we starting
okay what's up what's
up yo man I want to get right to it cuz
we you we talked a lot off camera but I
mean you've been in this thing 30 years
and have reinvented yourself time and
time again how what's the key to
it um I don't know if it's a key I
think it's really being in tune with
yourself and being real with yourself
and knowing
that when it's time to Pivot you got to
know how to Pivot you know what I'm
saying and I thank I thank God for for
giving me the discernment of when to
pivot and when to know that this season
is over and how to jump into our next
season of my career and guidance on how
to do it because you got to remember
through each when you pivot it's like a
restart and a lot of people don't be
don't like to restart they like to just
stay where they at in life and see if
they can keep pulling as much out of it
but hey that's all you going to get out
of that that part but now we have to go
to another part and I just thank God
that he allowed me to always know where
to Pivot you know I'm saying I think
that's how I stay relevant by
staying um very true to myself knowing
when a season is over and knowing it's
time to exit and do something else so
what does that look like is it is it a
feeling you have is it you're looking at
the Horizon and seeing things change
like how do you know when the stand your
ground and and whatever you're working
on and when it's time to Pivot to what
you feel like is coming next that's a
great question um I think it's more of a
reading the room and the room is the
world right and just going outside just
regular just outside just watching
people um looking online just looking at
the energy of the world and just know
that hey what I was doing last year
don't everybody on this this year so
it's like you have to figure out how to
know where to go to be
relevant what's going on today and how
to not just only be relevant but to be
ahead you know what I'm saying so it's
like for me is always a feeling and just
reading the world's energy you know what
I'm saying and then just I think God
always Ta on my shoulder and like put a
joke in me just like I'm always want to
try new things cuz it's like a you don't
get that burning sensation like you used
to and you got to be real with yourself
like damn
I don't even like my stuff you know what
I'm saying it's like you got to start
back liking yourself first you know what
I'm saying cuz you don't you could just
be people be depressed you know why cuz
you ain't like you're not liking
yourself right at this moment you're not
liking where you at you you you got to
you looking for that spark that and
sometimes we look for Sparks you know
let me go spend something let me go do
this that ain't that ain't going to cut
it like you got to be real with yourself
like
yo my [\h__\h] ain't hitting like like I
used to you know what I'm saying I got
to figure it out and that means going
back and sitting down and figuring it
out and it don't come overnight it just
it's just going to take some time it's
like you you was outside you with the
man you know what I'm saying but you got
to go back in training camp you got to
go back into the camp how you know the
difference though between like this is a
trend this is a wave but that's not my
wave because you can't chase every wave
every time that's what I'm saying you
got to go back in let that wave be that
wave you fall back build what you trying
to build so when you come
back it's like a reinvention okay you
know what I'm saying come back with your
own wave bab exactly cuz you'll know
that wave is dying be like D I feel it
people you you can feel it in the air
people be like man I don't like music B
me music music music what do you do
[\h__\h] you do music you know you had your
way
boom not not n I'm here and it's like it
it just repeats itself you know what I'm
saying it's like you got to know when
you know it's pay attention and know
like you'll feel it cuz it's something
that comes in your spirit that you'll be
like nah I know I got it no I got it you
know what I'm saying it's like you don't
really know but you just feel
it and then you just pop back out and
then when you pop back out people like
yo that boy he he killing it again oh he
killing the game you know what I'm
saying look at mustard he was chilling
he popped back
out yeah yeah
it's just what it is it's just you sit
back evaluate live life figure it out no
rush everybody it's there so much
everybody can eat yeah you just got to
know how you going to pop back out I
feel like you kind of hit the nail in
the head too right you said pivoting
without context of what's coming next or
I'm seeing it as pivoting without
context of what's coming next could be
you messing yourself up pivoting with
context of what's coming is you getting
ahead of the curve and I don't know it's
one of those things where I feel like
artists like to be kind of self-absorbed
is probably the best way to put it right
like a lot of times they like to focus
on their own sound or their own craft so
for those type of artists and those type
of creators how do you even begin to go
into the world and and look for what's
next without without feeling like um you
you don't got to look for it it comes to
you okay because they searching you
ain't See It Fade to Black when
inspiration I can't find inspiration I
go find it yeah and who you come
to cuz I'm always
inspired but he didn't know he just know
that when we all work I'm always
inspired that's what he know of
Timberland that Timberland find
inspiration from
somewhere so I don't really have it so I
need to go get
it somebody who has that SP exactly so
when somebody knows of you and they see
your it's a glow that just gonna show on
you you ain't got nobody knocking at
your door cuz you ain't you ain't that
you know what I'm saying like you taking
a like a Hiatus right but then all of a
sudden somebody go knock and you you
just fulfill somebody's Joy you didn't
know summer Walker was looking for that
sound she was everybody's looking for
something cuz you know the temperature
of the world you just stand in your
bubble and somebody going to come and
say man we should go check out blah blah
blah then there going always going to be
that person be like in the camp or in
the circle you sure but energy going to
be so
right everybody going to have the energy
of let's go see let's go see that cuz
they know you was F they know you fire
yeah and they need that they just know
you fire period like you know what I'm
saying like whether I don't have a hit
in four years I know that [\h__\h] fire
yeah I know that producing fire so ain't
going to kill us cuz that that you walk
in the room you going to feel it [\h__\h]
but then [\h__\h] the word going to spread
it just going to spread like WiFi
yo blah blah blah got such and such he
got that [\h__\h] he own that new
[\h__\h] that's interesting because you talk
about people coming to you there's
another situation um like one of my
favorite Clips was when Kanye was
talking about he was going to everybody
for um stronger and then he went to you
and then you see in the clip you like in
like 3 seconds it felt like you knew
exactly what to do with the the beat I
don't the drums I think it was
specifically in that case like what do
you or maybe we could just talk about
that specific case like what are you
listening to and what were you telling
him spec specifically to help him
understand like and and then what was he
seeking cuz me watching from the outside
I understand the general but like from a
producer to producer like what was he
personally like trying to find and what
were you able to give
him see when we talk
music with with yay yay such a
genius I didn't know what yay was I know
know yay is a frequency
guy and I know that I have a lot of
frequency in me so when I went in there
I just know that when he said something
about Sexy Back drums and the hit I knew
exactly what he was talking about
because that's the mission I was on just
to make the kick drum hit so hard that
you didn't need a 808 or a Basse sound
like a dominant to make you be like
you know Bing your head it was
just and it hit in a certain
way that it just was captivating so
stronger he was looking for that same if
you look listen to Stronger it don't
have no
Baseline yeah
yeah you know what I'm saying so it's
like sexy B don't really have no
Baseline it's just a s
got it
okay you know what I'm saying like it's
a method to my little Madness cuz it's
all math and numbers and frequency and
I'm I'm just like a frequency person
like just try to make something that
people don't know that they want what
they
need and and I think at that moment a
stronger like Kanye knew when he heard
sexy back he probably saw all the
elements that wasn't there but felt like
it was there
and he said I need that got you got you
it seems like man you really are like a
scientist when it comes to just sounds
in general because like today for
instance we
got well no I won't even go that far
just like the all the different sounds
your sound period is just so unique that
you know it when you hear it period like
like spe especially at a specific era
like I don't know if you feel like you
evolved and you you know maybe on some
new [\h__\h] we haven't heard but there was
a time where it's like this is so
distinctly
timling where today we got tags and
stuff and then that's how we identifi
but you just had to beat forel had like
the little you know the forehead you
know what I will credit that to
like to us too but then I want to I want
to
say technology evolved so was changed
the frequency in itself I think analog
allow us to have other analog gear to
maybe utilize to kind of give us a sound
and we you still have it on digital but
it still comes out one way right so I
think and this is just Theory right this
is my musical IQ Theory like the way KH
used the ASR the way Rizza use the
ASR it kind of like the ASR was kind of
like a
limit and that's was over there the
keyboard over there it's like it kind of
limits you so it kind of like for it
kind of allows you to create an an an an
orthodox style
but the
frequency on how it came out was
different on everybody so which kind of
added to that sound
because everything was analog and it
allowed you to tune it in a certain way
not saying you can't do that on digital
cuz that digital has grown to that but I
just felt
like what kind of like I got I take
credit that it it was us we all were
uniquely different um but I think it was
the tools that we had to go search for
that we can add on to make a little bit
of that sauce a little different now our
swag is our swag right for real bounce
is his bounce my bounce is my bounce I
just think
that the sound quality from how Dre used
how he used SSL we all have a SSL but
the way Dr Dre Ed it and Teddy
Riley I it's unmatched it's just wait
anything come out of that it's like I
you just be like you don't even say
produce you be like Dre mixed that
didn't he Teddy mixed that didn't he
yeah so it's like it was so many
components that could be used that all
gave off a different feeling when it was
ran through
gotta you know along with god- giving
Talent of what we had in us too you know
what I'm saying and I I think
um we was the first of our kind like
kind of introducing the world of new
cadences um new bounces and then I feel
like it just evolved from there and
that's why because we are The
Originators we're not copycats you know
what I'm saying so it's like why you can
tell a timling sound because
because I thought my sound was
trash and then it
became what I thought was trash or what
I thought
was imperfect
perfect I thought my stuff was not
perfect I like this ain't this don't
sound like no Drake this don't sound no
Teddy but all along I was creating my
own sound and Missy was telling me no
you got a sound but I understand
greatness so I thought I wasn't great
yet but all along I was becoming great
you know what I'm saying but at least I
had my eye on the priz who I was chasing
or trying to get a seat at the table not
to compete but just like to get in the
big boy room like you know what I'm
saying these are the Elite
producers who produce everybody and
every artist going to you know now it's
like I'm in that cycle of greatness when
was the moment where you feel like you
were in that big boy
room I never really felt into
like I got to say really like now now
that's crazy that's weirdest the
weirdest thing like because everybody
you a legend I'm like damn I guess it's
over I guess I made it like I guess and
I'm like damn I've been in the room this
whole time it's that type of thing you
know what I'm saying like I'm like damn
I was in the maybe cuz you know I was I
I was working without blonders I was
working with blonders onone so I
couldn't see what was going on so when
when was the first time you feel like
the world showed you you were what you
were oh I feel like when I did a Leah
when I went to the a shoe store and this
girl was like
yo this girl said something about they
was talking about a leyah but I know
said and somebody said oh that's a guy
um yeah he worked with a leyah oh he got
to do the
beats her beats is fire and that's when
I was like like cuz I didn't know that
you know that was the first time I think
I I felt like I was
responsible for maybe even putting beats
on the map cuz I thought it was always
based on the artist and so her kind of
that kind of let me know
that we matter you know like damn I made
a difference cuz who I didn't know
people listen to to the beat right and
that was when she kind of verified that
as a fan
of aiyah but then said yo the beat that
fire like the what and then then I
started hearing it more I'm like
H then I'm like okay I guess I do got
something you know but when you just
when you in it you never going to see
yourself as Perfection yet
you know you all you feel like you never
really reach
that that goal it's like you always
chasing you know what I'm saying so it's
just and it's a good thing because it
keeps you on your toes you know yeah
it's crazy man imposta syndrome Timlin
is blowing my mind right now man I can't
even imagine you know what I'm
saying cuz yes it feels like the the
people who end up being the greatest all
have like a story of imposter syndrome
I'm saying I still have it to this day
like it's just one of them things man
because Missy taught me so well
um she just trained my ear to the
highest level that I don't think lot of
my stuff that I won't play because I
don't know if it's up the par but my
people was like man you better play that
play that and I'm
like after all these years I still be
doing that that's crazy CU I just I just
put myself to a high standard that I
don't
know I'm just hard on myself I don't
think I ever reached reached it but now
I'm s wanted to
really appreciate all my highlights now
I'm starting to Bast in the glory
of I am I am great I
am I did change the game you know what
I'm saying I think I'm now just
accepting it and being comfortable of
saying it you know what I'm saying I
always try to keep
a I try to I mean I've been told I kind
of was arrogant at one point you know
what I'm saying once I was told that I
kind of
like really fell back you know what I'm
saying
because you know life you know what I'm
say I didn't know how to deal with just
life stuff so it just like
so I just fell back and just be like you
know just keep head down and keep being
great you know and I think um the life
lessons that had me in my imposture
because as I was I went too high and I
got I felt I start feeling myself
and so God took my hearing away meaning
my gift of knowing what taste of great
music is just because I just got you
know I feel like it's always a hedge
around me and I just think I got too
much into myself and thought I was
bigger than the music and then the music
tapped me on the shoulder like uh uh uh
like what my shirt say uh uh
uh uh uh uh and God tapped me you know
what I'm saying like and I appreciate
those moments cuz
trial and error let you know if you
really great can you get back up when
everybody throwing stones at you you
know what I'm saying
like it
just that's that's the character of who
you are do you really love it you know
what I'm saying like I really love music
I mean that's all I know you know what
I'm saying my I I pride myself on my
musical IQ but now I'm just really like
really digesting the highlights and
accepting that I am great and humbly
accepting it you know what I'm saying
like I ain't nothing to be [\h__\h] with
humbly you know what I'm saying humbly
you know and when did you feel like
people were throwing stones at you in
particular it's probably it's really the
let me explain some to man
like it really the enemy is the
enemy it's really just
me cuz I don't really be around but but
like when you hear five or five or six
people that five turn into 5,000 in your
head let just be real you know I'm
saying two turn into 2,000 one turn into
1,000 he be like only one [\h__\h] told you
you a godang tell your your homeboy your
home girl be like man everybody don't
like my music man and who is
everybody this two people said that you
go to to the other room and see if they
like it but two people you stop
that's just human nature man like some
people stronger than others and not just
like for me I had to you know it's
called it's called building character
you know what I'm saying and for me I
was
just that should hit me by surprise you
know what I'm saying when you know and I
was dealing nobody told me how to deal
with the Enemy you know what I'm saying
so that's stuff you got to learn on your
own and I'm glad I got through it but
but it's a heavy it's a heavy everybody
don't make it you know what I'm saying
cuz they'll be your in your own head and
you won't go
nowhere I don't seen it man that [\h__\h] is
real that's the that's the worst feeling
ever that's worse than any enemy is your
enemy how did you work through that
because I like we work with a lot of
different artists talk to a lot of
different artists and there's always
some type of battle whether it's
overthinking or something right some
message in their head I think people do
that in general right not just artists
yeah that's his life yeah like at what
point was there like a turning point
where you're like all right this is me
and I know I got to talk to me and it's
nobody like it's nobody
else
um I'm always like that like I try to
I'm a Loner anyway so it's like I got to
deal with it cuz it's not that that
voice is loud in your head that's why
you got people deep depression and you
know the youth today they they too much
in their head that's why that's why
mental health is so real now because
nobody a lot of people loners and then
sometimes you can't just go talk to
everybody man
because they human too they going
through stuff I tell people learn how to
get get a close relationship with God
and I'm telling you that's going to help
you through everything and I'm just
being I'm being as hon as I can be
because can't no human help you you know
it it'll pacify
you but the real relationship is when
you start getting in that word and
getting the word mean it's putting on
the word word and just letting God give
you the answers through your spirit you
know what I'm saying and you'll know and
once you notice that you'll notice like
that's what I I I tell it like it is not
to be like super religious or nothing
like that I'm just telling you like God
will set you down so you can respond to
him and a lot of times that anxiety
those those imps just go away because
you ain't going
to you know you'll ask your Mama but
even you just don't want to go to
another person because
they just they got their own
contamination you know what I'm saying
like everybody got their own they can
get and it's like you just giving them
stuff to feed to get back to you then
they going to give you their
contamination and it's like you just
getting poison you just getting you just
falling to the ground so you know what
I'm saying because get I mean it's cool
we do these therapy that's great but
it's like at the end of the day you got
to sit down and talk to go and sometimes
you're not going to get an answer and
you just got to just know but you know
you look back and be like damn when you
thought you was going to jump or do this
or go crazy you was still and you don't
realize that until you just like you
know what I didn't do that I I kind of
handle that pretty good but you just
going through it you feel like you ain't
but then you look back at it you be like
okay I just got to do this more often
and not to push people away you still
you know but you just don't make that to
go to you know what I'm saying you start
to learn how to deal with yourself
because at the end of the day I all you
got is
yourself that makes me think about again
that idea of like reinvention time and
time again
like what did you tell
yourself to see the idea of I'mma get
into
streaming to me that was like a crazy
jump oh man let me tell you something
that
was God oh Mindy boy the enemy was big
de the enemy cuz first I was like you
know I'm too old ain't nobody doing like
it was oh it was bad it was bad until I
just like like I said I started
preaching who I am and what I am and I
start accepting it I'm like no n I'm a
fighter like and I not not like who says
it's too old who says that who is
telling me this who is I'm like who is
like who what in the freak is going on
like and I just said oh I've been here
before cut on that camera start doing it
got comfortable with the
uncomfortable and not knowing that's
what I
needed for my life span to be that I
found
joy in screaming I found me at a piece
of like that I didn't know I need it so
listen to The Voice like we going to do
it and you know with my man Creator God
back there he know like we used to get
in arguments late at night the stupid
just me battling with
myself thinking that I'm too good or I'm
too this on that Hollywood [\h__\h] bro and
not
knowing I'm serving the people and
knowing that I'm serving and
helping it gave me a joy that money and
nothing could give me knowing that I'm
giving
back and you know of course yeah you you
make money on it but it's just
like it's you you know like look at Kai
Kai like yo I'm going buy a school I'm
going to do this because it's so like I
started to understand like when they say
chat chat chat right and I start like yo
this [\h__\h] got a feeling to it that's I
can't explain cuz once you like get in
that bubble of it and I just had to get
through the in initiation of like
self-doubt or I'm too old or I'm this
I'm that ain't nobody going to do this
ain't nobody and just start doing me and
to the point to where it's like
scheduled out that we got a team we got
we built the infrastructure behind it
and the real the reality of it is is
like the elevation of new tech and I
started to know like this going to be
where all the money the new stars are
made and I just started be like Oh I'm
not going to be I'm going to be the
young old [\h__\h] you know what I'm saying
like I'mma Be ahead of the curve you
know what I'm saying then I start seeing
other people like Grandpa sniper he get
he then people be watching him cuz he he
he came from the Navy he be sniping
[\h__\h] for like 400 miles and people
like oh in the chat and I feel like yo
the [\h__\h] so engaging bro I'm like yo
then I'll be on the games and I'm
watching then I start seeing pinky do I
start like y I say yo this [\h__\h] is
amazing because you it's like screaming
allows you to see unhidden talent in
people yeah it's like the new you
finding new stars for me is being a it's
opened up my my creative pool so much
that like outside of music is like but
we can do music this way oh we can do it
that way oh we can we we might can
scream it and do it oh I might go to
studio and do it like it it it it has
opened me up to a a portal in my brain
to like just endless creativity bro and
I just and it it just where I I always
wanted to to be is in technology but
technology didn't catch up until where
I'm at today you know what I'm saying
and so I can't my mind was already there
but if not available you goingon to keep
doing what you do you going keep you not
and then once you get in that that
psyche of what you do and then doing
something new and just be like it's just
like what the hell am I D like I ain't
got to do what am I do this you start
all this stuff you start telling
yourself and it's like just do it man
it's going it's going to serve you
purpose and they like you know I start
telling myself as serving me purpose and
and it damn sure do and you know and
through that and then once I start to
really enjoy it the the the the the fans
come the people come and and I track I
told myself like I I was like I attract
all the youth you know what saying
that's like to me that's is so beautiful
because I'm not I'm not the end goal but
I'm like a coach Prime to all the
creators out there it's like that's
Timbo that's blah blah blah and it's
like yeah I can get you to this point
but it really is up to you and just me
giving my feedback in my knowledge I
know I have changed so many lives and
people text me like yo you by you just
talking to me now and it's making me
think like wow my music had that much of
an impact so it's my duty to serve you
know what I'm saying it's like I guess
it's like God just open up new new pages
in my life that I didn't know I needed
but I'm destined to do like it's like
it's the walk and I'm just I'm just
right now I'm just saying hey I
Surrender let's just do it like I'm open
to all new stuff like I'm not one of
them guys who be
like man that's old or that's that no I
I'm Innovative that's that's how I got
in the game people didn't like me
putting crickets in records butet I was
yeah I put it in one in a million I use
Cricket for a high hat come on man then
I put I put Godzilla in a a genuine song
like bro like you got to think I was so
before Pokemon it was Timbo before
Dragon Ball Z was me yeah know what I'm
saying I'm the one that brought vtron
He-Man all the stuff that this coming
back today I done put in music me and
for real both like I got my stuff from
Star Wars George Lucas from watching all
the stuff that y'all love today you know
what I'm saying The Boondocks all that
stuff but we had fat
abber we had you know all these more um
Saturday morning cartoon where the music
was crazy in it there was a cartoon when
it had pepples and Bam Bam they had a
band the music that they made on they on
their cartoon I was like
yo get out of here
Scooby-Doo the music was the soundtrack
all that's what made the cartoon back
then so I saw it start elevat and I saw
see Dragon Ball Z the Tekken the video
games I say oh bro then I start seeing
all the the youth when they play games
and I'm like yo it just it just
repackage in a different way it's the
same thing that I grew up on but it's
repackaged
and so we my daughter and my son we' be
talking I'm like and I show them I said
look look at the EV evolution of this
look what it started from punch out now
look where we at B Tyson punch out like
look he said damn y'all play I said yeah
look at this and now he goes back to
Roblox in Minecraft stared from here and
they be like yo don't you see how what
we living in a Bo this whole world
assimilation right and they be like damn
that's deep dead so it be like I just
now that I can where I'm at today I can
see that it's
like I get a a preview of What's Next by
me being centered as a person you know
what I'm saying I can just feel the
energy of the world and can tell what's
next like you know what I'm saying just
like that's just the gift that I never
wanted to lose cuz it's like I can give
a young person or somebody else and say
hey you should go here just about the
pop how you I said I you ain't out in
the club I said bro I know what the I
know what the girls want to hear I know
what [\h__\h] they' be like and then when
I then they P damn he knew I was like I
told you I just know it's just I can't I
don't have to be in it it's just because
of where I'm at in life and the gift
that he G God gave me and what I know I
have done I can give to others because
I'm aine so I don't got to be in Live or
over there or but I can tell you from a
pattern of what I'm seeing in the
world okay and that's how business I
built from patterns human
behavior I could just know if I'm in
line I could tell you
what I ain't going to say I'm accurate
but I can put you on that right and then
you can take it from there because it's
it's you you I'm giving you the sauce of
where to go but you know how to elevate
it it's it's your age bracket like you
know what the freak to do like but me
put you go over here you sure trust me
bro this about to pop and then damn you
was right oh I'm I'm how you know I said
because I am music
[\h__\h] the freak you think I like that
you keep talking about like I can show
you the way but you still have to finish
it out and because it goes back to that
coach Prime analogy like literally I had
that experience where I start watching
Colorado because of Dion just you know
and what he brought but then Travis
shador made me stay cuz Dion's not on
the field I can't watch Dion exactly but
but his his knowledge makes you be like
as a as a young adult you like I don't
know what the [\h__\h] he talking about yeah
regardless you can say I know what the
freak he talking about yep
so that's all we want you know what I'm
saying and that's what God give us our
gift cuz we know what we good
at if any I can't probably tell you
about Finance or over here but when it
come to
this you'll be a fool not listen to me
you know what I'm saying like because
I'm just too tapped in I'm too and when
I mean tapped in is like and and even
everybody around me like no he tapped in
and it's like I don't have to leave the
house to be tap nobody first of all I
tell people like none of y'all [\h__\h] go
out leave out the house how about that
like I don't know where y'all party at
y'all go meet in groups how you know
that because [\h__\h] it ain't safe in
these streets [\h__\h]
you understand like how I supposed to
know cuz I just know it's a energy bro
it's a Synergy it's a line it's a line
and it's like I just know you know what
I'm saying I it's just one of them thing
I just can see it I could just
see you know I could you know you just
can see it you just be seeing I just be
seeing it yeah how did you approach the
the vulnerability side of streaming
right and what makes me ask that is I
feel like a lot of
a lot of Superstar acts so we we even
say like Superstar The Legend acts I
feel like stay away from it because the
audience is demanding so much
vulnerability but these are artists
coming from an era where like you don't
have to be vulnerable to be successful
right like there are artists that I feel
like were huge in their time that I
don't know too much about as a person
versus the average artist today for them
to sometimes even have like a tenth of
that type of fan base we already learned
so much about them you know I'm saying
getting to that point and I've seen that
turn like I said bigger artists Legends
away from that so one was that
challenging for you to be so vulnerable
to these people and kind of open up this
different side of yourself and then two
how did you approach that like how did
you get yourself comfortable with that
like I said man it's uncomfortable
comfortable you just got to do it and
once you start to do it it's like
practic and it's like it's anything man
when you go to the gym anything you
don't want to do it but once you start
doing it you get
addicted and you just start to be like
you know what I like this
cuz do you really think about it you you
ain't you just own a camera I'm still in
my house so what would I do normally in
my house that's facts you know once you
start putting it like in reality you be
like what would you normally it's the
thing I have to get comfortable with do
I want to let people in my house but not
physically be in my house but I feel my
whole chat in my house in my pres they
talk to me if I'm picking my face stop
picking your face they doing ah and I
listen to them cuz I feel like they in
my house but then after a while be like
[\h__\h] y'all in my
house I'mma pick my face sh you know
what I'm saying get the freak out of
here you in my house you want something
to eat and then they go to their
refrigerator you know but the chat feel
like they in their house they feel like
they in my house too even though they
going to another refrigerator they feel
like if they see me go to refrigerator
they feel like they feel like we doing
it the same thing you know what I'm
saying it just it's just a energy that
can't be
described that goes through that camera
screen and if people say like you know
it's it's it's it's the new way of
communication man that's the only way we
find our information is through
screamers and through people who are
bold enough to get on the camera and
make a video and say hey there are orbs
in the
sky you know what I'm saying and you
have to take that not look at for me I
won't look over my show I'm like hey man
where you at where you see that at I I
feel something I feel you know what I'm
saying it's like the the new information
is not mainstream media it is the
screamers in these apps yeah and a lot
of people are still stuck on the
old I've been saying it for the longest
time I'm telling people even
about you want to call it with AI I
don't call it that I call it I call it
in a a second
opinion yeah that's what I call it a
thought
I don't I don't I don't I don't I feel
like I have
help oh now I can double up my business
in a different way now I can be as
creative as I want to be now the oh the
vortex of my brain has been open I have
a second opinion man I'm curious man
what what Tim you chat GPT for like what
what what are the promps you working
through
man I'm I'm selling my prompts too I'm
putting them on live we got we got a
template I got like I look bro it's it's
the wildest way how I would look at it
bro like cuz it's like how would you put
a sentence and my guy creative God Z
like that's a tech like I said both of
us like Tech Gods but I feel like he's
the future of where is going as a black
man and like just knowing how to speak
our language to chat
GPT cuz I speak ebonics I speak goofy
right but with helping him he he know
how to tell me how to interpret what I'm
trying to say and then I'm like what if
we say it this way so to me it's like a
cross word puzzle it's like a game and
it's and then when they give you the
response like damn that's deep then I
take whatever chat TBT responsible okay
I like the name I said I'll call my chat
big all right B
so what's going to happen to ASCAP is
there ever going to be what's how how's
music going to be published in oh it has
to be new laws and new imp impation I
can't pronounce the word new ways of
doing things and people have to adapt
and it might give
me it's going to give me another way of
looking at it and it's like to me it's
like Ping Pong under
mind chat G just as
smart and it's making me
rethink the way I was thinking which I
always been like that to to me it's like
giv me verification of what I already
thought in lame as term I'm like well
basically saying and they said you're
absolutely
correct I'm just giving you a breakdown
if you want to be more granular on why
that happened I'm like you know what I
mess with you Vic cuz you know I a not
that I'm not this the the greatest dis
the greatest weed in the dispensary
store you understand like you know like
my brain is not that you know so I need
to break this stuff down and got you Tim
I love it I can't wait till like it
walking here and I'm like can you open
the door for me yes I'm cool with it cuz
I know like everybody be afraid and
stuff to me this is what I've been
waiting for yes this is what I've been
waiting for since I was a kid so to me I
am going to run a monck and if you don't
run with me you gonna be looking down
the street sitting at the god Dam water
like damn oh to us and don't let the old
man just beat you to the punch I'm
trying to get everybody run here get on
this technology the same way y'all
[\h__\h] got on autotune but everybody
tried to hate on it but now you can't
live without
it Bingo all right so better take my
advice and know that coming from me a
Jedi I'm not no regular
degler I'm Timbo the damn King so if the
king and remember I never followed
nobody I go against the
grain and my when I do that it has been
it worked out pretty well for me right
so it's like if I'm telling you this is
the way because I feel like my
creativity just only that much of what
the world can offer with this with these
tools and
technology so I'm always ahead of the
time and embrace everything and I think
people that are creative should embrace
it too everything that's available to
you because now the sky is just a big
ass view there no
limits what was your
transition like we bring it together
like the transition from being
paid 100 plus bands 500 plus bands for
Beats to to what you you know I mean I
don't know what people get paid these
days I know no it's it's yeah we got the
we got inflation is real on us boy we
got deal it got devalued very bad like
um we was the start of you know of
everything you know we we created
like the music was looked at as a
car now the music look that as like
cookies or something or something this
it's like G gas or something like you
know damn it's $5 for gas but you go pay
$200,000 for that car act like that
ain't nothing but you tripping about $5
putting in the
car so that's how that's how beat so I
think you know but hey man you know when
world it's it's it's it's it's you know
in life certain businesses take
a don't it changes some going to devalue
you know what I'm saying and some will
still be you know high and ranking like
department stores a lot of them
Clos I'm sure that they like man this
online stuff and but then it's got to
you just got to Pivot in a different way
and find to how
to make a lucrative business on what has
devalued in the world and like you know
people like going to Studios and going
to session has got costly you know what
I'm saying so it's like you can do the
stuff on your on a laptop and like just
be smart business right you know what
I'm saying like I don't like the fact of
sending Beats and you know what I'm
saying but I think for certain artists
the best work is made
together but I know
that when an artist has a lot of
followers that's more of the bread then
actually you know the music is a great
big part but it's still advertisement
secondary it's not it's not the it's not
in the front how it used to be it's in
the back so a artist not going to
give to they're gonna say send me
something versus getting in the room and
getting in the room is more like I think
in today's world like okay I got to make
that I gotta I want to make that novel
that's going to set my next four years
off if I go in this one time with this
producer rebuild
this for you I wouldn't have to you know
especially if a person got 100 million
followers like it's strategy with it you
know what I'm saying today so it's not
like before we was coming it's like we
were starting that's how we had we
didn't
have this the emails the send the
Dropbox but I I I got a feeling I'm glad
that we didn't grow up in that area
where you had to go get in the room I
think that's still the best product to
be made when the producer and the artist
are in the room but now we have other
metrics to go by that determines how
great you are and that's a number
metrics a following metric a this how
much advertising dollars how much this
how much that so the music is just like
oh let's get a song oh it's hit it's a
hit oh okay and you know that they they
spend the money on it so it's like it's
all a business you know what I'm saying
which I tell you know creators and
producers okay we know that it's little
devalued but here's where the pivot come
in how do you make value to what you
already are I think Metro does a great
job I think a lot of producers doing a
great job job you just got to do
more it's unfortunately but it it's I
don't know if it's going I be I fight
and I still fight the good fight and
I'mma always say that getting in the
room is the best way you know I think
right now the independent game is so
heavy that it's going back to that
producers are linking up with new
artists and you know what I'm saying and
they building they following which I
love you know I and it's you see some
people going up the hill 200 oh that
person like you know saw four bats go to
from 5,000 to 700,000 you know then but
now you got once you hit this like okay
now you got to break that door to go hit
3 million 4 million like how 21 Savage
like everybody and right now we at that
new fresh journey of
building so this is where producers and
the artist can create a sound I try to
work with artists who understand that
you know either they self-contain they
do everything they
self um they produce you know or they
have their
producer with them cuz they have a sound
like VA has her producer NZ s has her
producer you know it it it it it I
think that's that's when you start
hearing great music you know what I'm
saying like people linking up I feel
like this is the this is the era for
producers to link up and artist know
that that's your vehicle to that's your
car you got the you got the new
prototype Ferrari but it ain't ready to
go drive all the way yet but you got the
new shape that what's coming in the
future you know I'm saying so it's like
stick with that don't change up don't go
stick with your stick with your your
team and as you grow and get big don't
let nobody break that and I think we're
going to see more producers and artist
collab but it's starting from this and I
want to be I'm at the HM of it cuz all
my albums I'm going to put out going
forward in 20 25 is going to be with new
people that I'm watching up because
people just like
feeling you know it's up to the artist
if they trying to be an artist for you
to go sell your product but for
me I'm selling great music I'mma point
you to what's who you should watch out
for CU a lot of people when I play my
playlist on my
screen it's all new artists they be like
yeah this playlist is fire yeah people
you ain't never heard of but I just know
how to curate great I'm a great curate
like I I'm I'm a taste maker first
that's what makes me good at music
because I'm a tast maker so if I put
something I'mma I can curate a playlist
for your ass even to the point like my
daughter she she'll be like oh okay and
we be sending stuff I say yeah I'll put
this with this with my Indie pop I'll do
BL blah blah blah mix it up and it's
like people be like H that boy Tight cuz
it's like I just know good music I know
what people and and people don't listen
to albums no more listen to a playlist I
know
nobody listen no damnum l to a playlist
and you're just cool with whatever goes
right you're not like hold hell to like
man I wish we could do albums again you
just want to go I feel like I feel like
we going to have great albums coming out
but they're not going to be you GNA have
to go search it's going to be somebody
that knew yo that album tight you know
think about when you first heard uh
James
Blake you know what I'm saying like you
know what I'm saying is underground it's
a it's a it's it becomes organic I think
we going to go back to
great feeling of great music again but
it's it's it's going to be from the
Internet it's going to be you know your
feed the list you know that's how I see
it like damn who is this what's this and
background music now that we hear on
post it's like we going to find that new
that new [\h__\h] like think about it
like I think one of the biggest
songs um right now is the uh
um
damn it's a what people be trying to
give they
um they testimony speech and that guitar
play in the background like like K use
it somebody else will use it somebody
created that song that's song the
biggest song is on everybody's
platform you know what I'm saying so
when you hear that song with a song Oh
that song oh what's that other song
chase me when I FL got s that's on
everybody sentiment page you play that
song right
now in the stadium going crazy but you
don't know who that artist is no I don't
yeah but you know that
song so it's about the feeling man the
feeling is out there now it's up to the
artist they got to work it to say yo I
did
this and then people start to follow
their story you know what I'm saying
it's still work people got to work bro
ain't no more laziness right now people
got to put the work in and it's it's I
think it's I think it's a righteous time
for the music business you know what I'm
saying especially with independency you
know what I'm saying everything that's
going on is it's like you got to you got
to destroy to rebuild and I feel right
now the industry is going into this
destroy everybody got a voice everybody
speaking how what they don't like what
they we're
going and then we watching new new
fertilizer come up and new grass being
grown that's the new artist you know
what I'm saying and I think that's
that's just where it's going by 2026
that thing going to be booming just how
like Bitcoin you every like I don't know
about Bitcoin now
look we we said it was going to be
100,000 or two years ago me and my man
we like
we I said man bull y'all gotta
understand this is Tech this is this is
this season is is all
about I hate to see use this word but
it's all about the Nerds
it's all about them they are the God
dang winners they going to be the ones
and you got to be both you gotta be the
you got to be cool at the nerd cuz the
Nerds is going to run this
[\h__\h] for sure because everything is a
push of a button cyber attacks going to
be going CRA bro you about to see some
[\h__\h] and you going to be like damn then
you going to start seeing other people
build a tech team I'm telling you now
start now cuz if you don't you're going
to be late to the party it's GNA be some
genius kid you gonna be like God Dam we
looking at Mark Zuckerberg bro he's 30
something years old and he's a bill he's
probably be a trillionaire by
40 you understand so the next one is
going to be like 18 years old because of
tech y they talk about now all the time
um because of AI exactly there's
probably going to be a onep person
billion dollar company coming soon
that's crazy to think about yeah
to do yes
yes like on my show
yes yes but all of this kind of alludes
towards the the different era wherein
like like artists got to work harder
this is the respon this is the
responsibility of having the freedom
right you don't get the freedom without
having to work hard and I think people
didn't plan for that part and now we
have this ability to go direct to Fan
there's so many benefits of it I know
you're a fan of it as well like kind of
share your thoughts on just direct the
fan this whole climate that we're in
right now I feel like you know
everything requires work but it's great
work you know you building an audience
man like like if if if Kai Ray Duke
Dennis and them boys ain't showing y'all
how to be direct to people y y'all
should take that as a playbook in
music take all the screaming people as a
Playbook like if they put bro okay I be
drewy oh bro it's like direct to consuma
fans it's like bro you you have to get
out there I think it's the best thing
because now you can go set up shows you
can go do things that you you just don't
know look at
Ye Ye is killing it like but it ain't
mainstream but it's a you could put I
think Independence you can start
building your [\h__\h] build your platform
build build your business as you be an
artist like don't don't wait for to go
always go get a deal be the
deal what's that mean you are you are a
deal you got to structure yourself oh I
want this okay well I need to go get
this go to a bank versus go to a label
you can go get a loan and build your
[\h__\h] out you are you are like oh I want
to try to get a deal no [\h__\h] I you know
I don't going got to try I am the deal
like I am people I am the real deal
people need to see me you know and build
your system I just think people just
don't want to put in the work of
building like um putting the work in and
really understand what a directly
consumer really is and it really is
really like building like a tech team
behind your [\h__\h] and and and and owning
the IP of what you built whether if it's
5,000 people 6,000 people 6,000 people
can make you too million dollar
depending on your price point or how you
see what are you offering to the fans
you could be as creative as you want
want to be you know I know it's going to
take some money but you can go borrow
whatever you make or you can just get it
from the mud and start doing it take
every little piece put it back into the
product and don't and then as you want
to expand you know you can either go a
label route or you can go a bank route
or you can go a hedge fund or an
investor you know what I'm saying
because you have value you have a
catalog you building up that you can
sell now you own the Masters those
Masters get licensed out to all these
movies you got all these songs look at
Russ I mean just it just it just you
know it's more work you know what I'm
saying you just got to be you know it's
like anything you got to be
reasonable
and and put the work
in everything is obtainable you just got
to put the work in but I think directly
consumer is the way to go I think we're
going to have to have a lot more
creativity in general in terms of how
people offer to their fan bases because
everybody thinking about streaming all
right what's next oh I could do some
shows and sell some kind of merch but
it's like those three defined boxes are
limiting people in terms of how you can
interact with your fans and what you can
exchange other than a t-shirt you know
what I mean other than doing a full
traditional tour but there's so many
different ways cuz you're just a
business just be a creative at that
point exactly you could do you could do
shows in fortnite they already showed
you that yeah you do shows live
streaming from your house you do so many
way we in the world of technology we
don't know what people going to like
there's a girl it's a hologram right now
in I'm telling y'all I'm like yo bro
virtual artist is going I'm telling you
it's already existed you know what I'm
saying like I'm telling you she sells
out
shows like I'm like yo y'all not seeing
what you're not seeing technology evolve
you can be everything you can you can
you know you can be in Virtual we just
got to get we just got to I think people
got to wrap their minds on what's coming
and just be and just started to open up
to it you know what I'm saying and I
think that I ain't got time to wait I
just got to go you know what I'm saying
and you know people catch up there'll be
the youth to catch up and be like that's
cool think about
it people buy skins bro yeah and spend
millions of dollars digital art I think
that's going to be the Way digital stuff
it's going to be those pieces that those
tangible pieces
but you know digital access is going to
be the wave and artist going to like
start doing like shoe collab but digital
[\h__\h] like that and it's goingon to be
sold on and put in my fortnite game or
put on my character you know what I'm
saying like the Travis shoes say that
digital you want to put it on your how
you yo that's $50 or $20 yeah maybe it
ain't two 2,000 for the for the but
that's $50 people really go crazy over
skins that's a whole another untapped
Market that like people just don't don't
think about and I like it's so many
Avenues that's going to be open that
artist going to have to think about
those things not put it as a back burner
to be like man that [\h__\h] man and you
know you have to open up your mind to
other thing besides like you say shows
merge what the normal physical stuff
what about the digital stuff we could do
behind the scenes what this what it is
what we can go here how do we go
broadcast everywhere without going
everywhere Y how do I be in China how do
I go this who do I go you know you might
go to China to go talk to a team over
there to to to see your vision that you
got so you can be home but you don't got
to be in but then when you go to China
now you doing now you doubling your
price because now you physically
there yeah you know what I'm saying like
so you just got to just rethink things
different especially with our ability to
connect with people from far away yes
like just that I even the way that I've
come up with their music I was working
with artists in Japan before I was
working with artists in Atlanta you know
what I mean see and that was just what
came to me that was what connected and I
feel like more artists just need to be
more open with what connects to them
because we work personally like when we
talk to certain artists it's like all
right but if I'm not in the US or if I'm
not in my specific city where it's just
like all right if they're already coming
towards me there was a time where I
guess I can see it's like it's so hard
to get there then it makes sense to not
try to connect with those and try to
figure out how you can make it closer
cuz it's it's Capital intensive to go to
Paris but now you got people who love
you in Paris or whatever I mean like you
said there's so many digital ways figure
it out and focus on them period think
about it why you think you do email
blast and that stuff actually works so
think of tell them what I'm saying it
actually works it works but it's like
think about it for your product yeah
yeah you got to think like a real brand
like a depart but gay guys he's going on
I tell him all like we got to Yo treat
this [\h__\h] like it's everything like a
like it's
pelaton what would they do what can we
do to do the same thing they doing in
our world oh maybe we do a running you
know send a blast out that data goingon
to mean something why you think
everybody is so scared about their phone
cuz what they won't why we getting rid
of Charlie Tik Tok cuz of the data
yeah and once people understand that and
like man you could create so much BS and
start and it's like it start off 100 not
2,000 the numbers are different from
having to physically go touch and seeing
it like that's why you got to start now
that's such a like breath of fresh out
to hear you say cuz I feel like modern
artists don't get the context of it
because they're they're living in it
right all they know is this time where I
got to do all this work I got nine
things I got to do to be an artist and
we always said I always feel like
artists just from other Generations like
this is kind of what y'all were asking
for like I've heard artists and
interviews say you I wish I had more
direct access to my fan base I wish
there was a way I could touch the people
without having to go through a label or
a major distributor and it's like y'all
wishes turned
into what's the word I'm looking for it
turned into like a um reality or
burgering there we go burgering for like
the new artist but I think it's out of
like context so I mean for those artists
who are thinking that well I know the
the the obvious answer is like yo just
do it like you you living in a good time
but you know when you're dealing with
artists in your work life who you see
have the mentality what are you doing to
just push them towards the now like do
you just let them do what they do I just
be I be a vessel I try to be you know
cuz I'm I'm I'm I'm I'm seeing the
opportunities I'm learning to but see
I'm at a place where like it's available
so it's like I'm a I'm like a kid again
so for them it's like damn so I got to
understand both perspectives so I just
try to be what what they need is
motivation
the new artist just need motivation
because it is it I mean me doing it
myself it is a lot of work so I'm like
well damn it is a lot of work
um it ain't you know ain't turn on the
switch and you just sit down and watch
it you know what I'm saying and I just
and I just chalk it up and say damn I
rather work this way harder than because
it's easier I ain't got to go lifts I
ain't got to go do this I Ain't Got You
know I ain't got to travel I just got to
just have schedule I got to have my life
scheduled out at this hour I got to do
this at these things I got to set this
up for post
I need this team for this I need that
for that just keep it going every day
the same thing you would keep if you had
if you was running
Apple there ain't no difference you just
keeping your just keeping that [\h__\h] just
running once you get it the thing is
just figuring it
out I I would love your perspective on
this what do you feel like what do you
feel like was the hardest era of Music
in terms of the work on the artist and
the
producer I don't think it's no I think
all erors are hard it just what you
consider to be
hard Paul you
know I'm saying like yeah I don't
know
damn
yeah but you know
that what about on business on the
business um side like obviously you're
streaming and you're you're touching on
a lot of things you said but just from
at your point and your career you have
these new things that you might be
looking into that are more Innovative
and Tech Edge for business but are there
any traditional things you as an artist
like are you like looking to I don't
know maximize your catalog somewhere or
are you looking at things outside of
Music in general like just from a
businessman standpoint oh everything is
Tech everything I look at is tech tech
tech driven and for its catalog is using
the tech to to
build multi catalog start over again
just rebuilding it all over again
because now screaming ain't the era
where you need one if you get that one
that's a bonus you just need to put out
good music at all times you can't get
stuck on oh is a hit is it that is that
I don't had that error but I didn't have
this error I did a hit on
everybody it's not a person I done a hit
on so like the new thing is if I get a
hit today on a new artist that's that's
a blessing but I think a hit is a
different way a hit could be gaining
2,000 fans when you didn't you only had
one yesterday that's a
hit you know what I'm saying now we got
to make another hit we got to get
20,000 we got to get 30,000 think hits
are different nowadays you know what I'm
saying for me and
um I embrace it you know what I'm saying
I just had to rethink rethink it like I
can put out a lot and that that that lot
can be curated and be distributed
through the
world long after I'm I'm gone you know
what I'm saying that's how I look at it
it's like it's a new way of looking at I
can't look like oh this going to be
massive at radio or this you know what
I'm saying that's for the subina of
Carpenters unless I got an artist that's
in that you know those are Sabrina to
tell us with that's that's that's that
but then I'm looking for
like yo when you look
at a Timlin new playlist you like yo
these all new records like now you
listen to playlist in a different way
it's like it's being digested different
like I want to be a curator and then
like y I want to buy then a publ my
publishing will be like yo we want to
buy that curation that whole playlist
that's got like 100 songs in there
another 100 song and then out of that
100 maybe 10 of them like were big
screaming hits but the rest made but
then when you add it all up it's
probably worth 40 million 50 million so
to me I just
I just did it in a different way but in
this generation you know what I'm saying
so for me I embrace it all I think it's
I don't have no problem man I don't got
knocked down so many times in my life it
ain't no problem I don't be getting back
up so many times so
it's I don't like to do it you know what
I'm saying but hey sometimes you need it
keeps you healthy you know what I'm
saying keeps you active keeps your brain
going I want to close with a game of
sorts I call it a superpower game
because
somebody who studied the game really has
Insight on the musicality of people I
would love your personal insight and how
you see other people's superpowers so
you mentioned Miss Elli let's start with
her what's Miss 's
superpower
tenacity
fight she taught me how to fight and not
to
accept you know what I'm saying
like it helps the battle with
me from my mind and knowing that she's a
woman and this her and her mother you
know what I'm saying and Missy is my
hero you know what I'm saying she she
she is David you know what I'm saying in
a female version you know what I'm
saying and her Goliath was people
telling her she can't do it she don't
look this way this ain't that Missy
never saw none of
that none of
that which birth lizo
she made a lot of women
stronger you know I watch
women credit Missy for giving them the
courage to go forward in their dreams
and vision no matter what you know what
I'm saying that's that's everybody don't
have
fight you can learn fight you can get it
but you got to know you got to the first
the the first measure to that is
get pushed down all right you get back
up and fight what you gonna
do you gonna go home and cry then you
get up and fight then you now you have
fight now you got to keep
fighting what about for
real ah I call for
real for real to me is
like um he's a
Archangel he's like a disciple he's uh
he's a Visionary who which y'all see for
real day for a style he's been that way
for real always
been he's he's okay if if if I'm Obi-Wan
Kenova for real is
Yoda he's Beyond
me he has Insight that I go to him for
advice forell and Missy are like my two
like brother brother and sisters from
Virginia um I always wanted to stay
connected to them because they had
different for real for real superpowers
that was the question his superpower
would
be
knowledge
viewpoints on how to take your emotions
and put
it in line so you won't react off
emotions he has the gift of of
calm walk down this
path and your light will shine like for
real is a is a is a true beam of light
him and Missy but he's a true beam of
light um I can say for real has
something that I don't I never had in my
career and that's 100% of a
song Happy is 100% for real the biggest
song in the
world and I think that's like you don't
hear
that
100% yeah I not think about it like that
exactly that's what for real
is a shooting
sty what about somebody like Swiss
beats Swiss Swiss set me
Swiss set me down like made me had to I
he set me down I had to go sit down and
reevaluate
myself when he came
[Music]
out he said don't get it twisted [\h__\h]
I'm a disruptor too so what I say about
Swiss the best two fighters was who was
it what who was it Muhammad Ali who who
was it back yeah well it's like he he
one of them he's he he he he a Jedi too
like what I would say about Swiss Swiss
is Swiss has something too Swiss has his
fight he has fight too I put him in the
fight he
has all of these people have originality
so I'm not going I'm going say but you
said superpowers I said
fight fight tenacity too
all right two more
Kanye Kanye like
Zeus Kanye somewhere else he like you
know see oh uh what was that I like to
put stories to movies what was the
venard where the [\h__\h] went up to the up
to the space and he had to go visit go
see the other dude sit on the rim what
movie was that was it Green Lantern it
was some one of them movies that's
probably Green Lantern yeah probably
green l
the whole league he had to answer to
those folks for real I mean Kanye Kanye
like his
superpower is
360 he see everything before it
happens
Vision thr interesting one in there Mike
[Music]
Dean
frequency Mike de frequency God
he know how to penetrate the soul
through
sense not knowing that like he know how
to trick the numbers with it's 432 he
can add 432 to which is not I don't know
if that's a frequency because it's
always 432 Herz and you got 111 Herz but
I never Hur
43022 so he know how to take calm and
give you coma
you know what I'm saying so that sound
like the coolest [\h__\h] ever right there
yeah like when you was calm now you com
he got put you to sleep boy he got that
he got that you hear it on Travis Scott
boy you know what I'm saying you put you
put loud and C like you get a combustion
you know it's like
boom like you know say
like [\h__\h] just it just mess up the mind
we get greedy do one more we got to say
timberling I don't know what the freak I
got like a mut I'm a mixture of
everything like
a I say my superp power I'm Doctor
Strange I
no people how the freak you do that
like I just took what you did and what
you said and put the world man why can I
think that's why I'm
timberling you are the Hulk Captain
America and you are this I'm Dr
Strange I love it I love it appreciate
you man yeah this was cool I can talk
music all day all right so what we going
to do next you got to you got to play
something
[Music]