There was a time when music came with
rules. You couldn't sound like anybody.
You couldn't dare look like anybody
else. And fans knew exactly who they
were supporting. And I don't think those
rules disappeared. I think they were
replaced. And the artists who understand
the new rules, they're not just making
songs. They're actually creating worlds.
Now, like I said at the top of the
video, there was actually a time when
sounding like somebody else actually
came with consequences. And you might be
thinking, consequences from who? And it
wasn't from the industry, but from the
culture and the players in the game
itself.
>> Like not that long ago, you'd get
clowned and really talk bad about if
your song sounded remotely like anybody
else's song.
>> But now if your don't sound exactly like
whoever had the last hit, then you're
not doing a good job. It's the weirdest
thing in the world and I don't
understand it. Remember that. Remember
that when you got when you got called a
biter? If you even like even if you said
a line from from anything that sound
close to another song or if your beat
sounded the same as anything else or if
your hook sounded kind of like anything
else, you got called a biter. Oh, you
biting. You biting. You a biter. That
was like it was a like real it was a sin
to even remotely sound like anybody
else. And now that's all you can do. So
there are people who feel like music
culture has stopped enforcing
originality. And because of that,
artists stopped being identities and
started really becoming variants of each
other. And once that happens, everything
starts to blur. And I think the blur is
what people are reacting to when they
say that music feels boring right now.
They're not talking about the sound.
They're talking about how you guys are
making them feel.
>> It's not exciting.
>> The the rappers are not exciting. The
singers are not exciting. There's no new
photographers. There's no new companies
coming up. like who's who's making
something new and fresh.
>> I think there's a lot of new and fresh
[\h__\h] happening. It's just not [\h__\h] that
we going to like. You know what I'm
saying? Like there's a lot of new
artists coming out of this that the
other doing it off like crazy small
[\h__\h] but it's not [\h__\h] we would listen
to and we need new different stuff right
>> now. Nothing inspires me is a pretty
harsh review, but I also think it's a
signal that fans are feeling like they
don't have anything to belong to. And
that emptiness, right, the emptiness
that the fans are feeling, that doesn't
just stay abstract. And eventually that
feeling starts to show up in places
where we expect fan loyalty to be at its
peak.
>> Earlier I saw this video about the
concert experience. I would stitch it
but I lost it. And this guy was
explaining in this interview just how
shitty concerts are now. And I
completely agree or how much I love the
live concert experience. Like I got to
admit the entire like vibe of it has
changed. Especially like the big massive
concerts and festivals. First off these
things are getting so [\h__\h] expensive
it's not even worth it at this point.
Then on top of that, they always add
these [\h__\h] fees. Like Ticket Master,
for example, they always add on all
these fees that you know for a fact do
not exist because they're an electronic
ticket. They're just ones and zeros. If
you're going to a rap show, don't expect
the axe to ever be on time. And not only
will they not be on time, but they will
be extremely late. A lot of bands also
don't like to have cell phones for their
sets, which I can kind of understand,
especially if it's in the dark, which
you could argue could ruin the
experience for some people. But hey, we
live in the 21st century. I mean,
there's going to be cell phones. What
are you going to do? And there's some
acts that literally do not rap during
their performances. Being able to
perform while singing and or rapping was
literally considered a skill and I
believe if you look at acts 20 30 years
ago is a completely different science as
it is.
>> Now I think we can all pretty much agree
that concerts are the top of the
mountain peak for a fan experience. So
when concerts start to feel hollow
especially the people that like to go to
them I think that one that should be a
signal to the artist and two it's a sign
that the relationship is weak long
before anybody hits the stage. And I
also think that's when artists start to
ask the wrong questions. Instead of
asking, "How do I deepen my relationship
with fans?" Most artists will ask, "How
do I perform better?" or "How do I get
more people to the show?" But world
building doesn't start with you becoming
a better performer. It actually starts
with you figuring out yourself.
>> Oliver Tree, the character, the persona.
Can you describe what that character was
like?
>> It was myself and authentic to me, but
turned up to I want to say an 11, but
it's probably more like a 22 or
something like that. The haircut was the
haircut I had my whole life. I was too
scared to get any other haircut. The
jacket was something I stole from my mom
and my mom and my dad would wear it in
the 80s. The pants were the pants I
always wanted. The glasses were like the
little glasses I would wear as a kid
that made me feel cool. So, it was kind
of taking the most ridiculous versions
of myself and kind of just like putting
it into one place.
>> Now, if you watch my artist archetype
breakdown video, then you will know that
I personally break artists into three
categories when they're building out
their artist personas. Your purists,
your characters, and your hybrids. And I
think that whether you decide to create
an artist persona or really try to
figure out how to be yourself, one thing
is very clear. You have to commit to it
because that commitment is what gives
fans something to recognize. And once
the recognition exists, context starts
to change what things are worth.
>> I paid $1,000 for a backyard concert and
it was the best show of my life. I flew
all the way to Vallejo, California for
this. Uh included in the ticket cost is
a lifetime access to all future shows.
The line was wrapped down the street.
This is for the rapper Lar Russo. And
the coolest thing is this is his house,
his mother's house that he grew up in.
In the backyard, they built this awesome
setup, stage, bleachers, the whole nine.
Even the neighbors had a good view. And
then he began the show. [music]
[singing]
>> He invited me up on stage and I let him
know how much his music inspired my art.
Then he had a violinist perform. Then
the artist broke down in tears cuz
[music] he was blown away by the
support. It was beautiful to see so many
brothers vulnerable. Outside the
concert, he had free food that came with
the ticket. And then at night time, he
had a banquet dinner of all the people
who bought the thousand ticket. And this
was also included with the ticket cost.
Uh they had shrimp, lobster, steak. They
even had a vegan option. I don't know
anyone offering this much value for
a,000 bucks. Shout out to La Russell.
I'd do it again.
>> So here's a fan who loves this artist so
much that he's willing to pay to step
inside of a universe that already meant
something to them. And all the artists
had to do was start the steps to
building that world. And I also think
that when a world exists, value stops
being confusing for both the fan and the
artist. And that's why for a lot of
fans, some things last long after a roll
out is over.
>> What's the longest amount of time that
you've owned a pair of socks? I've owned
these Talented Creator, these Odd Future
donut socks for 12 years. Can you beat
that? And they still in decent [music]
condition. Now, I'm willing to bet that
that object didn't survive because it
was just basic merch. For that fan, it
was proof of belonging to something. And
that distinction actually matters way
more than most artists realize. And I
think that since the dawn of time,
right, since the dawn of artistry,
artists have always tried to get off,
you know, the t-shirt, hat, hoodie
combo, a lot of really basic kind of
merch stuff. And there's a place for
that within your ecosystem. And for a
lot of fans, products only work when
they make sense inside of a story.
>> Oh my god. Taste like a three and 93.
>> Going on, man.
>> I ain't going to lie to you.
>> Taste taste.
>> Welcome to the future.
>> Hey, Skate.
>> This is not promo. This ain't none of
that, man. Hey, what this [\h__\h] with us?
>> And we got the new flavor that just
dropped hitting the streets. Trisha
Canada. For all our Trish lover.
>> Oh my god.
>> If you love Trish, drink this. And you
don't got to get high and still handle
your business. Quuego is the FGO. You
know what I'm talking about. You want
that good flavor, you need to get on
that quo.
>> That's why [\h__\h] be on that oil.
>> Yeah. That's why they be on that oil.
This hole look good.
>> But now you can enjoy the taste. Imagine
you can enjoy the taste of Hennessy. But
you don't got to wake up with a hangover
and have a drunk accident. That's what
we did for you, man. You can drink this
on the way to the gym, on the way to the
job, on the way to the church. You can
share with your family and
>> now feel however you feel about the
product. I think that this is actually
one of the best examples of an artist
creating a product that makes sense to
the world they've been building. Because
if you listen to the rapper Sauce Walker
and a lot of his music, yeah, it's about
rappers like him and people in Houston
in general have gone through and are
going through because of lean culture in
Houston. So when a rapper who not only
has experienced that and been through
that themselves finds a way to talk
about that in the music and then create
a product that represents that, I think
that that's the golden jackpot of artist
products because when something belongs
to the world, fans don't really need
convincing. they already understand the
context. And that's when your fan
culture needs less instructions. And
speaking of fan culture, there is a
moment within world building where a
world stops being about just the
aesthetic of it and the products within
it. And actually starts being a language
or a way that your fans speak to each
other.
>> My apps.
>> So that's a fan explaining how to say
everyday things in Cardanese, which for
those of you who don't know is Playboy
Card's fan-based language. And as funny
as that joke is, we got to admit, bro
seems pretty fluent. And that represents
something beautiful, right? Because when
fans can start to translate and explain
the world to each other, then the artist
doesn't really have to explain much
anymore. At that point, the fan culture
starts to carry itself. And once the
vibe of the world is felt by your fans
and the language starts to spread,
figuring out how to identify with you
visibly becomes way easier.
>> Cardi is still the best dressed, he
likes to mix it up. I don't care what
y'all got to say about that thong. That
thong was fire. Shut up. What inspired
your fifth?
>> Today I am dressed as King Vamp. I'm a
cosplayer type, so I figured I'mma
cosplay as the better K Playboy Cardi.
You feel me? So, got the crown on. I got
the cloak with me. I got the fur. I got
the trip pants. You know, we got it all
today. We got it all.
>> Who's the best dress, Cardi, Ken or
Lone?
>> As of this very moment, Cardi is still
the best dress. He likes to mix it up. I
don't care what y'all got to say about
that thong. That thong was fire. Shut
the up. But Loan is low-key catching up.
He has a lot more diversity in his
style. You know what I mean? I like
Cardi for what he does, but Loan's
getting there. Loan's getting there.
Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, as wild as that clip is, we can
clearly see the point, right? Fans in
Playboy Card's world don't really need
explanations. As a matter of fact, they
could be in a room with 10 million
people in it and see each other and
recognize each other instantly. At that
point, I don't think it's fair to call
that fandom. I think we got to call it
what it is, a tribe. And I get it right.
Like, a lot of these things are
definitely way easier said than done.
And I don't necessarily expect every
artist at every stage to be able to go
put together the best versions of each
of these different categories. But if
you break world building down into these
really simple categories that you need
to focus on, right, the aesthetic and
the look of the world, the unique
experiences that come with the world,
the unique person that comes with the
world, and also the things and objects I
can get if I take part in this thing,
then that effort definitely compounds
over the career of most artists. And if
you can figure out how to bring all
those things together in a way that
really does uniquely represent you and
your music and you know the type of
people you want to attract, then you
unlock the final stage of world
building, which is when consumption
turns into protection. Now turn it over
to Council Member McKe Rodriguez for a
point of personal privilege.
>> Thank you, Mayor. And I actually have a
few. Um, today's going to be a very
challenging day, but I'm going to start
off on a on a positive note. I want to
wish a very very happy birthday to a
very very special woman. She is an
advocate for higher education, a
philanthropist, a mogul, a poet, um, and
a mother. She actually has many, many
children, sons particularly. Uh, she
once said, "Spur of the moment, I ball
like Genobi and you can get deed up on."
Celebrating our beloved San Antonio
Spurs, while inviting the opposition to
collect their L's in piece. Happy
birthday to the queen of rap, Nicki
Minaj. I can't wait to get a copy of her
new album, Pink Friday, too. Now, on
this channel, I've played lots of clips
of fans who are willing to crash out
about their favorite artists or even put
themselves in embarrassing or
uncomfortable situations. And I'm
telling you guys now, no roll out can
create that and no budget can buy that.
That only happens when the fans start to
feel like the world is a part of who
they are. Now, I think the reality is
that all artists don't lose fans because
their music isn't good. For a lot of
music fans, once they finish that song
or they finish that music video, there's
nothing for them to connect to. No tribe
to join, no share a group of people to
talk and enjoy this culture with. A lot
of you artists are just letting your
fans finish the song and then walk into
the world emotionally available to
connect with something else. But you got
to realize when it comes to fans, songs
get streamed, worlds get protected and
invested in. And artists who understand
that don't just release music, they
build universes and entire worlds. And
if you need help building out your world
as an artist, we actually offer that as
a service. We help you figure out the
aesthetic, the vibe, and the mood of it,
and then how to translate that into
content and things that you can activate
as an artist. So, if that's something
that you're interested in, link is in
the description below. Hopefully, I'll
see you guys on the other side. But, I
want to know how you guys feel about the
overall artist worldbuing process. Which
of it is the most difficult for you. Is
it building the persona? Is it figuring
out how to do unique experiences? Is it
figuring out unique products? Or is it
really just bringing it all together?
Let me know your thoughts in the
comments section below. Other than that,
if you like this video, make sure you
hit that like button, subscribe, share
this with an artist that needs a little
bit of gain today.