what's up everybody once again is brand
man shot on a Friday and obviously I'll
have my normal back around and whatnot
not in that normal location so I still
want to do a video Friday means it's
music strategy resource tool today we
talking about a strategy so let's hop
right into it because I did this topic
on an email newsletter and a lot of
people they thought it was helpful when
I say you know what eventually I'll do a
video on it today is that day I already
came so project release strategy that's
what we're talking about a lot of people
have had trouble where they say I don't
want to drop my music and nobody
listened to it that's one problem but
then a lot of people have even more
reservations when it comes to dropping a
project and nobody listening to it and
not only the other problem is like you
have nobody listening to it then you
have the option of if I drop all this
music that's taken me this long and now
next thing you know I don't have any
other music you drop all I can do is
just promo and you have this pressure if
nobody listens to it and I don't have
any music to drop then it's gonna be
another three four months before I can
drop some music and get it it's a real
problem so what you can do is combine
the two methods because a lot of people
say I'm just never gonna drop a project
until I have you know a lot of fans and
the other option is this let's just
pretend you have a 5 song EP project and
you've been dropping one song a week
well you can drop each song a week right
five weeks consistently or it could be
every two weeks it could be every month
whatever you want to say but let's just
say five weeks I drop one song each week
at the end of that five week process
what you can do is then package it as a
project so as you release let those
album covers be consistent the song
covers be consistent so then it starts
to look cohesive in hindsight people who
who are experienced in real time
especially if you have a few fans
they'll be like oh this is dope if
they're just hearing singles but then as
they start to see that consistency in
the visual they'll probably start to
realize okay is this a part of something
bigger was going on and then the people
who aren't necessarily fans and they're
just listening they'll still just
experience getting fed can
only as singles they might not look deep
into it but then the biggest biggest
benefit is anybody who comes in in
hindsight who comes in after everything
it's already done
they just see a project so you have your
singles but then they get a project as
an experience but without all the hype
and all the pressure of saying oh
somebody has to listen to this album
this is a project I put all this extra
effort in it so I got to create a huge
media run and all that stuff it takes
some of that away and that's the only
way I would honestly do it at the time
when it comes to just being an
up-and-coming artist I mean I would drop
it one time also but my other option
would be doing that I wouldn't even
worry about doing the biggest media
Marina or biggest marketing I'm running
the world for an up-and-coming artist I
would do it that way take a lot of the
pressure off but you still get the
content you still get a packaging and
you keep your consistent ego kissing
consistency going were ties and so you
know the process and the marketing
funnel keeps getting bigger maybe we'll
talk about marketing funnels in a
different video but look I'm up just
googling for now I don't need to tell
y'all everything other than that when I
let you guys know that February 19th
that's the day that the price is going
up for the master music networking guy
so that's y'all got it till Sunday to
get it for $35 I did say I was gonna
keep it at our lowest possible price
point for you know just two subscribers
to cop at a low price but then it's
going up so we're finally here it's been
about a month month and a half whatever
the time period has been it's going up
giddy if you want to get it for that
price but before it goes up other than
that it's been doped maybe we'll do a
video on it when it comes to people who
have been talking about the results that
they've had even in this short period of
time just using the tacky side of there
but we're gonna do that another video
like I said so if you like this video go
ahead that like button in it like it
might as well share it and if you're not
subscribed but you know what to do he's
dead subscribe