all right Cory you know how they say the
catalog is the key to artist Freedom
right yep yep that's the art that's the
value that's where the money comes from
we got a video of an artist breaking
down how his catalog legit freedom but
he's giving Game and his real life
situation so we got to play this one for
the Pod bro because I haven't seen a
better example a more transparent
example than this where artist is really
showing the power of their catalog and
just changing their whole lifestyle
check this out can you tell me how how
many projects you have on dsps do you
have Anya myself or like just as toal
own like if I go to your what do I own
or what's mine okay yours and then the
tsf uh okay so well my catalog I
probably have maybe
like it's in it's between 27 to 30
albums or something like that in a 10
year in the 10e span from the sauce
twins to S Walker I have
between 20
have in 30 albums almost and that's a
lot of music first and foremost and
let's just start here key to the catalog
is you got to get the music out there in
the first place yeah we got to get the
performance going on but let's just let
this thing especially by the end of this
year it's going to be for sure full 30
it might be a full 30 and I miscount I
just know for sure it's somewhere it's
in that range what about just as a as a
label as a collective as a label I'll
probably own I don't know maybe uh maybe
120 to 100 50 projects like albums cuz
like all of my friends I got 50 artists
50 artist signed to my distribution and
my record level 10 of them are are uh
producers that make beats and stuff and
they still have and they still have
albums as well like uh bodies at work as
well and then I got 40 some artists it's
a little bit over 40 it's a little bit
over 53 but 10 are producers and the
other 40 artist are like artists and
some of the artists that sign to me
people don't even know that they sign to
me or that they my artist today we have
business with each other but I still in
on their catalog so if you incorporate
everybody that's signed to me I have a
50/50 uh split with their catalog on I
probably got like 150 albums 150 albums
would you say that and if you look at
that by songs each album got like 15 20
songs on it so I probably own I don't
know 2,000 3,000 4,000 songs all right
again KJ catalog is numbers first and
foremost I got to remember every single
song you drop is just are dropping that
bigger bucket of having a full-blown
catalog but like let's let's get it a
little bit deeper into the game back to
your catalog
recently you linked up with Empire and
I'm wondering like what was the timing
for you to like make the decision to
kind of link up with a guy like gazi and
bring what you got going on in Houston
and tsf together with what's going on in
the Bay Area at Empire um it's a funny
story because guys have been trying to
sign me since the beginning of my career
it was just um I was doing business with
people at the time who just didn't see
fit for us to do business together and
at the
time I've always had control over my
career but I was trying to allow people
to have management and have opinions and
things of that like that and it just it
never worked out for us in the beginning
and when I finally found
distribution it was before I found a
distribution on my own without gazi
having any or empire being anything
doing a part of it I found uh I found
distribution in California when I was
hanging with famous dicks I met this guy
named Wayne and I started working with
create music group create music group
right and um all right so that's a key
part of something he said like he he
don't touch on it all the way but he
basically says hey I've tried to have
all these different managers and groups
he he had to do a lot of testing but he
but he end up taking his artist career
into his own hands and found
distribution in a situation that made
sense for him yeah like that part we
can't miss on cuz he ain't go through it
all the way but you know good managers
bad managers or people who just aren't a
good fit for whatever the time is like
situations like this everybody has it
everybody has it along the way yeah when
I first got with create um this like
eight years ago and they like you know
they they fill to my whole catalog and
like went through all my YouTube videos
and all them just the bodies of work
that I owned that I allowed them to
facilitate
and they came back with like 80 racks or
some [\h__\h] like that that you didn't even
know was out there for you I didn't even
know that was out there like yeah you
know from what you looking at right now
you could be making somewhere between 80
to $110,000 a month just right now and I
was like that's a lot of money missed a
lot of money Miss that's a lot I find a
lot of these Boutique distribution
situations too are a lot better for
artists who do have something moving
like that because they the deals are
usually where that money is also so
their money too in a percentage so they
are inspired and incentivized to go find
that money for you out in the internet
but if I'm just on Dro kid or you know
one of the lower tiers of most of these
Dro platforms it's like my job is to put
your junk on the platforms yeah I mean
you know I mean yeah I mean I even W up
from there because I mean create music
group is is special in the sense of like
I mean this is the first time I ever
really heard it be referred to in the
same breath as like a Distribution
Company typically I hear more about it
in the r a publishing company and so
none that makes me wonder are they a
Publishing Company offering dis show
services to stand out or are they a dis
show company that figured out publishing
services to to stand out you know cuz
and I think the other big Testament to
it um and probably is what made him so
attractive to Someone Like A CR music
group is that they're looking like hey
bro you you have years in the game youve
built this catalog there's a very clear
line of value here that we could help
you out with because to your point is
like hey there's probably money that you
miss that you don't know about you have
the Cog size to where that is very
likely you know what I'm saying it makes
sense and this is what we can do for you
and to your point it's like how many
other situations would it have made
sense specifically for what he is going
through in his artist ten not many bro
not many that was like eight years ago
so you know what I'm saying I got with
create and I brought I brought my whole
label over to create and I left my
catalog there like but I still have
probably like a 16 or 13 or 12 album
catalog that's not with create to that's
with ton C that was like from the very
very beginning premature premature T
yourself stuff you know what I'm saying
so when I got recreate I start making
bro you can have different situations I
love this problem is he had like a lot
of artists that we talk to they're doing
this at the very beginning where they're
diversifying these Distributors and it's
like you only got 10 songs out and you
have five six different dros that is
spread between that's not the play y but
oh I'm about to drop you know a five
album run with this one Dro and then I'm
going to do another five album run with
another Dr R in different situations you
can leverage a catalog like that because
it's it's product right like it's just a
line of product and you can say hey
we're going to do a deal around this
this is one of my products I'm the
artist but you but a lot of times I
think artists think about themselves as
the product yep when you are the creator
of the product yep right right like a
label okay because of that agreement you
might be the product that gets you know
uh locked up for a given period of time
until the deal is over right but a lot
of these the dro deal side is more so no
the music is the product and how do we
want to package it do I want album one
through three and then you do album four
through five somewhere else that's
really what you should be thinking but I
think most artists again like they're
just like I'm looking for this one home
to have and hold me forever that's not
how this game works yeah 100% I start
making nothing less than five to six
figures a month for the rest of my life
from that point from seven years ago wow
every month every 25th to every month
I've been getting a six figure to seven
I mean a a five fig to six figure check
and that could be anywhere from 60,000
to 200,000 I've never got no more than
200,000 so far like that's still crazy
my goal is to get like a quar million of
money so every mon yeah independent this
just our YouTube videos and songs and on
[\h__\h] so create just you know I'm saying
they open that door to like just really
make me my record when me and my friends
a actual company a actual business to
where every single of my friends and
Associates and counterparts on my Rec La
all get a check on the 25th every month
man that's the that's the thing man like
cuz really all of us are owed this
money black we yeah we get when we get
put in Clips if somebody Clips you up
Corey somebody clip me up and then it's
being played on a repost page and all
that stuff really all of us are Ow like
money for everything we put out content
wise let alone like if you're creating a
horror product like music or something
like that and the right situations can
make sure you get all of that we we who
got deals out there for us man I was
just thinking that yeah who who who has
a deal y'all somebody comes with the
right pitch we are we are open to what
it looks like to make the Pod do what
pods can do so obviously create was
great for you that was create so when
now when you talk about the Empire [\h__\h]
it only made sense for me to sign a deal
of any sort with any
company that was only that only if they
was going to allow me to not bring my
catalog with me because most companies
when you got a catalog like you they're
like yo we going to need to bring that
catalog over period if you want some
millions of dollars from us if you want
us to do business with you ever we do
together don't work the catalog still
going bring in that bre hey back to
exactly back to what I'm saying you
already got something that was that's
working don't go into a new situation
and thinking that you got to mortgage
your house right it's like no my house
is already doing what it needs to do we
can go build a new house but this house
right here is good my car is paid off
this house is paid off you know what I
mean grandma like no I'm not selling
this thing I'm I could pass this thing
down to the kids y'all up there
mortgaging grandma house instead of just
building a brand new house and saying No
this is proof that I can build a house
so let's go build a house together
artists managers there is no way you
should ever do a regular pre-safe
campaign again because forever fan has
forever saves where a fan could pre-save
your music one time and then
automatically pre-save every song you
ever release after that that's right
forever and on top of that forever fan
has email and texting all in one
platform this is built out for artists
who don't have huge teams and don't want
to get overwhelmed doing too many things
in too many different places so go to
Forever fanm music.com No Labels that's
no labels with an S and put in the code
No Labels O2 to get access and try it
out for only a dollar Forever fan is
your goto place for your marketing needs
as an artist so you can stay organized
have your own infrastructure to make it
lot easier to go to the next level again
that's for everfan music.com
laabs and type in the code No Labels O2
at checkout to get access for only a
dollar now back to the episode so in in
reality Empire was the only it was a few
of them that kindor respected but Empire
like guys that he actually respected my
business mind he respected my business
module
and he he he respected the numbers that
I'm able to pull up put up on my own
without a company without resources
without an engine without a machine
without the the being serviced correctly
I'm still creating I'm I'm generating
six figures he said something key there
without being serviced correctly without
all the things and really you want to
look like a potential lick to these
companies y but then don't get licked
that's the game right they need to be
able to see opportunity but you don't
want to get screwed in terms of how you
allowed them to be a part of that
opportunity if that's what you do so
they need to be able to look like dang
this artist is going crazy without me if
I add what I know how to do I can make
this go crazier yep what a lot of
artists are looking for is I'm not going
crazy but if I if I had you I could go
crazy it's like no man I'm trying to
multiply I'm a multiplier here that's
what most people in the business want to
be they want to be a multiplier but if
you're working with zero what does my
multiplier do zero yeah if you're
working with one my
multiplier okay I'm a 3X you're a one
that just left it at
three h I guess but that doesn't give me
much gains you know what I mean if I
could 3x something I want to add my
three to a two to another three to a
five you know what I mean because then I
get better better Returns on it that's
how people are really looking at it in
terms of investing their times
particularly people who aren't like just
straight up trying to screw screw you
over but they're
like I I'm not TR trying to screw you
over but I am trying to be real because
just how you value your time your life
and your investment this is how I value
my time my life and my investment and I
might not even own this product so
you're gonna get passive returns off of
this thing after the work I'm only going
to get return on a certain period of
this work yeah yeah now I agree man I
think I think it speaks a lot too to
just where the mindset of the the major
label system is is moving towards right
cuz you can see through artist
conversations like this and you know
little stuff you may pick up with other
artists that labels are very clearly
focusing on a catalog acts right artists
that or songs that have been hits or at
least know culturally loved for whatever
reason for a certain amount of time and
are actively looking for artists that
have already built some type of a
foundation you know and I was just
telling the artist this today is to the
point you just made it's like hey bro
any proof of concept that you have the
disc could work immediately push you
over like 90% of the artists that are
typically coming through label system
like for you this thing may seem small
but you know they've talked to a
thousand artist this week and you might
have been the first one that even offer
that type of information or that type of
thing around it and so like for the
artists that
are interested in signing to a label or
just even want to like flirt with the
idea you have to go into it knowing that
the artist who would like ass Sal Walker
has been working for years and in built
catalog and these Revenue sources and
has a proven track record are going to
be more valuable and valued than you the
artist that to your point is looking for
the situation to get started once I get
there facts bro if I come up to you and
I was like yo I have this amazing idea
for a company and based on what the
marketplace shows I can turn this into a
hundred million doll company okay oh
sounds nice yeah but what if I say yo I
got another I I got an idea for an
amazing company to take advantage of an
opportunity this could be a $100 million
company I've already built out this
company to a certain degree got some
customers and I'm about
$200,000 in Revenue a
year that hit different right do hit
different man I've already did the work
and I'm really proving this the problem
is a lot of artists are option A they're
just an idea their whole career is an
idea yeah you know what I mean where you
need to be an idea that's been executed
and got a little bit of return some
level of prototype like you said that
that's saying oh snap not only did he
show the opportunity the opportunity
makes sense but he's made ground and
shoot how can we just like double down
and get this to that that potential yes
he was able to make a quarter million
with a with a six people team imagine if
I added my my 30 people team oh he
didn't even know he could be making
money over here and like that's all they
did exactly yeah yeah that's exactly
that we just had to go collect we just
pushed the [\h__\h] button we a it's not
even like we did work we just said hey
um you're actually supposed to get money
over here yeah bro you you looked over
there yet oh no we got a little surprise
for you then man you you going to like
this easy easy work easy work I'm gen
annually every 12 months I'm generating
millions of dollars and not a small one
like a nice amount so I'm nowhere near
with Empire but but tsf is a very small
year I'm I'm a small Indie major like
what I got a staff a back office I got
two two commercial places of business
two compounds with my company ran and
facilitated and you know gazi was just
the only person who was like you know
what I see what you got going on I
respect it and I'm willing to to fund it
I'm willing to give you more more
finances more weapons and I don't want
to own your catalog if you feel
comfortable at one place at the period
of time where you willing for me to give
you XYZ Mount of millions of dollars for
your catalog to bring it over here then
we can do that but I kind of didn't you
know like really made it clear with him
like I just don't want to sell my ke I
just want to live off of forever like
that's something I can real quick next
lesson like hey there is somebody out
there who will give you the deal if you
got something real there's someone who's
who will give you a deal that makes
sense for you y'all just got to stop
saying yes to the first man who show up
having a catalog that you are in the
green and you don't owe anybody
recruitment that's like you own a
Chick-fil-A two three four Chick-fil-A
or you own some Walmarts or some car
dealerships or something after all the
bills is paid your pro and this the
thing with the music [\h__\h] too it feels
like it's all profit cuz you been did
the work I been did the music I been
shot those videos bro he he he cooking
right here he cooking he cooking I'm
going just throw a term out cash flow
that's the big big thing he talking
about cash flow money coming in month to
month and it's liquid because he said
liquid cash y'all understand that all
right Jeff Bezos right billionaire Elon
mus billionaire but that doesn't mean
all that money is liquid or a lot of
it's tied up in their business
especially Elon right a lot of his net
worth meanwhile somebody like Bill Gates
who pulled out a long time ago hasn't
been leading Microsoft obviously he's on
the board da d da like liquid cash he's
probably still the richest in terms of
just liquid cash and able how and that
gives him a flexibility to take
advantage of New Opportunities right
it's the same thing on on every single
level so when you talking about all
these things pop up what you can do or
new opportunities that can grow your
money in other ways
and might become long-term Investments
if you have liquid bro like cash coming
in to fun your lifestyle and New
Opportunities bro like you're good you
you are good versus that I I've heard
this from a lot of people like who came
across the lump sums it's like they get
that lump suum but then you also don't
see new money coming in so you panic
like where's the new money going to come
from because you know that this could go
down I still still got to live life kind
of like what he said so I don't know man
I I love the fact he cooking on this
point I've been released these projects
that [\h__\h] been paid for but I'm still
getting paid for it right now it's like
owning a movie company it's it's a huge
difference so I don't have to like
famous TV show goes into syndication
you're going to get syndicated your risk
forever whoever the [\h__\h] owns fresh
prince of B Martin any of these type of
shows BR you know like the people who
did friends are making like I don't know
it might be like 10 it might be like I
don't know they're making like tens of
millions of dollars a year off of
Friends episodes and they did creators
no I'm talking about the actors each of
them and that was that show was like 20
years ago when they went off God damn
okay so when you talk about syndication
that's what I think about bro like you
just it's gone it's past work mailbox
money crazy just say you get $300,000 a
month for the rest of your life you can
spend the entire $300,000 down another
the next month that's imp like that's
doesn't that's crazy that's crazy but
that's what owning your catalog as an
independent artist need if you're
successful for sure you're getting a
guaranteed 90,000 120 150 140 125,000
guaranteed every month I can flush 125
and this has nothing to do with all the
extra money I make and I'm getting 200
180 190 but this that had nothing to do
and I'm going to get 20,000 over here
for this song this show I'm getting
8,000 for this post I'm getting 10,000
away these clothes that's the best place
to end it new money coming in every
single month when you can still put your
energy into new opportunities
and if you spent that whole 100K whole
50k whatever that number is for you that
month it doesn't matter because it's
going to reappear the very next month
yeah 100% the power of the catalog this
is another episode no necessary podcast
I'm BR man Sean and I'm C we out peace
appreciate you for watching if you like
content like this you'll love seeing our
Amic marketing strategies that we use as
an agency to actually blow up artists to
millions and even billions of streams
that are available for free at Noels
necessary. comom and the cool part about
it that's going to really make you love
it is we don't have to be all
entertaining and add all this fluff just
to get some views that we do on YouTube
we get straight to the information
there's play byplay and courses that
give you a breakdown of every step that
you should do to get success and you
have the ability to have communication
with us we get on live talks a lot of
cool things for members and it's free
just to hop in so check it out right now
at no labels necessary.