you know but this whole toour is a it's
an investment you know we're investing
back into the business you know what I
mean so it's like even if we got to take
a l on the toour it's fine we're going
to give it an experience that like no
you know that you go you go to one of
these venues and you buy another $50
ticket for another artist you're not
going to get the same experience as when
you came to the show that joinan
did and these venues these are
like 2,000 C venues so most of these
venues you don't got like you don't got
parking for like four buses cuz nobody
comes into these venues with four
buses right it doesn't make Financial
sense right so you got to you know you
do simple math right you got $20 a
ticket or oh sorry $50 a ticket you got
2,000
seats right so when you do the math your
guarantee you know you might walk out of
one of these venues a Live Nation venue
or something you might walk out with
30,000 maybe 50 you know what I mean so
anywhere from 20 and 50 depending on the
City if the Cap's a little higher or
lower markets are different you know
what I mean and so
um to bring one of these on the road
your with a driver cuz you got to pay
for the so you got to pay for the bus
you got to pay for the driver you got to
pay for the fuel right so a a 34 Day
Tour is about 20,000 just in
fuel right so so a day you're spending
about
$2,000 when you summarize it right so if
if you got if you got we got one two we
got well technically three in a semi
right so we're 6,000 a day on buses
technically we
driver right z bus and what's in each
bus all right so star bus so Joiner crew
bus and then I got management bus so me
and joy early what we did Is 2020 when
Co happened the touring business went
down so me and him went in and started
buying up buses so we we own all the
buses
bought it while it was low we bought it
while it was low yeah that's all you
know what I'm saying and so um so we we
own about five so y'all rent rent them
out to other people we we even own our
own SE uh trailers too so there's a
whole another story there but our
trailer hit a bridge in Chicago they had
the measurements wrong on the bridge so
the top of the trailer got shaved off so
we had to go rent another trailer to put
on on here that happened in Chicago yeah
it's crazy that was on this tour yeah oh
recent yeah that just happened yeah um
so yeah you know uh and you don't have a
show every day you have a show today and
you have a off day tomorrow but you
still paying the cost yeah right so it
it just doesn't make Financial sense
sometimes we'll bring some of these
buses into the venue and
um they won't have parking because they
don't have facility for that many but
like an arena has places and docks where
you can park the buses these guys guys
not every venue does this these guys
were able to do it but we had a venue in
Toronto and um we had a um Park like you
know 10 minutes out two of the buses
only one bus could stay out there you
know cuz of the permits and Roads and
[\h__\h] like that so there's a lot of
logistics with it um and so so you're
talking you know a couple thousand on
each of the buses um and then we got the
trailers you know so this this trailer
right here this is all our
merchandising so we just put dedicated
merch in here the F the first tour we
were on look you see stacked up stacked
up with stuff you know and then you you
can't carry everything on the tour so
you got to get shipments in so as we're
selling we're sending shipments to the
next cities that's coming cuz we can't
carry everything you know what I mean
it's just not enough room right and so
when we had our first toll we had a bus
but we put all this stuff in the Bays of
the bus so we couldn't even carry that
much you know what I mean cuz you know
finances were more limited and things
like that you know you know but this
whole tour is a it's an investment you
know we're investing back into the
business you know what I mean so it's
like even if we got to take a l on the
tour it's fine we're going to give an
experience that like no you know that
you go you go to one of these venues and
you buy another $50 ticket for another
artist you're not going to get the same
experience as when you came to the show
that Joy did that's important man like
to me that's a big deal so I tell a lot
of like smaller artists who can't do
what y'all talking about like there's
all these like alternative venues that
you can use these days that aren't even
a main venue like if you go to peer
space or something where it just looks
different and I always say because
you're going to go on the same stage
that these other people are on and if
you're not doing something special up
there production cost cost money then
it's just going to feel like another act
but y'all actually have the ability to
invest and I I love that y'all are
cognizant of it like literally someone's
coming the next day and if it just feels
damn near the same like how is what I
did Special A people is just coming in
grabbing their bag how you keep cost low
next city so they got a mic they got a
stage yeah what I mean they basic house
lights basic sound you know what I mean
like that see then we going to deal with
things like this you what I'm saying
look look look you see it right here you
what I mean it's another day man every
city like yeah something but look check
so this semi
right so these are the video panels we
bring in so we bring in our own walls
and stuff but so this gets stacked all
the way to the back right and this [\h__\h]
ends probably where these wheels are
right
there just in lights alone lights video
we bringing extra sound into the venue
and it goes all the way up you see that
bar right there yeah so that it goes up
about a little a little bit higher than
that we went on a Chris Brown to he had
one just for [\h__\h]
clothes like his
wardrobe and like dances on stage and
all the wardrobes yeah so that that tour
that tour was like 2019 that [\h__\h] was
like a crash course cuz we went into
that tour and we was just looking at the
whole operation the whole setup yeah it
gave us Insight on oh [\h__\h] like if we're
going to do it this is what it's going
to look like you know what I mean so
this was like our baby step into
like getting there you know what I mean
this was like a baby step into that so
you know we start investing into our own
stuff just for that reason alone you
know and we was like we don't want to be
subject to oh we can't do it cuz Finance
is going to let once once we had the
money we was like ah we got to get what
we need so we can build on it you know
what I mean and set up the foundation
yeah it's interesting man cuz you were
saying over there right like you saying
like for most artists it's not worth it
to do do it so what was the conversation
that you and Joiner had that made y be
like no it's worth it for us to go ahead
and made this investment so I'm I'm a
numbers person right and I'm more of
like you know the business swivel on
this right so I'm constantly looking at
it from a numbers point of you he he's
looking at it from a creative experience
you know obviously content more video
driven so the video is like mandatory
you know what I mean um so I would say
it was more of him decision you know cuz
from a numbers view nobody will say it
makes sense I was like bro like what are
we doing this is crazy right um but he's
like I don't care I'll take the loss on
it bro I don't care the experience has
to be A1 the fans have to leave so they
come back and they and they feel they
want to see what I'm going to do next he
goes it's no different than my my music
videos they watch one of my videos and
then they're like yo I can't wait till
join drops another joint and we don't
know what to expect from him y he goes
my shows have to be the same way and so
when he broke it down for me like that I
was like all right [\h__\h] it like you know
we put it this way we started touring in
2016 we've been reinvesting into it and
we're in 2014 in 2024 now yeah so we've
been 8 years reinvesting into this
business to just keep trying to level it
up you know what I mean and then you're
going to hit that
you're going to hit that you know escape
velocity yeah then it's going to be like
okay now you know not just like anything
bro you drop content you drop content
you get dropped and then you get picked
up by a label and you know you drop
content you drop content you get that
one break you know the touring business
is the same way you got to keep
investing into it you know I mean
there's no shortcuts it's hard ticket
buyers people coming out spending their
money it's hard ticket buyers you know
and they they're coming out to these
shows spending you know they're spending
a ton of money like it's not just $50 on
the ticket you know what I mean like
it's a preparation how they going to get
there the
food you know spending money
merchandising when they're in there
drinking um clothes whatever you know
what I'm saying it's like it's a whole
thing that goes into going to a show
they're going to call off work or
they're not going to work that day you
know what I mean so it's not just a $50
ticket or a $100 ticket you know what
I'm saying there's a whole so you know
um it's not easy to get people to spend
money to want to come out and watch you
that's like one of the hardest things to
do like people don't even pay for music
at this point right so you want me to
leave my house you know what I'm saying
yeah so it's it's really tough man even
with a fan base it's it's really
difficult what about festivals do y'all
look at festivals or y'all try to stay
aside from it so they can only see you
when you come out that's that's an
interesting one um so you know the
festivals what they do is right they
they'll they'll um they'll have the main
Headliners and they're paying the
biggest bag to them and then everybody
else is getting shorted on the bill
and they're just running up the numbers
on the short they know your value is
more than whatever it is in that market
but they're giving you a lobal offer
because you get to headline for you get
to perform with this person on that
stage they're selling you the stage you
know what I'm saying and so these
festivals are set up where um you know
you're not making the money you you
really
should right you're going to make the
money once you're that guy and you're
like top three on that stage right but
you know everyone else ain't really
making that
you know what I'm saying do you think
they mess up the ability to do your own
show or do they help like maybe you do
it one year then the next year you come
back and just do your own show um I
think it's I think it's like anything
it's like Supply supply and demand you
know so they they they're like oh we're
going to grab you so you can't perform
this Market when we come in cuz you're
going to have a radius clause and all
that you know and we're going to get you
on the low and you're going to accept it
cuz we're going to bring all these
people out that you can't get in front
of because it's more people at this
Festival because of the headlines so
they're leveraging they're leveraging
the fact that they got this big festival
with thousands of people in it the big a
the big stage you know the benefits is
the benefits is you're not having to pay
for all
this right so we have to pay for this on
our own [\h__\h] we go to a festival this is
already there right and then we just
bring in the staff that's going to make
sure your shit's done right right like
what's the radius clause what's that a
radius clause what's that uh well like
uh you can't perform within a certain
mile radius of that location so if it's
New York they'll say you can't perform
there for 90 days or something you know
um before after or whatever it is you
know so you can't go to that City and
perform so yeah so they're just taking
like almost like exclusivity for that
time
frame yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah you know
so it's you know it's um yeah so you
know the festivals is good you get a lot
of exposure and stuff but then there's a
lot of artists that go on these
festivals but when they go try headline
they can't sell nothing
so they're doing the festival circuit a
lot of artists they get a trendy record
and then you see them they're on every
festival and then they try to do their
own headline and they can't do it and
it's like you haven't invested into your
your audience long enough you haven't
invested into doing your own shows where
people want to see this experience that
you can give them they're not they're
not sold yet you did the festival
circuit and they saw like another 50
acts you were one of 50 you wasn't one
of one on your own show you were one of
50 right so it's like what experience
did you and then what you're not even
headlining that cuz you a trendy artist
with a a record that just popped that
year someone else's head and their show
is looking crazy you know I think they
said something about cardi like cardi B
she had like did some Super Bowl perform
no wasn't Super Bowl it was a Coachella
or something yeah it was a Coachella and
um something about how she had to invest
like 600k or something it was something
I remember that yeah yeah yeah right and
that was like what they were doing right
it's cuz she invested back into I'm
going to make this [\h__\h] look so epic so
every single one of you that are here is
going to say I need to go to a cardi
show when I pull up in the City by
myself I feel like that's the that's the
real downside to the festival rid life
you don't care enough to invest to
create your own experience while you got
to let Coach roll Law whatever Creed it
and I think that messes with the young
artist like ego cuz I can imagine bro
being like a new act your first time
ever performing as like a festival 30 40
50,000 people and I can imagine it just
like [\h__\h] up your mentality moving
forward you know what I'm saying like
what it is yeah think that's what it is
exactly like I'll show let me show you
the bus though so you you can see you
see what what the road look
like so what we did was we wrapped the
whole [\h__\h] with Tully and the Joiner to
get the promotion around it we were
going to be on the road anyway right so
we're like we might as well go ahead and
you know promote promote what we're
doing with Tully and you know and the
project that this the first time y'all
did this on the tour like wrapped it
yeah no I had it wrapped before but um
on the tour yeah cuz I was cuz I was
like the The Branding is current this is
like the current tour branding yeah we
so we just did this we just did this for
this tour specifically so to wrap a bus
you know you're talking about
10,000 roughly to wrap it you know
outside of the car so there's so much
miscellaneous cars you you rent a
trailer you're spending another 3 4,000
for the month you know just racks up you
know the driver gets paid a little bit
more to pull a trailer they get paid an
extra 50 a day or whatever you you know
so you're paying another 3,000 for the
driver for pulling the trailer you know
you go into a city like New York you
can't even take this in there so we get
to if we performing in New York this has
to park in like Jersey City or some [\h__\h]
then we have to get like a pickup truck
that will come in and pull this pull
this in cuz you you can't it's like you
need permits and [\h__\h] to bring stuff in
you can't bring these buses in they'll
let the semi come in but it's going to
come in load out and leave and then come
back you know so there's some there's
some you know this Logistics that come
with the whole thing extra cost cuz now
you got to bring that in right you got
to get the pickup truck and the driver
to bring this in when you get there um
here we we'll jump on the
joint like our house basically you know
what I'm saying this the living room um
and all the bus have different layouts
these are shelves these are Pros buses
and all these get built out you know
specifically so the crew bus got 12
bunks in it it's like jail
[Laughter]
yeah but this this is like you know this
is this is a little bit more comfortable
um go through here you got like the
bathroom a man this is like a restaurant
level sink man it's a nice bathroom man
we got uh two bunks right here one two
so I usually travel one two people with
me you know what I mean and then I got
bedroom got Studio set up in the back
why is there a studio in yours make
music you make music too yeah yeah make
beats and [\h__\h] you know so I went school
for music okay I went to full sale in uh
uh 2000
2004 so I graduated from there so my
passion was always to like do music I
just didn't know how like or what my
position in music was going to be so it
started with like just making beats and
[\h__\h] like that you know and then um yeah
and then um and it's like I don't really
get that much time to do it cuz I'm
always handling like the business side
of it but it's a good like mental Escape
just to like be able to make music
sometimes it [\h__\h] get used sometimes it
don't joiners picked up a few joints and
did some joints with it which has been
dope it's been like that's just like
damn like that's fire you know what I
mean but yeah I've got to stay focused
on really the business side of it you
know numbers yeah but yeah so I got a
little setup here if I ever want to make
music sleep go to the front Lounge
handle some business it's just going to
be comfortable on the road as much as
possible yeah yeah you know what I mean
and if you said the first tour y'all
share the bus everybody was on the bus
it was nuts do it was crazy crazy so so
the layout in in like the crew bus so
this back area would be like a lounge
with like a a sectional
couch right so you got like a little
couch area the entire middle so like
really from like here all the way up to
the front right you got bunk so you got
1 2 3 4 5 6 and then on the left side
you got 1 2 3 four five six and then you
got a hallway in the middle so the left
and right is bunks all the way down and
then you've got a lounge in the front so
you got a front Lounge the bunks the
back
Lounge man I bet that bus
stink I ain't taking you on that
[Laughter]
bus yeah but you know so traveling
traveling with the crew side is it's
tough It's got its challenges you know
what I
mean yeah and so we was you know we we
used um um the crew bus and so the first
tour we went on um we we only had um yo
we didn't even have [\h__\h] bunks on the
first one on the first one we had a back
lounge and a front lounge and we had
[\h__\h] was sleeping like this bro
like you know what I mean and it had
like a fold out couch and people were
like laying like this across and they
had one person going like this another
one like it was
crazy you what I mean like it was wild
like and and the back Lounge it had the
sectional like this yes so I I'd sleep
on this side Jord was sleeping on that
side you know I can make you appreciate
this though you know what I'm saying so
when when we did that so much he was
like bro we can't do I can't do this
[\h__\h] bro like if we're going to tour we
can't do so yeah soon as the co [\h__\h]
happened we was like [\h__\h] it let's get
our buses let's go and don't get me
wrong it's not just get a bus and it's
like a car it's just there if you don't
use these shits they'll break this
things like all right so
look one tire on this bus is $1,200
right so you got two four five six seven
you got eight tires so do a new set of
tires on this whole thing 10
over right all right then you got
airlines that travel from the front of
the bus all the way through to the back
of the bus so it's it's on suspension
and Airlines so you know if you're on
slopes and [\h__\h] like that so if an
airline braks your bus is already
starting to tilt and airlines are just
Airlines like they can break they can
rip they can you know what I'm saying
they can split like so you know you got
a chassis you know which is the main
Pros chassis um and there's a bunch of
work there with brakes and rotors and
all that right um You Got um you got a
generator that's on the bus so a
generator you got like a 20 Kow
generator that powers this a generator
is about
$20,000 right and then you got a blower
on a fan and so the blower on the fan
keeps the generator cool so if the
generator at any point blows or
overheats or some [\h__\h] like that it's a
$20,000 generator like you're going to
have to just replace right because you
didn't take care of it or over
overheated or whatever the generator
tires into the AC's so we got uh we got
one on this one we got
three AC Zone one two and three so
usually got three to four AC's on the
bus so the generator allows the lights
and the AC and televisions and
everything to run you know what I mean
initial investment when you said hey
we're going to go in get our own buses
um all right
so such a loaded question because you're
not buying them brand new right you
buying them brand new it's a few million
dollars right so 2024 type [\h__\h] right
all right check this this bus right here
is a 2001
chassis okay it's 20 year old okay look
at the inside though yeah it's renov on
the inside you will never know cuz it's
on 01 chassis but it's renovated so
these buses see a lot of artists what
they do is like oh I want to book a bus
it's going to be new what's the year and
that's the wrong way to look at a bus
you should never look at a bus like that
right cuz you could have a new bus and
it's not even broke in which means
you're going to have problems identifi
the problems you only identify the
problems on the bus as it goes as it's
on the road okay you might not have a
motor problem you might not have a
transmission problem but that's not the
only only thing you got to worry about
on a bus if you have a air leite problem
your bus can't move cuz your bus is
going to hit the
floor you know what I'm saying so you're
going to have these other issues that
you might have not encountered yet so
they always say you should get a bus
that's like broken in so you can know
what the Kinks are in it and you can
address them right you know what I'm
saying so um you know this bus
specifically you know it's a 01
obviously renovated on the inside new I
mean if you bought it right now it's
maybe like
350 okay you know so um when if we if we
ever were to book a bus on the road now
I would never ask what year it is the
first thing I would say is how many
miles on it I want to know how many
miles have been put on the bus so these
things can go for a million plus miles
so this bus only has
200 I got to check maybe like 270,000
miles so this is like broken in now
right but it's got mad life left it's
got 800,000 plus miles depending on how
I take care of it yeah right so it's got
a lot of life but it's a
01 so it's broken in 270,000 mi and it's
only a 01 it's not been it's had a
remand engine it's a original engine in
it you know I mean so it's like it's
it's it's it's it's it's it's you know
it's not been overworked right you see
what I mean but it's been broken enough
to be used so the first thing I ask is
how many miles on the thing um cuz
that's going to if they told me oh the
bus got 800,000 mil I'm like oh you just
running this thing might have issues on
the road that might be the time where
[\h__\h] the motor goes out or the
transmission goes out the second thing I
ask is when was it last on the
road if it's been sitting for 6 months
cuz it got out of the shop I don't want
it it doesn't guarantee me the [\h__\h]
going to work when it get on the road
cuz you might have some other problems
that come up now you I mean so I'll be
like did it just come up a tour perfect
that's the bus I
wanton because it just came off the tour
I know it's already faced all its issues
it's going to have on the road show me
the maintenance log what's the issues
you had on the last run you know what I
mean cuz bro it's a nightmare cuz what
you you put up a deposit right you
booked the
bus now you're on the road now you have
an
issue technically the company's
responsible for being able to give you
another bus and all that but these
supply and demand they can't just get a
bus so now what you got to book flights
what you doing waiting on the company to
book your flight n you got to show you
going to probably book it and then ask
them to pay you back now what's the
chances of them paying you
back right so it's like you could book a
bus thinking you getting a great deal
and just end up screwing yourself into
double the amount of money because
you're going to have issues with that
bus and now now you fighting with that
person there's a lot of shady businesses
and Shady companies out here a ton of
them I've dealt with them the reason I
bought a bus is because I had a operator
operate my bus and he did shady [\h__\h] so
I don't [\h__\h] with him no more cuz this
whole business is dirty you know I'm
saying it's a dirty dirty business like
[\h__\h] you you take a you take a
bus somewhere people take Parts out of
your [\h__\h] and throw it onto another bus
and switch it out you'll never know
you're not a
mechanic that's crazy man because I was
just talking about the other day how the
industry like artists usually get
pointed to record labels in terms of all
the the evil or just things that's bad
but then obviously we have this Live
Nation thing and you hear okay well
there's things on touring side and now
you're talking about something as
specific as just who's operating the
buses it just s sounds like there's so
many different L businesses to learn
like being an artist manager right and
then there's so many potential bad
people that you got to protect yourself
from listen the touring side is probably
one of the ugliest really yeah like the
record label stuff it's like right in
your
face you know what I mean it's like
wearing a suit across the boardroom you
what I'm saying and they're telling you
your face in this business like you
don't you don't know it you know what
I'm saying like again a mechanic right I
don't know if you
[\h__\h] took some [\h__\h] out the bus and
replaced it with something else and you
know what I mean like you don't know
like you don't know until you stop and
have a problem with something and now
it's like now you going to match up
serial numbers is this the part I
bought bro imagine imagine you take your
bus into a you take your bus into a shop
right everything good right imagine you
go on the back you got two tires or
sorry you got two on this side two on
this side then you got singles right
what what are you going to do go look at
them and think about how they
blew you got no clue so what you got to
track the serial number on the tire you
follow what I'm saying it's like there's
so much little things within the bus
business that I had to learn because I
bought the buses then I had to operate
to operate them and then once I saw it
wasn't going the way it need to go I was
like damn that's how I got my crash
course in it and it's like it's cool I
took the L you what I mean because
that's how I learned about it now I know
you ain't going to get over on me on the
road when I have to book 10 buses cuz we
going to go do stadiums now and when a
driver say oh this went out oh did it
how'd you know
that yeah I mean and they start talking
their lingo you know oh yeah you know
the transmission's out and the the
motor's doing this did you plug it into
the ECM he's like oh how does he know
what a [\h__\h] ECM
is yeah I mean yeah can you show me the
report did you take it into a shop what
shop you take Mom and po no no I need to
go to a Detroit Diesel I need the report
from
them you know what I'm saying so it's
like I know enough now to know where
like a driver can't get over on
me you know what I mean and I took a I
took an L with that before just to be
able to understand that and learn that
so I won't be in that situation got you
you know what I mean and so there's a
lot of little Logistics to this you know
they're like oh the generator don't
start the generator don't start oh look
we're trying it and we're going to have
to get a mechanic out oh you spend
$1,000 oh he couldn't fix it we're going
to have to get someone else you know
what I mean but why don't it start when
was the last service on it you know and
we're looking at different [\h__\h] and I'm
learning the [\h__\h] you know what I'm
saying oh the solonoid you just got to
replace the solonoid look the shit's not
touching that part's like [\h__\h] couple
hundred
bucks yeah you know and so so many again
we're not mechanics so we don't know
this stuff right you know what I mean
like I don't know this [\h__\h] I'm I'm
learning [\h__\h] as I go you know what I
mean I was I was told my steering is off
oh the steering's dragging you're going
to need a whole new front end right Trev
they were like you're going to need a
whole new front end right you're man
your steering is really bad it's really
bad the steering fluid's good but this
[\h__\h] is so stiff so I was like word I
was like do me a favor get the alignment
done first change these ties at let's
get the alignment done first he did the
alignment yo it's fine
now how much did that cost y [\h__\h]
less than 500
bucks we you're talking 60,500 bucks you
understand what I'm saying
yeah and so we had a tie that blew on
the road so we got a new tire put in and
then we were on the road for 5 days and
the steering just get kept getting worse
we went and looked at the new tire the
whole tire the inside thread was flush
like had no thread in it and we only
drove like maybe 1500 miles maybe and so
it's like you know there's a lot of
logistics to this business that a lot of
people don't understand and I don't know
you know not even close to what I need
to know you know what I mean but it's at
this point it's all high level [\h__\h]
right I don't need to know everything
I'm not a [\h__\h] mechanic I don't right
but I just need to know enough or I need
to have enough resources you know um my
guy Travis from major Toren he's like a
good resource he's he's dope cat he's
got like eight bus is he does a lot of
the big tours in the US you know what
I'm saying if something go wrong he's
the one that was like yo Drew have him
turn turn turn the wheel all the way to
the right and go look at the tire and
then have him do all the way to the left
and go look at the other tire and I sent
him a picture he goes yo the tires is
flush go get that alignment he's the one
that told me yeah you know what I'm
saying and then I went and did it he was
like is it good I was like yeah
everything perfect now he's like all
right bet I didn't know what to look at
that I'm learning that [\h__\h] now now
whenever that happens I know right you
know what I'm saying because of him yeah
you know what I mean so um the the
touring business I'll say is real
important that you just have key people
that you can trust that know enough
about the business so you can lean on
them as [\h__\h] comes up brust break down
you need a bus you know they know you
know they can get you on the bus or you
got a problem with the bus they can tell
you hey diagnose it do this do that do
this to try to help you figure it out
you know it's small community too you
know and what's that what's that saying
um the the mechanic where the mechanic
always tries to JP you yeah that's what
this is it's just a more expensive
bigger version you know what I mean so
y'all got to rent these things out as
soon as y'all get off a tour basically
like is that the goal like to always
keep the bus so I had this one leased I
had this one leased for like a year um
now I'm using it um um but it's been
active I didn't just have it sit yeah
because it would have been worse if I
just had it sit so I ended up leasing it
cuz I wasn't using it you know yeah this
is crazy man right here yeah this is uh
the state set for joining you said a
state sale yeah State set oh State set
okay got you that was the production
that's his actual State set and then my
my one was used for the merchandising
we're going to the venue so you can see
like kind of like the setup you I mean
so you can see how how we got this whole
thing set
[Music]
up this lighting trust this right here
the video we're bringing this stuff
in man so I mean we talked about the
like additional production y'all bring
in obviously because y'all want a
specific
experience and how much that cost but
there's an additional cost of getting
people to set it up in every city right
cuz that's like that's not their house
all right so look in equipment right now
we're probably all right so we're like
200,000 just in gear
rental um we have Mike um who's our
production manager who's like pretty
much like the glue and the brains of the
operation you know what I mean um very
important to every day every setup it's
a lot of work because we're leaving a
city at 2: a.m. getting here at 10:00
a.m. setting up and then the show starts
and then so doing it the next day it's
like it's a lot but he's like the glue
um we got um stage hands at every
location so um we have
uh our front of house audio joiners
audio we got Mike um we got the video so
there's four and then every city we
arrive to we have about 12 Stage
hands 1215 stage hands that are helping
set it up and the problem with this
stage hands part is like a lot of these
people are just like labor so they don't
really know how to set it up so it
requires mik to guide hey I need this
and I need that and everyone's stuff is
unique like they don't know how to mount
and clamp certain [\h__\h] if they haven't
used it before you know what I mean so I
mean some of them is familiar some of
them is not you know but it's a it's a
it's a it's a new crew every day that
we're dealing with cuz we're not rolling
with the crew you know I remember again
on the on the Chris tour we went into
the arena and they had like [\h__\h] 200
Stage hands bro there's like [\h__\h] 200
people bro like setting up a show it's
[\h__\h] crazy I was like
damn you know but yeah so we don't have
to roll with everybody right you know we
have them here and then we pay for the
labor hours and stuff here with the
venue so it's another cost yeah it's
another cost um bring in some of the
sound as well bring in some of our own
sound as well um you you as you can see
it's it's a big setup yeah you know what
I mean like that video ball alone is
crazy it's crazy you know what's the uh
what's the numbers on the screen for is
that like where the panels go or
something or certain shots go or
something um what you mean like the like
the one two 3 four five like is that I
think he's just aligning like but yeah
yeah for the for whatever video he's
going to run yeah um see we're running
with a crew of like 20 plus right now
and obviously everyone's going to get
paid too you
know do you feel like it's a clear a
it's clear to see like the value of the
investment in this tour already like the
First shows was like oh man they can see
the level up the fans experience it I'm
bro this is the the blindest business
you could ever be in this is the this is
like the one business that you can't
write a formula to you know what I mean
like a lot of stuff you're doing you're
doing based off of um like a feeling or
like you know this is what I think we
should be doing you know um no if again
if if you told a record label even if
theyve got your touring rights I need to
do this they're not giving you the money
for it they're giving you tour support
to just get on the road they ain't
giving you the bread to do all
this because they'll be like no it's
it's um it's too much and we can't see
the ROI on it you know what I mean
they'll do it on the music because they
know what the streams and sales and all
that's going to equate to for them you
know what I mean but they're not doing
it like that I mean when we when we
signed with Atlantic in 2016 I think our
toour support might have been like 50K
I mean that couldn't even
cover production equipment that couldn't
even cover a
bus are y'all signed still now or no no
no we we we got off the we got off the
deal in December of 2018 okay any huh
been Indie sense so most of the big
growth that we know today came from
Indie stuff absolutely yeah yeah and I
mean that again that was a Learning
lesson too you know we did it and we we
learned it wasn't for us we learned it
wasn't something we wanted to do and so
you know um we wouldn't have known
unless we did it otherwise we were
constantly like you know looking at
other big artists going oh we ain't got
that because we don't
got that right we ain't got the label
you know what I'm saying so that's why
we haven't been able to get there you
know we went to the label so we know
like that wasn't the reason you know
what I mean so it's it's part of it you
know you you got to take some L's in
this business right like not
everything's going to be a win that's
why on the touring side when we when I
took the L on that I was like it's all
right you I mean I learn from it you
know what I mean I'm I'm okay with
taking a loss as long as we learn from
it and you know and it's it's part of
the growth you know what I mean
so so we try to tell our audience it's
only a real L if it stops you if you
move past it and you learn from it and
it just was a a learning moment exactly
exactly and then um yeah so front of
house right here they set up right here
and then we got the the merch set up so
I'll show you that and another thing is
like merchandising right so there's this
um what is that there's this stigma that
like touring is the way you make your
money merchandising is the way you make
your money right definitely hear that a
lot right and so it's
like I've seen artists go on the tour
and like they're not making that much
money on merch right cuz it's all based
on the audience right so if you
have uh what's a a general merch item
right t-shirt t-shirt hat Hood right
uhuh all right cool now let's think
about let's think
about um an artist right that brings out
I don't know let's say they bring out
10,000 people right
so if that audience comes out and let's
just say it's I don't know 90% female
and they're like dressed up they dress
up they put on their heels and their
dresses and right they're coming out
like a club to show out right right they
don't wearing a
hoodie yeah yeah you know what I'm
saying like they're not wearing a hoodie
well at least not thinking about getting
one right now not not dressed like that
your audience don't buy hoodies like
that they might wear it casually in the
house but they're not really that
audience right um and
so you know I think merchandising is
really important
um you know the stuff that we're doing
fits the demographic of Joiner you know
what I'm saying cuz joiner's fan base is
people that's s to hip hop and rap a lot
of backpack rap you know what I'm saying
and the women that will come to the
shows they wear t-shirts they wear
hoodies they don't care to dress up like
that you know what I'm saying some of
them in college you know what I mean so
this merchandise goes you know what I
mean and like you know we could be doing
over 10,000 night in just
merch just in merch you know what I mean
every city so we got 24 stops you know
you're doing over a quarter million just
on
merch and y'all are how do y'all project
the how much y'all are going to sell at
each stock um every Market's different
you know but we have this app called at
venue that does all the inventory counts
on what you have and then as you're
doing the sale it's it's pretty much
tracking everything you're selling so
you know what you're running short of
what you have you know what I mean so
what you talked about about sometimes we
got to ship merch ahead to a city that
we're going to be be at in the future
it's not like at the beginning of the
tour you pick each City you find out
during the tour and then decide yeah cuz
he'll be like yo we're selling we're
selling a lot of that white T-shirt and
he'll show me the at venue and we could
see oh [\h__\h] this one's actually selling
all right yo listen this next city I
need you to send me a shipment of the
white te's don't send me anything else
cuz we're selling the most of that right
so we can kind of make real time
adjustments using the app venue app
you know on it um and you know so
merchandising is a big business for
Joiner because naturally you know it's
um it's uh you know it's what people
want from him you know what I mean and
so uh We've invested a bit into it we've
invested into the online store a lot you
know what I mean um and and then
obviously you have the meet and greets
side as well where people like want to
meet Joiner and take pictures with him
so you have the meet and greet which
crosses into the merch because they
receed autographed items and stuff like
that so you've got your show guarantees
for for being here you've got your
merchandising Revenue you got your meet
and greet Revenue right um and then
you've got if you're booking any After
parties and things like that so those
are like your main income sources you
got your guaranteed Revenue you got your
merchandising you got your meet and
greet and then you got if you're booking
anything outside of that how much do
y'all get into the Afterparty Vibe uh
Jordan is just not the type of artist
that really cares for that stuff he
don't really care to be in the club and
I mean so you know
not not not nothing crazy but I mean
yeah the inquiries do come and it's just
a matter of how he feels you know if he
wants to go or not and depending on the
city and yeah but as again I think
that's also one of those things as you
as you just continue growing you know
what I mean that thing was like another
purchase I'm saying yeah you got a gam
ofi basically just hearing the trick all
day yeah watching it um and the meet and
greet revenues and the merchant revenues
like it's it's a lot man it's good like
it that that could exceed what you're
getting paid just to be here for the
show that could this literally has
exceeded on this tour has it sometimes
exceeded what we're getting here but
what we get in here we're completely
investing back into the business right
all right so does that break even costs
and then you have you know merch and and
that helps even fund most of the [\h__\h]
too got you you know cuz that stuff's
not free we got to pay for all that look
you saw those boxes that's all advanced
money that we haven't been paid for yeah
so what happens when you finish a tour
and you've got [\h__\h] 40 buckes
left yeah you're sitting on it so so
that goes into the merchandising side so
you know a lot of people you know they
try to stock up on this merchandising so
when we started merch we started buying
the merchandizing having it in a
warehouse so you're paying a warehouse
cost a fulfillment cost right and um
um we might have had like $250 $300,000
in product and zero in the
bank right because we've got all the
money in the product yeah and then what
we did was we shifted into a print on
demand service so now all the
merchandizing um prints on demand when
the purchase is
made right so now we're not holding the
inventory in a warehouse we don't have a
warehouse cost right we just have a
product cost for when it has to get
printed and a fulfillment cost for when
it goes out but we don't have to hold it
which means the purchase comes in and
it's Pro it's your cash FL positive
immediately right right so the only time
we're investing in merchandising at this
point is when we're doing exclusive
merchandising that we can't do on print
on demand so it's a unique item and when
we're on the road right outside of that
we look to integrate with Services where
we can print on demand printing
skateboards on demand you know hats on
demand t-shirt on demand backpacks on
demand blankets on Demand right so we've
got a whole product run and there's
sites like printful uh there's uh guten
and so these you have a Shopify website
you just get a guten plugin and now you
go to the G and catalog and you can pick
everything you want item wise you get a
designer to design the specs you put
them on your site order goes through it
goes through the G and plugin you didn't
have to pay for no inventory it just
printed straight on demand through G and
your opinion is worth the cost that they
take away from handling all those
Services yeah cuz otherwise you're going
to put it up front and you're going to
sit in a warehouse and you're going to
be hundreds of thousands of dollars
sitting in a you need that for marketing
you need that money to go promote what
you're trying to put out no sitting in a
warehouse somewhere nobody knows about
it it's interesting to see like even at
y'all's level where y'all are it's print
on demand as the best option it just
seems like it's about being Nimble
because a lot of smaller artists are
thinking like all right I might do some
print on the in just because I can't now
but I'm trying to get to just paying for
my own inventory and and having that
type of system but y'all basically have
like yeah no we need to we have so much
other things to invest in well you got
to think right what is the purpose of
selling merchandising what is the whole
if an artist is selling merchandising
the whole purpose of that outside of the
obvious which is making
revenue is your brand value right it's
um how much are you worth and what are
people willing to actually invest into
your brand yeah why is that important
cuz that's going to dictate your brand
deal right that's going to dictate when
Nike comes up and says hey we're going
to cut you 20 grand to do this or 50
Grand to do
this you know what I'm saying like
you're going to
um you know you're not going to
um you're not going to accept 50 Grand
from Nike if you know you're doing a
couple million on your online
store you're going to go what you want
me to do what for what
yeah no no no no no and you want
exclusivity where like oh I can't do
another shoe or a power brand because
I'm doing your [\h__\h] well first off if
I'm doing 2 million a year on the
store over five years so we're 10
million we're worth 10 million right now
if you want exclusivity right and you're
going to want rights to our store right
because that's where our traffic go
right so our starting point is a $10
million conversation
if this business is built up to 2
million a year our starting point is $10
million because we can do that
ourselves right and so cool now you want
what exclusivity to the name likeliness
for 3 years or whatever the time period
is and you know and you want him to
attend photo shoots and videos and all
this other crap you guys need him to do
all right cool so that's different
that's the separate cost to what the
online stores that's happening no matter
what right yeah you see what I mean so
the whole reason you want to invest into
your merch is so you can build your
value up cuz when you're going to do the
brand partnership you're you're
essentially saying hey this is my value
this is what I bring to the table you
know and I'm giving this you know 2
million a year up so let's not even
worry about it let's let's just let's
just build this up and then when you
have the conversation I'm just going to
do the numbers I'll say let's just talk
about our store put join to one side
talk about the exclusivity on the store
and the exclusivity on the products on
the store you know what I mean what is
that you guys do numbers you guys are
going to do your little valuations go
ahead and do it what's what number do we
land at all right great now let's talk
about what joint is getting paid to
actually step in and do it right so for
me it's important to build into this
business for that reason alone you know
we've wanted to work with a
brand you know we've wanted to work with
like in a power brand that was going to
step in you know we always use the uh
nipy Puma you know scenario as like the
man that would be like the ideal
situation you know like for us to be
able partner with the brand and do that
you know but again nothing comes to you
in the timing you want you know
sometimes you got to just wait and it's
going to come to you when it's supposed
to come so you know for us it's been a
bit of a weight game to get that you
know and the right brand will find us at
the right time you know and you know by
then we would have done the
groundwork and then the way I see it at
the very least they never came you still
got a business and you and you're
winning absolutely it's we got to be
able to survive it's like you can't Bank
on a record label for your success right
you're got to be like survive without
that if needed right and so it's the
same thing you know it's we going to be
able to survive without the brand like
we going to we got to do it no matter
what there's no there's no oh I start
making music once I get signed like you
know what I mean like you got to do it
so with we got to do it it's just part
of it yeah yeah you know I mean how did
y'all price y'all's merch like I guess a
good way to think about it is like from
day one and then how did y'all get to
where y'all are now yeah I mean there's
a pretty standard Baseline because
there's there only so much you can go
down on material costs you know what I
mean with quality and things like that
you can buy crappy items like you know
we're trying to buy like premium
products so they're not like washed down
when we started the products were a
little bit more low quality and but as
we're like obviously growing and we're
like oh no it's important that we give
someone an item that's you know just
going to last that's going to last you
know what I'm saying I think um look
I'll show you I'll show you some right
here this was like this is a really good
quality Hood right and I don't know
where he got it he might let me
see
um well that hoodie was actually
inspired by
this um we don't go to here it's
actually inspired by like this Versace
hoodie oh word so the Versace hoodie was
like $1,000
you know what I mean and the Versace
print was like basically that you know
what I mean and then we we had a a place
out in Florida that does merchandising
and we had him just create something
custom you know what I mean and and the
cost of this wasn't nothing crazy but we
selling it for like what $80 I think so
we did that you know that was that was
the really the the only custom one
everything else was print on demand you
can buy some a lot of these on on the on
the website got you yeah that's dope
that y'all basically treated like real
fashion where a lot of times they get
inspired by what they see out there and
then they figure out how to make it in
house bro we haven't even been able to
like really step into that the way we
want cuz join is like constantly coming
up with stuff but it really does require
like a brand to step in and help you
like put that together cuz like we're
investing in buses we're investing in
the music like like we're spread thin
like because we're putting money up for
so much [\h__\h] so it's like this is
clothing this is a subsidary of the
music it's like a secondary thing it's
not a you know what I'm saying and so
it's like that's a whole another
business so we really do need the right
brand to step in that's going to really
help us amplify and be a partner to it
but till then we're going to keep
experimenting we're going to keep doing
as much as we can you know what I mean
like join a when you see a state set all
he's merchandising he's wearing his
custom he created not now I'm busy like
outfits and [\h__\h] vests and you know
what I mean like and so it's like all
that could technically be product that
we could be selling right you know but
we can't Mass manufacture that stuff we
can get it for him but we can't Mass
manufacture that you know what I mean
because it's it's a big it's a big
undertaking how's that one been selling
so far it's good like we'll move it you
know what I mean like it's not going to
be a problem it should be all the key
things in terms of we can do the sit
down next yeah I think we covered good
amount right yeah
[Music]