could could I be like a Evil Genius
that's not that's not what God want me
to do I'm trying to show people how to
level up to Ma I can take one Loop and
show you ways that you never heard your
[Music]
Loop the girl sent me this song so I can
even take your song that you already got
and I can remix it and and when you pull
up rip play I'mma play you the original
and I'mma say yo I think I hear better
this way so I didn't need her to come
here understand she already sent me an
MP she have her so I'm sing so I don't
care if you play I said and what's
what's what's and she came off my show
London what's her name London London
Hill London Hill I'm already working
when I sent her a beat she supposed to
finish this beat but while she finish a
beat I already did three eight different
remixes of her beat of her song I'm like
y I want to put this on my album this
version yeah so I'm like playing with
different ones I'm like which style you
playing we playing let's play I'm got
the original already then we going to
play the boom bap because there's a lot
of different styles I think the boom
style is like the hardest one okay like
those Styles like cuz the way she's
rapping remind me of like why she feel
like Lil Kim so she got to have some
little Kim [\h__\h] this original that she
said yeah
[Music]
watch my off we are not the
samech
[Music]
like got the
all right so that's a version I said huh
as hard as it is I got I definitely got
to hear it is hard that [\h__\h] hard bro
but like for me I'm like okay what but
what that what what that gave you the
feel of what
like early 2000s right like yeah like
Kanye like my beautiful dark Kanye her
voice definitely is vocally like on some
so I was like yo so I said like I just
think about what the world going back I
said I feel like that's hard right but
boom bap is coming back you see a lot of
people rap into certain [\h__\h] that feel a
certain way right so I said well damn
New York is known for a certain style
set but what if she did it on this type
of [\h__\h] I think this [\h__\h] would Flex
like both like I said both you got that
version you got the original and you got
these versions so but I can give you
multiple
ways of hearing it so like the first ver
what was the first
[Music]
one Donald
Trum that make watch my li off we are
not the same they a bunch of rip offs
[\h__\h] CH let that that L face car insane
in thatp gloss just that plain make them
watch my lip off we are not the they a
bunch
ofch
like
[Applause]
[Music]
yo
talk that PL J make watch my lift off we
are not the same they a bunch of rip off
[\h__\h] SL like that with
thatan
with that PL
my
my not same
[Music]
that PL chain watch my li off we are not
the same they buch
of on this version she's going we are
not the same Li off and she's going down
the other one she's going more up was
that you that do it that's crazy that's
crazy that's crazy it do it how I
prompted that's crazy that's crazy
that's crazy there was like a laugh in
it was that you too no it it just do it
just tell I to do all that [\h__\h]
wow damn see what I'm saying what's
crazy too is um like on the marketing
side over the last you know four or five
years especially we notice a lot of fans
don't mind consuming all these different
versions so you can just release all of
them exactly cuz I watch you feel
different on each one yeah yeah which is
crazy cuz I mean I could see a whole
consumer Behavior saying this is my
favorite song Thank you but I'mma play
it in different Vibes thank instead of
playing different songs like no I'm just
going to play this same song this one at
the party this one when I'm chilling
make sure you show this on your thing
exactly show that that this one at least
I Like You release your joint on
something like this and then me as fans
I just make my own version and I still
stream it and are you still get the
credit like whatever like it's crazy you
can have a whole album of one song yeah
yes and it would feel different every
time you press even though it's the same
like all the be I playing one
sample all them afro ones like just
different I just go through make a bu
that's yeah like like then I goes and
folder and make a
playlist then if I want stem and I'll
hit the button and say
stem it is I'm just telling people like
look I ain't I'm good at what I do I
know great like I played you I know know
how to make music any on anything I know
how to make it sound good on anywhere
but I feel like I'm just a small vessel
in this big ass ocean I'm a shark I
could be a Megalodon but I'm not the
newest Megalodon there's another
Megalodon that's bigger than me they
just don't know it yet they ain't they
ain't here
yet but you know how many Creative Kids
and people out there that are that are
amazing and especially us as culture
like how we think and that's why I'm
talking to like yo the language model
even with chat gbt just like trying to
say yo we have to learn
Urban has to learn an urban dialect like
cap don't no it's not a baseball cap is
it you have to tell is it Urban dialect
or are you you know whatever that is
right so that's where I'm at with it I'm
showing you music part but I'm into the
part to help for people such as us and
creators how we talk how do we look at
music that that a way that [\h__\h] hitting
all right so what is
that I'm trying to make that y'all job
easy cuz I'm I'm I'm doing the backend
stuff now constantly we me and him both
feedback now I need to change this we
need to it need to be this it need to do
this it need to do that and he do that
so it's like we when when it's out to
y'all y'all going crazy with it I'm like
y'all don't know the back end that we
put to that like the hours in
hours cuz like it wasn't sounding like
that yeah I just knew the potential what
it was
yeah I said yo this is this is this is
me producing on the
spot without my you need your computer
no bro need my damn phone I my my iPad
and be on two different ones and do two
different ones each
time then I can take I say if it's uh
murder on the be yo take that flip it m
here the F there you go put your sauce
on it now get that back to
me I said that let's make her go Afro
man this make let's take a middle
eastern afro
mix I ain't time wait for you here give
me
that cuz I got the prompt book I got the
got Book of
Eli you know saying like I I'm building
it that's all we do then I just take it
flip I said what if we
put and then I talk to the H guy soon
he's like what
if he will say that [\h__\h] he do right so
Atlanta right so when I do like the the
the ones I play with the 80 so it's like
so I said damn Atlanta have a swag but I
don't want to say Atlanta so you know
what I say zone
six getting close to my heart now see
you know what I'm saying everybody got
different style even in every barrel
every College Park that was Dungeon
Family so it's going to know the pull oh
you like from this era
mhm you understand M so like I give you
another promise let me play you
something else so I was saying like when
I was doing I said damn man I missed
that old
like
uh like Memphis right like the rap flow
in Memphis like a Memphis Style
[Music]
[Applause]
are
my
[Music]
my [\h__\h] what Persona is
that that's my good
Persona I ain't got no character with
those yet but that's my hood S I call it
hood and
mile that's my playlist Hood M like
black that felt like that was one
exactly one on got to one of the
ones I'm trying to tell people bro you
can't don't do that to me you going to
like all right go
what what you playing all right watch
this don't let me go to my pop
side that's a whole another
game that's a whole another that's some
other [\h__\h] right
[Music]
there the
ground the
[Music]
ground and
the all of
[Music]
[Applause]
I see know
like me going to on
me on the like come there put you on
your
[Music]
G I want you a
baby every time I life I'm going to get
you in
[Applause]
my you me
now you me now
[Applause]
it's
[Music]
[Applause]
all pass in my
eyes
cast to
bch for let me
[Music]
[\h__\h]
[Applause]
[Music]
Ain nobody [\h__\h] with me man I'm
trying to tell you man I produce on a
different level that's crazy just tell
you I got something for everybody any
time you like come [\h__\h] you better come
correct you come get me I'm going to
knock your head off yuck like i' I've
been in demos of
no you ain't like this [\h__\h] you you a you
ain't y'all need a cut of just how y'all
look on the couch
justu even the vocals the clarity of the
vocals is like it's not even like close
to other heard uhhuh yeah that's me
knowing that's us knowing yeah yeah yeah
[\h__\h] triple one was
like that Con Bro that's that's a hit
bro but that one right there
a that
boy we w we had we had look we watch
y'all go from the roller coaster to that
[\h__\h] just said drop down y'all yall
there now we there now there you go
Believers you better believe you better
believe the king I'm back 19 years old
in this body oh it's a rap bro you don't
want to go
get level up level up your [\h__\h] now come
on now all right so that was a portion
of a longer listening session with a lot
of Dope music that we didn't get to put
out but now we're going to transition to
timberin explaining his process and how
he looks at AI with a way deeper
perspective because it was important to
him for people to understand that this
is not some kind of push button magic
he's legitimately collaborating with the
AI he's digging through the crates
looking for sounds and still spending
hours in cases to build one beat so
you'll hear him talk about his
step-by-step process on what he's
actually doing to create this product
that you just saw you're also going to
hear him touch on a powerful concept
that he calls sampling yourself
something that I think is going to
change the game for a lot of artists and
explain the idea of personas so here's
what you need to understand when you go
back and listen to the pop section of
this video you heard artists on top of
the beat but those artists in all that
vocal Clarity were actually AI generated
and if you listen closely the lyrics
don't necessarily make sense so you
would kind of equate it to basically a
reference track from a Melody standpoint
think of an artist coming up with a idea
and they just hum it to a beat right and
then they record that and now they know
for later hey this is what we're going
to build off of that's kind of how you
want to think about it but listen to
this clip if you're really serious about
understanding AI if you're serious about
your music in general I think it's
important to hear timbering out here but
then also after you watch that second
portion
go back and watch the beginning watch
this listening session again with a
whole new perspective and I think things
are going to click a little bit
differently because what he's talking
about is way different than the Doom and
Gloom that people sell of AI completely
eliminating real artist because to be
frank AI alone can't do what he does and
the same goes for any real artist out
there what's up everybody it's no labels
necessary and we are here with timberin
and man y'all about to listen to a dope
video this listening session that we did
like timberin is going to be giving
y'all an exclusive playing stuff right
off of his playlist Real timbering Beats
however we need him to explain what's
going on here because this is not the
norm like he used AI but it's not like
what most people imagine in terms of his
process so Tim can you break this down
for us please okay I think it's I think
the best way to put it is the
celebration of humanity and
machine and it's like coexisting in the
same world so it still
takes what I'm playing you is another
way of producing and using the tools
that are available for us to use um AI
is not nothing to be afraid of it's
something to get used to and learn how
to create it's going to be the way of
elevating your business and 10x and what
you're trying to do and just moving
faster you know and at the end of the
day it might not be as fast to some
people but to each his own there there
is a tool that's available for you to
elevate your production and just really
get into your creative space because it
really you really think about it how
creative are you if I gave you uh if I
gave you a gift and say Hey you can make
every beat with your thought would you
take that gift of course you'll take
that gift now that gift is available to
you people get afraid of it and it's not
nothing to be afraid of it's something
to embrace and to really like dive into
your creativity because it's like
now a lot of things I feel like we were
limited and you know you really couldn't
do everything that you possibly could do
when you in the studio um and if you a
real big like you dream big and you
think big and you want to do everything
that's possible but sometimes like you
know everybody don't want to get on
Discord
sometimes and some people don't want to
fly or go places but they're sin and you
I know that's the whole game is sinning
thing so my thing is imagine if
you if before you sin you can do
complete your idea to the fullest and
then send it to that same person but
now that person you going add the choir
you already can put a choir to it right
so you can still send it to that person
that you want still to add the choir but
guess what you gonna spark his creative
juices and he gonna think well wait a
minute what if we add I'mma add this
part I'mma do this part on top of that
so it's just it's just a tool for me of
me producing like I I feel like I'm
always
evolving and I can I I always can start
a beat and make a beat but sometimes I
like to have the whole idea or I think
about the idea before I go to go press a
button but now that I have I can I can
actually communicate that idea before I
press the button and have a tool that
can do that that's like something I've
been waiting for my whole life you know
what I'm saying so it's a new way of me
producing versus me going to the
my Ableton to start first I can start
first or I can go to my Ableton pull up
a thought that I started and said okay
let me go let me let me collab with with
sunno um baby Timbo to see how I want to
make this flip so I'm like damn this a
dope ass sound but I actually want to
make this
sound be this way or make it sound like
a
um if it's a horn I wanteded to sound
like an African horn or like how I would
play in the backyard so it's like I can
describe those feelings that I that I
want and get that now with a with a tool
that's provided for me so to me I think
that's
like as a as a creative of my my caliber
that's just like that's the dream com
through you know I think
um the beauty about this tool that is
that shouldn't be so scary is it's it's
it doesn't copy anything it just learns
from Theory you know what I'm saying the
theory of what's already out there right
and I use it as I'm still doing what I
would normally do on my
Ableton then I upload it back to sunno
sunno gives me depending on my prompt
now and how I communicate and it still
acquires the biggest thing about this is
like with this tool is still the biggest
thing that it requires is human taste it
still requires your taste of what you
meaning that you can get I give you the
same the same thing you're not going to
produce what I
produce your taste and what you hear is
not my taste and what I hear so it's
going to give you something unique but
you still got to know if it's great or
not so anything that we do still
requires who you are it's still your DNA
it's like when I play you something it's
still Timberland DNA you know why
because my taste not just only Just My
Style everything about what I hear is is
is all me no matter where it's coming
from because I'm G be like oh that's
crazy that's crazy and a lot of people
gonna relate because it's just my
quality of what I hear music and how it
should be heard so I still need to know
how to communicate to this machine to
get out that timbering sound you know
what I'm saying it still has all these
elements in there but I got to know how
to to talk to it to get what I'm to get
my um the output that I need so it's
like understanding how to talk to it but
then when you say taste it makes me
think about like a Phineas B Billy ish's
brother they had one of the songs that
they did where I believe they were
listening to like a traffic light sound
in Australia and then they pulled that
sound put it in a beat and end up being
a part of a hit right I'm a part of the
beat right and the fact that everybody
hears that but he decided to pull it
that's basically the taste type of vibe
right like somebody saying I like that
sound it doesn't matter that y'all heard
it but I I felt it different right yeah
and it's it's it's a taste you know what
I'm saying like how it's How how you you
know it's like curation is going to be
big with this tool like you know what
I'm saying like I can give you a i you
can C curate something with the same
tool
but your ction could be it's going it's
it's not gonna sound like mine because I
hear different I think different you
know what I'm saying like Phineas thinks
different he hears different and he
gonna probably like damn I would have
prompt that too type of thing like you
know what I'm saying I was thinking the
same way so that's going to be another
language spoken in the creative world
and it's right now I'm probably like I'm
you know me I feel like I'm at the
Forefront of it all um but that's going
to be another way of communication in
the creative writer world you know what
I'm saying it's like people going to be
sharing prompts on how to get the best
out of this tool that we have you know
what I'm saying that's available for us
and that's going to make the beauty of
sound again because it's like what I
prompt and what you prompt gonna be two
different things and it's going to be
one
onone so it's not like you're going to
get it again you know what I'm saying
you just not and after after the same
thing when it comes to music you just
don't get the same thing again it's like
I'm not going you're not going to get
another Metro beat you know what I'm
saying this Metro is how he created that
like you you can try to create it which
you can duplicate if you finally pick
the sounds but you can hit you can tell
from the original you know what I'm
saying right right yeah that's
interesting man you talk about how
important the the prompts are going to
be and I mean since we kind of did that
that first session I was able to dive
into sunno a lot more and I think the
biggest thing that was surprising to me
is is how descriptive you have to be to
even get something that's that's decent
right like it's not as simple as go as
going in and saying make a dope trap
beat right it's like you have to be I
want ethereal drums with you know a boom
in Basse with these type of instruments
kind of like you were mapping out so I'm
wondering hearing the music and let's
say the terminology of of feelings or um
just kind of the I guess these these
descriptors for the music and the
instruments is that something that you
were kind of thinking about even prior
to the tool or what did sunno or did you
have to train yourself to kind of see
music in those words to to be able to
translate your skills as soono that's a
good question to for me it's like a high
learn of production it's like am I
really that great could I describe could
could I translate what I'm hearing and
what I'm feeling into words what words
would it pick what words would me and
the Machine collaborate on so to me is
like
it's it's it's it's a different way of
translating my music so it's like I'm
elevating myself you know what I'm
saying and I agree with you it is that
you can't just go you have to be kind of
detailed and at the same time
is you also training too because you
like no that's not what that means and
it'll spit out certain things that you
think would you think it how you know
how it should sound but it's not
spitting out what it what it sound so
that means you have to keep working with
it and maybe just maybe flip the words
around or maybe when a cap a capital A
uh or capital T for trap could could
translate better for the machine you
know versus the lowercase T you know
it's it's those little elements it's
like it you
know it's really like just elevating
your mind you know what I'm saying it's
like it's it's your thoughts it's
like it's going to the next level
creativity you know for like I said for
some people it's not going to
be uh it might be the last thing they go
to or it might be the third thing or the
second thing or some people the first it
all depends on your taste of how you
create you know what I'm saying for me
it like it speeds up time for me when it
comes to create creativity and force
finding uh say you know I can make my
own records but then also can present I
feel like there a expensive way
presenting
artist instead of this beat you can
present them a
whole uh you could curate a whole
playlist for
them you uh you said something like one
the language that the artists are gonna
be speaking in now like it's going to is
a whole another language and then when
you talked about a capital T versus
lowercase T all that together makes me
think more from a programming standpoint
where one little apostrophe you know
what I mean addition no letter Etc can
change an entire program it can break it
you know it can make it technically
right so is it really that like
sensitive it's it's it it's it's it's
not it's not now but at the beginning
stages that's how fast it's growing at
the beginning stages it was kind of like
oh this comma and and it does work you
can pray you can say 808 808 three four
times right so it knows like okay I got
to add 808 you know what I'm saying like
it's almost like saying don't forget to
like you going to engineer man cut my
808 up man cut my 808 so now you instead
of saying it you typing it cut my 808 up
cut my 808 up right so it's now it's not
as from where it started to where it's
at now it's getting a little bit more
simpler got but I think I like the
nuances because it makes it like you
know playing a game chess it's like oh
you didn't think of that
oh that's why why that high head a't go
and it's like how you get your high
heads like that you know it's like
anything you know you could see it6
132 but it's like if I can give you a a
symbol that can get 116 132 which you
know it's which one you prefer you know
what I'm saying it's like yo give me the
symbol to make that [\h__\h] do this triplet
you know what I'm saying or this
whatever I think it's it's what you
prefer I think you know it's a tool that
allows you to go beyond what you
thinking goog can you give us a
breakdown of like or a walk through of
your collaboration with sunno step by
step like am I you start at the doll you
do X Y and Z and then at what point you
go over there then you go back because I
remember you talking Do It um but I want
people to understand okay the first
thing is I do is I say I go on to my
Ableton I go through certain like I go
through my patterns right or certain
sounds or pattern that I like and then
um there's a couple like say some s Loop
makers or you know yeah Loop makers and
so I might find a loop and it's only
like a couple people that I like their
Loops right so I might find a a loop so
I started maybe on Ableton a little bit
right or I could just
take the pattern might give me a simple
boom boom boom and then I put the loop
on top of or whatever the beat so I
already have those beats already done
from my Ableton correct so I these are
like beats that I have just stashed so I
go to like my my folders and load up a
beat and um I trans I transfer it to my
phone or to my computer which on my
usually I do it for my phone because I
like to move around so I just download
it to my Dropbox on my phone and then I
because you can put the app I mean the
app is is on the browser and on the you
know and it's a app so I put it on I put
it back and upload it back
intoo I prompt it a certain way because
I know what I how I want this sound to
be and what I want it to be so my prompt
is are very
like very accurate so it kind of
knows to elevate what I just gave it you
know what I'm saying on what I prompt so
I I take that beat put it in it gives it
back I sit there and generate like Noah
I think the snare should go over to the
left so I might prompt it a certain way
until it gives me back then I put it
back over then I get what I like I put
it back over in Ableton and start
playing with like the EQ and really
busting it down and adding to it but
it's like I done got four of them at
once instead of like one that I'm
working on you know what I'm saying and
it's like inspiring me like oh [\h__\h] I
hear it this way yeah now let me put it
back over here and tweak this and do
that so it's like
it's like a companion you know what I'm
saying it's like I do I could do it over
here or I could start I could start with
just most of the time I could start with
just a loop you know what I'm saying and
I can say hey drum should go here this
could go there it's all about my prompt
and the style that I wanted you know so
I could real simple words certain
language and it it gives me back a cool
idea then I can take that idea and send
it over over to my Sado or my Ableton
and start is chopping it up and doing
what I
do you know what I'm saying it's like
it's a it's a great collaborator you
know what I'm saying I feel like
somebody said it best they was like yo
start sampling
yourself you know what I'm saying start
making your own Loops you have this tool
to do that so this kid I saw on his page
he got on soono he started doing he's
like yo then he put it back in Sado
and start adding his own you know adding
sauce to it but he's like damn I just
made my own I just made 15 Loops out of
this one
sound you know what I'm saying so it's
like it's a it's it's a amazing tool
once you get all the way engag to it but
that's those are the steps how I use it
you know what I'm saying and I'm always
finding new ways but the best way to say
is like I still use the dog I don't I
don't I don't never I'm not rep it's not
replacing in the doll it just I'm just I
have two dolls now you know what I'm
saying I can go here or go there and add
them all together yeah I think that
changes people's perspective a lot
because when you think about AI music AI
beats or whatever immediately your mind
is going to well the AI just creates all
of it right but you cut all of that in
its head uh once you say I'm sampling
myself right the fact that you you are
giving it references which is you that
you created something me it's learning
me in a better way exactly so it's no
way for ours to be the same no so like I
I I don't believe in like it's it's cool
it's almost like a I know that part
where people say the creat of music
that's like the fun tool of person who
don't make music you know what I'm
saying they can probably make some and
it's going to spit out but it's you got
to treat this as like it's you you got
to give it you got to give it you you
know what I'm saying it's not going to
know you you have to give the machine
your taste of what you what is looking
for us so once it know that like oh we
trying to do this we trying to elevate
from here all right let's go so what's
the prompt what what are we doing how
you want me to flip it you want me to
take this lay over you want me to put
the more 808 you want me to make it this
or you want me to make that [\h__\h] sound
like it's Latin I said yeah we gonna put
something like we're gonna make it regay
tone take this same oh so take your
drums that's already there just swapping
around exactly got you got you and then
that's another big thing because in the
listening session you go through a bunch
of different genres and you talk about
your personas
can you just break down like from a
technical standpoint how people should
think about personas or use that type of
idea as a tool okay so this is the thing
like the personas like those are just
tone tations right and and I I gotta say
s has some of the best P personas but it
it that spits out and it gives you but
it all depends on like it all depends on
um like it might pick up a Persona that
has a the a a train or like you know
what I'm saying it might be the area you
might say Nashville um Memphis and it
might give you a Persona that's from
Memphis that's from or like a sound that
how Memphis person talks so that's it's
all about the personas is is is going to
be like it's going to give you depending
on what your prompt is right because
some some of the person GNA be hit or
miss and the beauty about it is it pick
a Persona that
fits what you prompt it the the track to
be you know what I'm saying so and the
ill part about sunno is you can save the
Persona the one that you like so for me
you know as I'm breaking the thing in
and working with it
um I have made picked some great
personas and save some great personas
and started
developing like different tracks around
those personas you know what I'm saying
it's almost like
having a whole a whole session in your
house when you don't got nobody
everybody could be gone out of the
country you like look God I gotta pull
my Persona up and work with you know
what I'm saying and do this and do that
and you can keep that Persona add to
what you you know what I'm saying you
add it to your original vocals or how
you want to do it it's it's it's amazing
so when people listen to this music
right in your playlist they'll hear some
voices some people singing like those
are the anas can you explain like where
the The Melodies that they're saying or
and the language or the words that
they're saying is coming
from the language the language is well
it depending on the the genre a lot of
the times like a lot of um you know if
you listen to Latin music and in Nigeria
and all these countries it's like it's
different language barriers
so if I'm if I'm doing a dimbo it's
going to give me Latin laor it's going
to give me a Latin
Persona because it knows but then it
don't right so it's all about if you PR
words for it to say so sometimes it has
a button what that instrumental you
could do instrumental or you can give
you different Cadence and that goes on
your prompts too so you can when you
write up the word you can write yeah but
how would you write yeah in the song how
would you say it so it's like the way
you just type and it's simple but it's
like the little spacing and what you say
kind of prompts the Persona that it's
going to give out you know what I'm
saying and like and then the
sound it's kind of you it's kind of
amazing how it knows where to drop put
in take out blend in and you got to know
like what type of flow of you looking
for because Cades are different they are
they're playful they're like vulnerable
Cadence they're more silent they're like
with Cadance you know what I'm saying
those terminologies that can help out
with the Persona and what you get you
know what I'm saying the thing about it
towards the
flow it
understands it understands
like where to place things I can't
really explain how but it just sometimes
it's like it just a taste you know what
I'm saying it's because it it can it'll
generate bull crap you know what I'm
saying like it's not it's not it don't
come out like that the first time you
got to sit and play with it and move it
around and keep generating the thing
about it is you can keep generating you
know what I'm saying you can keep there
nothing to stopping you just hit hit of
a button oh let me change this word oh
let me Pro all this that and it would
give it just
knows what fits what I can't explain how
it knows but it it just knows and once
like because you can look at your prompt
and be like okay you automatically feel
what it should be and it kind of gives
you what you feel so it's like it's it's
it's it's I think it's amazing too
because you
can't you can't really dictate the flow
but it knows to give it a flow from what
you fed it like the music that I gave it
is like got that Timbo so it knows
how that okay this should have this on
it all right so in this last segment of
the interview Timlin is going to explain
how he remixes artist music using this
feature called covers and to be clear
when you go back to the beginning of
this video the part of the listening
session we're showing is an artist by
the name of London Reed that's a real
artist that is not an AI artist she sent
one song over to him after he made the
beat you know the typical process but
after they got to that part where you
hear the original everything after that
is Timlin using the process that he's
about to explain now you know this this
feature that's on soono called covers so
cover is really like it allows you it's
really like a remix button right that's
what I call it it's
like you can so this girl gave me the
song London
Hill I Love the I love the song I love
where it was going but I also heard it
in a different way so I uploaded in
covers and prompted the way that I
thought it should go or I want to hear
different different styles of this song
so whato does it it it it hears it it
prints out the lyrics it reads out the
lyrics and only thing I have to do is
prompt in the style that I want to remix
it in and how I want to remix it and
what I want
so that's really it that's really like
it's no hard steps to it it's just you
thinking of the style you think it
should be so it'll take
elements that are already there from the
original like the producer who did it
right so it know this is the sounds that
it that that you uh uploaded and it
it'll rearrange it on your prompting you
know what I'm saying and maybe adding
and taking Parts away and adding new
parts changing this and the ill part
about it it it
changes her flow it makes it according
to the Trum So like like as as I'm
playing it you're going to hear
different inflictions in her voice some
go high some go low it as the beat as I
changing what I want the beat to sound
like and what
style it gives it it dispens it back
accurately as you it's crazy how it
interprets it back because it's not like
it understands what has been uploaded
and it gives you
back something that's amazing when it
when it's done generating