Music videos might be the most expensive
lottery ticket in the music industry and
artists are scratching them off with the
wrong coin. And there's been a pretty
heated debate in music about if music
videos are dead. But I think before we
can really get into that conversation
and start to understand things from both
sides, we got to make sure we know
what's really happening behind the
scenes. So, let's start here.
>> People keep asking me if I think that
music videos are dead as a music video
director. Personal opinion is yes, no,
and kind of. labels have been spending
less and less on music videos, which
means that there's been a bunch of like
more mediocre music videos that have
arisen in the last 10 years. That
reason, when social media took over,
those music videos kind of slip to the
back in terms of efficiency in reaching
a new audience. However, performance is
always going to be something that
audiences want to see from their
artists. Like, we get excited about
seeing Beyonce in concert because she
sets a precedent in her music videos.
But simultaneously, times have evolved
and content is king and everybody's
attention is on their phone. So, this
means that our jobs as music video
directors are still very much needed,
but they have kind of changed. Need to
be able to take all of the creative
storytelling skills that we remember
from the kind of more traditional music
videos and reapply that into vertical
video content. What I'm personally
seeing at the moment is that they're
kind of three tiers of music promotion
visuals. Bottom tier is the kind of
really lowmaintenance content. like an
artist can literally post up their
camera and then perform the their verse
to camera and put lyrics on the screen
and they will get a bunch of views from
that and get a lot of new audience. I
will say that as we continue to see more
of this though, there's going to be a
need for artists to get more creative
with that kind of content, thus still
needing some kind of visual creative
director. That kind of content is great
for getting new audience in the door,
but what about keeping audience and
making audience obsessed with you and
turning them into megapans? And that's
where the second tier of visual music
promotion comes in. And this is kind of
like the newest form of music video that
we've ever seen in the last kind of 10
years. I'm seeing lots of artists put
their own take on this. But essentially,
like we're talking about Tik Tokified
music videos, Instagramified music
videos, you know, like all the
creativity and the performance level of
what we used to put in like a
traditional music video, but curated and
compacted into a vertical format. I
think this would rely heavily on things
like transitions and visual effects and
kind of camera tricks. All types of
things that we've come to develop an
appetite for as a social media audience.
And finally, the third tier is the full
scale music video productions, like the
more traditional music videos that we
know of. So, all artists are going to
have to be able to do all three.
>> And the thing is, it's not just the
directors who are saying that music
videos don't have the same value.
Artists are actually saying it, too.
>> I shot a music video for this feature
that I'm on with a label. Their budget
was $80,000. [music]
We shot a $80,000 video that me and my
homie could have shot for $1,000. And I
was like, "Damn, the label spent 80,000
on this." Then the label didn't like it
and they scrapped the video then. So
they hired another videographer and they
paid 30 grand for that video. So they
spent that much money plus they flew me
out, plus they paid me to be on the
song. All this different [\h__\h] And I'm
just thinking like then their album came
out, they sold 5,000 copies. They didn't
even recoup for that one thing. So, it's
like, and at the end of the day, those
artists will never get paid because the
label chose to make these decisions for
them.
>> And see, that's the real frustration.
Artists are still putting time,
creativity, money, and energy into these
music videos, and they feel like they're
not seeing the return they deserve on
it. Basically, they're starting to feel
like the results don't match the effort.
And it's not that music videos are
useless, it's just that the music
industry doesn't move in the way that it
used to, but a lot of artists still
think it does. And I think that's about
to get really clear moving forward in
this video. So that yes no kind of is
probably the realest summary you're
going to hear about this whole thing
because in 2025 and possibly moving
forward, music videos are dead if you
are still someone that's spending
thousands of dollars to multiple tens of
thousands hoping that it'll blow up like
it's 2012. But also not dead if you're
using them for creativity and
storytelling and world building. And
they're kind of dead as a song promotion
engine. like it's not the main engine
like it was 5 10 years ago. But here's
the real turning point. The internet and
fans are starting to do the job that
music videos used to do. Let me show you
a moment within many moments that
explains this whole shift.
>> Call me that. [music]
>> Don't call you that. Don't call you
what.
>> So, I'm sure by now we've all seen the
viral clip that was taken over Tik Tok a
few months ago. And I think this right
here is a little bit of everything,
right? This is a Kendrick Lamar song
that has no music video. I don't believe
it's ever had a music video come out.
Uh, they got a completely new life
because of a fan-made song, right?
Another producer made this song using
his vocals. He's probably a Kendrick
Lamar fan. And what's even better is
that that fan probably wasn't even
thinking about promoting Kendrick Lamar,
right? But then that song got picked up
by another fan of both Creed and
Kendrick Lamar and of this song
obviously, right? And created something
that went further than probably most
music videos will ever go because if we
actually started digging into numbers,
right? Like this this clip right here
has 28 million views which is crazy. And
if we go take a look at the actual song
which was created by the producer uh
Lovi the song has 5.8 million views
within a year right compared to the
original Untitled Five by Kendra Lamar
which has 4.3 million views across seven
years. So I think this whole situation
kind of proves two things at once. One,
songs can go viral without a music
video, right? Like that Kendrick Lamar
song was literally resurrected because
somebody made fan-made visuals to it.
Which actually brings me to two, fan
edits and just social media content in
general can massively outperform a music
video. Once again, that one edit for
that Kendrick Lamar song, you know what
I'm saying, probably did more for
Kendrick and that producer than any
$30,000 $100,000 music video could ever
do. And this is, I think, one of many
moments where the industry started to
realize that the power doesn't
necessarily live in the music video
anymore. It lives in clips. It lives in
remixes. It lives in influencer
campaigns. And it also lives in fan
culture and short form storytelling,
which brings us straight to the people
on the front lines. Okay, so if a song
can blow up without music videos and fan
edits can possibly carry more weight
than a music video that was paid for by
a label, that just makes me wonder what
do the people who work social media
actually think about all of this.
>> Yeah, you see, I got to make this [\h__\h]
again cuz y'all didn't hear me the first
time. But uh yeah, if you're a music
artist in 2025 and you still prioritize
music videos, like fulllength music
videos, you're [\h__\h] I I'm not I'm not
kidding. I'm not saying that [\h__\h] for
clickbait. You're legitimately [\h__\h]
Um, so [music] for context, I'm a social
media manager. I study all this [\h__\h]
whatever. I work with different brands,
creators, some artists, whatever. And
um, yeah, everyone should be
prioritizing short form platforms. IG,
Tik Tok, those will be your best
friends. The amount of time that it
takes for you to produce anything on
YouTube or like any fulllength long-
form video is not worth it for an
independent [music] artist right now.
And I feel like you guys kind of know
that, but it's just the whole, oh, like
I'm an artist. I'm not a content
creator. like that whole that whole
dynamic that y'all got going on. Yeah.
Um, suck it up cuz this [\h__\h] is here to
stay. Like, [music] and here's two
really good examples right here. Like,
they do this [\h__\h] for real. So, like
there is a way to still be an artist but
still make content consistently. Like,
really think about it. For as [music]
long as it takes for you to sit down and
plan and organize and then execute and
then market a long form video like a
music video, that takes [music] way too
much [\h__\h] time. The name of the game
now for media consumption across the
[music] board is output. If you cannot
put [\h__\h] out at a quick rate, you are
[\h__\h] So all that [\h__\h] that you was
doing with like you taking 3 months to
come out with one music video and then
like you get 500 views to 1,000 views
and then everything stops there, that's
not doing [\h__\h] for you, bro. You're not
going to grow. You're not going to
become a full-time artist. So uh yeah,
bro, get to work. Like the [\h__\h]
>> So you heard, bro. If you're using music
videos as your primary marketing
strategy in 2025 in the foreseeable
future, then yeah, I ain't even going to
lie, it's hard for you and it's not
going to get any easier anytime soon.
And I think he articulated it really
well, right? Like artists are used to
seeing music videos as these kind of
like grand productions and grand
projections of their the artistic vision
and and the visual elements that tie to
the song. Whereas we live in a consumer
market that wants, you know what I'm
saying, popping [\h__\h] every day, you
know, if you can possibly produce it.
And if you look at the internet outside
of just the music landscape, there are
content creators who are giving fans
that type of experience on the internet,
right? Like I've said it in many videos
before, I've come across Tik Toks and
YouTube uh shorts and Instagram reels
that the production quality only look
like some [\h__\h] that was coming from a
major network. So when I as a fan, as a
consumer, see these other creators who
were able to put together really
creative, really high quality pieces of
content in in a you know what I'm
saying, a short time frame, then when I
look at, you know, music artists and I'm
like, "Hey, bro, why we got to wait
until January to get that music video
and it's October?" Like, why you can't
work on something that that can come out
now? And I can already hear you guys in
the comments, right? Corey, you just a
marketer. Bro is just a marketer. Y'all
don't understand the artist plight, bro.
Y'all don't know what's up. And if
that's the case, maybe you'll listen to
it from an artist who built his entire
career off of doing it the new way.
>> I still only believe in short form
content. I do not think a music video is
going to blow your song up. I don't
think you should invest in music videos
unless the song earns one. You're doing
your short form content and you're
promoting your your your original music
on Tik Tok, on reals, on shorts. Then
when a song has a moment, you know, it
it earns a music video. It earns more
content. Like this is the mindset shift.
And honestly, I think the shift that's
going to keep a lot of artists from
going broke trying to put visuals out
because before and even with some
artists today, right, they believe that
every song should get a music video.
Every song deserves to be beautifully
captured and and presented to the world
in a nice bow. But in this current
landscape, only winning songs should
earn a music video or ones that you feel
like really tie back to your lore and
your world and need that extra artistic
push. But this next clip, I think, ties
it all together.
>> Matt Kabashi asks me, "Now, if you drop
52 songs, should you be doing visuals to
all 52 as well?" Mac, the answer is no.
Music videos just don't have the power
that they used to. We're not in TRL
days, the 106 and Park days. We're not
even in the YouTube days. Now, music is
one of the smallest revenue generators
on YouTube. Where we are right now is in
the content era. You need to be putting
content around all 52 songs. And so I'm
not even talking about 52 pieces of
content. For every song you put out, you
need to put out 10, 20, 30 pieces of
content around that song. Whether it be
content you made on your iPhone or you
got with a videographer and you shot
60-second clips the same way you would
shoot a music video, but you're shooting
it for social media. That's how we're
doing it right now. We're putting
content around our songs and that's how
we're gaining exposure for that music.
Now, if the song begins to work very
well, then you take the money that you
have in the budget and you put it into a
music video and you spread that song
even more. But don't do it from the
beginning. Wait and see how the song
does via your content and then shoot a
music video if it begins to work.
>> And here we have it. One of the rare
moments when an artist and a label exec
agrees on something because they both
just gave you the same blueprint in
different language. Create short form
content around your music to figure out
which song is the song. Watch how fans
react to that song and amplify it. And
if it hits, then drop a music video to
expand the world and the universe around
that song. So, when you really start to
think about it, music videos haven't
died. Their job description just changed
a little bit. And I think that no one
explains the purpose, the kind of inner
working of the purpose of a visual
better than Tyler the Creator. So for
me, like you said, forget the piano and
the strings. It's But I write songs. So
like for me, it's the frame, it's the
it's the texture of the brush, it's the
colors. It's not just like you don't
just read my lyrics and be like, "Oh, I
get it." Like I'm not that type of
rapper. Like you watch the video and
hear the beat and hear when the drums
leave and how I'm moving and you like,
"Oh." That's why I like people seeing me
live cuz it's like, "Oh, we New Magic
Wand. It's number six off my Egor album.
It's my favorite song I've made to
date." That song wasn't as popular as it
was when it first came out. That was a
slow burner. And every time I perform
that song, I let people know, hey, this
is my favorite song before I do this
song. And people would see that song
live and see the energy, see how it
felt, whether it's the fire, see how my
legs move. And that song start gaining
traction and popularity because it gave
some people context. [music] And a lot
of people who didn't like that song said
they saw it live and was like, "Damn, I
understand it now." So when you're like,
"Well, has your writing got better?"
Yes, because I've also gotten better
musically. So, for me, it's not just
lyrics. I don't think I'm like a Earl
sweatshirt or like a gaze or something
like like I'm a you got to look at the
whole thing when it comes to me.
>> And I think this is the missing piece in
the whole argument. The part that some
of the detractors and the people who
don't believe in music videos really
seem to forget because what Tyler is
saying is that my identity isn't fully
expressed through audio. You have to see
me to completely understand me. And I
think that that's a very real, very fair
point to make, especially in this new
era that we're living in where everybody
is hyperfocused on world building and
artists as characters and unique
experiences and things like that. And so
when I hear artists like Tyler say that,
it makes me think that music videos
aren't dying, right? But maybe basic
music videos are dying. So videos with
no concept, videos with no identity,
videos that you can tell were just
dropped by the artist to be able to say,
"Hey, I put something out." I think it's
fair to say that those videos are
bleeding out on the floor as we speak.
But the videos that deepen your world,
your character, your aesthetic, your
values, your universe, those are
priceless and are probably going to be
here for a very long time. So, here's
how I think you should think about music
videos uh in 2025 and moving forward.
Number one, don't start your roll out
with a music video. Start off with 10 to
30 short form clips. You know, these can
be things that were really simply shot.
These could be pieces of content that
have strong visuals and concepts behind
them, but are taking less time and less
of your budget than a music video would.
Start here. Use this to promote the song
and kick off your ad funnels and see
where things start to go. Which actually
leads into my second point, which is
watch what the internet gravitates to.
Fans will tell you what song matters and
deserves that attention. Hell, if the
song blows up enough, strangers will
tell you what song matters and deserves
all of that attention. And if you see a
fan edit taking off or a particular
piece of content doing better compared
to your other pieces of content or you
start to see the song grow on DSPs or
all these little signs that start to let
you know that hey this song is the one
then congratulations that song has now
earned a music video. And my last tip is
make your music videos be extensions of
your world building, right? Like don't
create them solely for the purpose of
marketing looking for an exact dollar
ROI on it. These music videos should
introduce a era or reveal a character or
deepen the mythology and lore that
you've been building around your your
artist persona. Or it should be
literally showing the universe that your
fans will be living inside of. Cuz music
videos are no longer the spark for
attention, right? Or in most cases, it's
not going to be. But they're still an
explanation. An explanation of you, your
world, and what you want us to believe
about what you're trying to bring us
into. And if you're watching this
thinking, "Bro, I don't even have a
world for my music yet." We can help
with that. For the first time, we're
offering artist worldbuilding strategy
calls. And on these calls, we'll help
you do things like build your character
or build your visual identity or design
an era or come up with the look and feel
of your artist universe. So, if you
already know that your music is good and
you've gotten proof that your music is
good, but the look, the feel, the brand,
the world, all of that is missing, then
this is the thing that will help you fix
that. So, if you're interested, link is
in the description below. So, once
again, music videos aren't dead, they've
just evolved. Short form content from
the artist helps to build momentum. Fan
edits and influencers help to shape and
create culture. And the music videos are
the big explosion that help to define
the identity. Or at least that's what I
think. But let me know your thoughts in
the comments section below. Do you think
that music videos are dead and they're
pretty much a waste of an artist's time
and budget at this point? Or do you
still feel like music videos are the
holy grail of content and artists should
be looking to make music videos for most
of their releases? Other than that, if
you like this video, make sure you hit
that like button, subscribe, share this
with an artist that needs a little bit
of gain today. My name is Corey and I'll
see y'all next