all right next topic man we got some
some sauce from the Brandman Network
Community just another great
conversation again for y'all who do not
know Brandman network is a community
that's free for the artists out there
um we have these conversations here but
this is where we get into the details
not just through conversations by um
through what I'm about to talk about
right now but also through legitimate
classes information that walks you step
by step so when you want to step by step
the exact strategies we use as an agency
all that stuff's free inside of here but
you got to join
um and we're not letting everybody in so
it's better to try to get in sooner than
later now
what is the question
I don't know how to say this name I want
to shout you out but I'm gonna just call
you Jay Quito you know what I mean now
the question is what to do when labels
Reach Out
and I want to get into this conversation
let me pull up the right tab there we go
hi guys I have some labels reach out to
me to have a meeting and possibly get
signed to them I'm pretty new to all of
that I was wondering if anybody else has
advice on what to do when labels reach
out and are they are there any red flags
I should be looking out for
all right Ty Towson said hey don't have
advice particularly on the above but
wanted to say I'm feeling what you did
for what you mad for that's one of his
songs I assume shout out to dang I wish
I could say your name but what you mad
for shout out to you for having a dope
track to people in the network mess with
now Albert Johnson Jr says I was
approached by an indie label back in
2020 but it was such a wild situation
they ended up breathing there I think he
meant to say breaching they ended up
breaching their own contract because
they were harassing me about switching
all of my previously released work under
their publishing with BMI well I would
say because I didn't know anything or
had anyone to have anybody talk to at
the time make sure that they're not
trying to get credit for everything
you've already released right so he's
saying you've done things before you
gotten in agreement with them make sure
that they're not trying to get ownership
of all of that stuff as a part of your
agreement or at least if they are y'all
need to talk about that right next thing
that Albert Johnson Jr said and if
they're asking for your Masters off rip
that's a red flag all right might be
obvious to some of y'all but just wanted
to say now
let's stop there because we know there's
more dope conversation in this space but
with that alone jakori what do you think
about
the advice that Albert gave and then are
some other thoughts and signs that you
feel like people should take into
account what labels reach out yeah I
think Albert's Albert let me read it
real quick yeah I was ever's uh comment
was legit so I mean I think it's about
breaking it down into steps right and I
think that if a label reaches out to you
one of the first things you should do is
research and one just look into that
label and make sure hey is is this label
legit yep is the person that's reaching
out to me from the label legit
um you can do this to a number of ways
right like LinkedIn like look up people
on LinkedIn Google the person's name and
the label name and see if any articles
any references come up that around that
person but like just do research and
make sure that this person this entity
is someone that's worth you talking to
and they're offering you a serious a
serious um situation so with that being
said I'm assuming we're going to move to
the rest of the conversation assuming
this is a legit label that's reached out
to you all right to talk to you
um I think the very first thing you need
to do is just take the call like take
the have a conversation with them
because
every
label person is different
the way they're going to kind of
approach things is going to be different
but I I personally believe that you
don't start to see how seriously someone
is thinking about you and their
situation until you get a chance to
actually have a conversation right not
saying you have to go into it with any
expectations that'll be something
that happens at the end of it but like
just having it just to see how this
other person talks to you or talks about
you or just kind of what their head is
at right why do they even reach out to
you oh we saw XYZ and we thought you
were cool that right there bro like
that's the biggest thing why I say
everybody should have a conversation
yeah right because when you talk to
these people you're gonna learn what
they look at yep right what they find to
be interesting about you and just hear
other elements in the game that you
might not be accustomed to or you might
have heard on paper but you don't see
how it act
um is executed in conversation right
it's a completely different flowing part
of the game to get used to and then you
talk to multiple people if you're in a
position where multiple people are
calling you then you can start looking
at commonalities between conversations
and piecing things together and involve
your perspective on things from there
yeah exactly exactly that's the biggest
kid like even if nothing comes out of
the situation you have a better
understanding of how these people move
for the next time you get into this
situation other than the next neighbor
that reaches out so it's like every
conversation you have strengthens your
defense of giving finesse I'm saying
ideally because either you're taking
enough information to at least know like
the right questions to ask the next
person you talk to right at the very
very minimum like you should learn
enough from call a then by the time you
get the call D you already got a list of
things you're gonna ask the kind of I
feel the situation out right right
um but then on top of that thing also
too just like being normal in this
situation is very underrated right like
I see artists get these label calls and
I just throw every [\h__\h] thing out the
window bro all the the rhetoric they've
been talking for the last couple of
weeks goes out the window they're
talking about doing things that would
never typically do but I need you to be
detailed because I don't want people to
miss what you're saying like what do you
mean when you say like they're talking
about things they never would talk about
or do things they'll never would do are
you talking the label side or the artist
side artist side Okay so
I remember we had a situation with a
client where the label was telling them
to like they might have to take their
music down or something right and like
this person was seriously considering
doing it because the label told them
doing we like well bro you ain't even
signed nothing yet one you know what I'm
saying like so that's crazy and then two
like no they're wrong in the situation
for how it benefits you they're right
for high benefits of them but they're
wrong and how it benefits you know what
I'm saying and so but I think a lot of
artists just are willing to be super
compromising out the gate without even
like one just saying if they're serious
and then two like understanding like
what could happen if they do follow the
direction of this person who to be fair
does not yet have your best interest at
heart there's no reason to have your
best interest at heart you ain't signed
nothing yet yeah you know what I'm
saying so it's like I can sell you the
dream and it sounds good but like who
knows if this is the dream I want to
sell you once the ink drops right that
dream I completely switch up I got you
man that's what the real [\h__\h] is about
to go down you know I'm saying so I
think just like
being normal in those situations not not
switching up too much but then just like
talking to them like their people you
know because I do also think all right
as artists you go into a lot of these
conversations looking at the other
person is almost like a savior
especially a r but a R's managers I
reckon to some degree as marketers we
get that but we all get the Starry Eyes
bro they staring at you and you just see
all their hopes and dreams being
projected onto you you know what I'm
saying that's a scary feeling to be on
the other side of you know I'm saying
um you know Superstar is that could not
bro this is scary that's a scary feeling
to have that that was I was looking back
at you so I think even going to this
situation like hey this is a another
human being like we mentioned on another
car versus just a person doing the job
right and understanding that and knowing
that like I'm not going to treat this
person
any differently because of their tile
necessarily I think one is is empowering
in a sense because people can smell like
desperation on you bro you you've been
too nice you you moving a certain way
like I can smell desperation or two
which I think is worse smell that you
have not been in this situation before
right like you being too friendly on the
car Bro you've been too talking over
I've been looking at you for XYZ amount
of years and I think right like you like
moving in a ways of like if I'm an
artist 100 conversations with artists
this week who are maybe a little bit
higher than you like they they all go a
certain way very concise you'll say
maybe to the point you know I'm saying
not too much sugar coating maybe versus
you know newer artists like there's
gonna be a lot of sugarcoat because I
can tell this is your first time being
in the situation I'm not trying to scare
you away from what could be you know my
career change or opportunity you know
I'm saying I'm a string you're a long
through lines the way that I know people
like you can be can be strong along you
know just to be real you know I'm saying
I'll just be 100 so I think um yeah like
one thing is just like not to God the
habit of that but yeah the first step I
said is like take the conversation like
talk to them see what they want from you
ask them what made them reach out to you
you know like you said get an
understanding of what bread crumbs they
follow to get to you and and because in
that you will learn like what your
leverage points are right like you
smiling myself like man yeah bro I I
wanted to reach out to you because like
bro I think you're
I'm gonna get YouTube content strategies
like killer bro like should you doing
better than all the new acts we've
talked to this week you didn't know that
you know I'm saying today said that bro
now you know like okay hmm they really
like my my content infrastructure that
seems to be a selling point and
apparently I'm doing bad in x amount of
the new [\h__\h] that's come in
right new information that you would not
have had new contact you would not have
had if you had you not taking the
conversation so I think that's the most
important First Step take the
conversation set that up as fast as you
can there doesn't have to be any
stipulations that doesn't need to be a
specific outcome but it's like just try
to have a conversation as fast as you
can't have a conversation I'm with that
100 yeah 100 and we can get into another
comment in the space Adrian milanio says
I have had labels reach out at every
stage of my career 1500 followers 10K
followers 30k Etc the types of deals and
interest has varied for me I've done a
few deals where labels have provided
advances marketing support and chat
exchange for royalties percentages
in my opinion I think it's better to
keep building until you don't need a
label and can leverage better deals now
just with a little context I'm not not
going to go too deep into Adrian's
situations but on one occasion all right
he had a singles deal
and I only mentioned a singles deal
to help artists understand that yo man
like there's so many different
variations of deals so a lot of times we
think signing to a record label means
I don't know a 360 every single time
giving up the whole damn [\h__\h] yeah right
or give less of the [\h__\h] because you
really negotiated well right yeah but
there are so many variations of where
income can come from where income can't
come from what what's owned so you could
just make up some [\h__\h] like hey man you
get 50 of my masters and nothing else I
don't know or you could say you get uh
20 of my merch and 50 of my masters and
I don't know zero percent of my touring
or five percent of my touring like all
of this stuff can vary and it's up to
you to get creative and it comes both
ways from a standpoint of
what's the value of these people in my
eyes and of course what value do they
see in you or can they bring to you as
skills still from your perspective
that's what you you care about the most
so
a singles deal I think is a good way for
many artists to
see how much labels don't do oftentimes
right and it's lower commitment because
you're not fully in that relationship
it's only one song locked up you still
have an entire catalog if that song
continues to move and takes off then you
now have new attention that's being
brought to your other music you're
playing et cetera yeah right and that's
ideally though right the reality is
they can get locked up for they can lock
you up for that one song and not do [\h__\h]
yeah 100 and that just suck that's the
reality of it but the whole dream is oh
I'm only giving one ownership of one
song or partial ownership of one song or
sharing my royalties for this one song
and when it blows up I'm gonna have a
big name and the rest of this goes into
this catalog that I got so much
attention for that is the ideal scenario
yeah right but both sides is hey well
the song actually got zero gains only my
work that I've continued to do has
brought attention to it but what they've
done hasn't really get done much for me
yeah right so you know it's a it's an
ebb and flow to that and how you
approach it so I'm not saying hey just
because someone's offering you a singles
deal it's a no-brainer you should do it
you still have to get into
stipulations like my marketing budget
what is that if I do get a marketing
budget and what does that look like
because a label will say
you have a marketing budget but when you
actually go to work with them you don't
get tapped into any of that budget right
oh yeah we have a 50k marketing budget
for you but we have to prove every
little thing and every little bit of
spin for this marketing budget right so
whatever your system was beforehand
I have to approve it or maybe you didn't
have a system but you want to do some
stuff I now have to approve
every bit of that span and I'm gonna be
scrutinizing maybe I'm more flexible to
the stuff that is actually paying me
because you can use my studio or use my
content creator use my agency whatever
that looks like and then I'll say don't
do any of this other stuff right or
maybe
I'm just super tight with the purse
strings of how I spend the budget and I
don't have enough of a vision and
understanding of current marketing
to be able to say yes that's a good move
and no that's a bad move yeah so now I'm
not approving things you should do and
I've seen many times where artists will
have a 50k marketing budget and they
don't see 10k of it yeah all right 200k
marketing budget and they only see 100K
of that 200k in their agreements over
and they just never see it ever but they
come in with this idea this is my
marketing budget this is how much money
so there has to be additional
stipulations one of what actually
getting that marketing budget looks like
right not oh y'all just spend it but hey
how much of that do I get to take and
spend
based on my own discernment but then two
what are the specifics in general
like again not just what I get
but how does getting it look yeah period
right not what you're going to do or can
do but under what circumstances you're
going to give it to and then the last
thing is
that Vision again right how close can
y'all get in terms of the vision that
you want to achieve all right and how
much are they not only aligned with that
but understand the type of marketing
that makes sense for you as an artist
because if y'all are on the same page
there it's still gonna come back to the
same thing y'all are button heads and
even and look both ways could actually
be something that worked yeah but they
want to go about it in a different way
so I know it sounds like way more
detailed and nuanced than you would
think when it's saying when it comes to
what should I do when the label reaches
out but that's all the type of stuff
that you're actually looking for and the
more detail that you're asking some of
these questions
the more people start to understand it's
like oh this person is somebody who's
serious and we're not we can't just
throw [\h__\h] out of there can just [\h__\h]
them over bro just can't [\h__\h] them over
look at that brother have a conversation
ask some questions have another
conversation and get some terms get a
lawyer get a lawyer your lawyer bro
that's what the four or five step
process right hey well look get a lawyer
it's probably number one advice
however
make sure that lawyers are not the
labels lawyer make sure that label's not
one of the home that lawyers not one you
know a homie if somebody in some kind of
way all those things you know we think
is obvious but you know there's people
who are different parts of the ladder so
make sure that lawyer is you know fresh
and fit for you yeah exactly right and
that's that's why I say a lot later
because I I don't think one is needed
until like terms are presented but the
moment like it's like if we just having
the conversation yeah you don't need one
right we just talking but once like
terms are presented hey I think you
would look great in this deal lawyer
lawyer up yes I don't even know I once
out of um
uh one of my manager homies I remember
they was doing negotiating with a label
and he I always remember like because I
always thought it was so funny that he
said this [\h__\h] but they sent him some
contract and he couldn't understand it
and that was about to get low they end
up they did end up getting a lawyer so
it worked out but I remember he told the
labor he was like
send me this contract like you're
sending it to a third grader
and if my third credit cousin can't read
this I'm not real I'm not signing
nothing and they did it bro they went
back and took this like 30 page document
and condensed it into like four or five
pages but it was very serious it was
crazy bro I didn't think that was gonna
do it they really wanted his artists you
know what I'm saying so they wouldn't
make it work and then he took that to
the lawyer and then lawyer did his thing
from there but you know so I was like
but you you know you can ask for [\h__\h]
bro that's really it bro ask questions
have the conversation that lawyer up and
what I like about that last part that
you just said because yeah that was
always funny to me that that happened
but it's real
you want to make it as simple for you to
understand as possible yeah 100 and I
think growing up
you tend to think
when it comes to contracts you almost
expect it to be so complex and out of
your league then when you encounter a
complex contract you think something's
wrong with me because I don't understand
this [\h__\h] not something's wrong with
them yeah but you need to be thinking
something's going on here how can I
simplify this as much as possible again
still want to get that lawyer at the end
of the day but how can I get this to a
point where it makes it simple it sense
to me as possible so yeah 100 anything
like that okay can you simplify this can
you explain this what's going on here
your lawyer's gonna help with that but I
love the just hey yo take the whole
contract and shorten this [\h__\h] like I
heard the other like this shouldn't be
longer than x number of pages right when
people do stuff like that anything that
helps you out because a lot of times
there's a lot of Superfluous information
it's not trippy over words man in
perpetuity for continuity of the
universe like what are you talking about
reverse bruh
that's the bruh the universe [\h__\h] is why
I didn't sign that contract when um who
reached out to me I don't know if it was
NBC or Wall Street Journal so they were
doing a Dominic Fike series New York
Times was right and I don't know who the
company if it was them specifically or
the company doing the dock or whatever
they hit me up they wanted to use part
of my Dominic fight video in there and
and you know I'm like oh that's so
that's a good look I ain't trying to
make money out of here and none of that
like that but
I just couldn't
at the time with the perpetuity and the
universe aspect of it you know I mean
I'm like I don't know where my career is
going to be is gonna be in 20 years I
might decide to become a politician or
something you know what I mean uh like a
run for election whatever whatever and
then all of a sudden they got the
ability to use this and all these
different platforms it might flip it
somehow I I told the lady hey
I would just like it to say y'all can
use it for this show this series
and any formatting of this series I
understand that whenever you use it
anywhere else in any other way you still
want to be able to use that because you
don't know what you're going to do with
the series but nah I can't just have it
languished where you own this content or
can use this content for anything beyond
this series and I don't know what that
is to me that was just a weird thing and
you know she was like oh man you know
yeah I'll send that back so it was like
dope she sent that back but then of
course the
people end up going a different
direction
you know it was just a different
creative Direction you know people who
were less resistant possibly you know
what I mean we don't need to have these
problems or potential problems which I
get I respect that at the end of the day
and I was like dang you know that sucks
but I don't know you know you kind of
just had to take that [\h__\h] on a chin and
I actually say that same thing when it
comes to labels if you feel
like you missed out on an opportunity
but it came from you trying to be
diligent
you just gotta take it on the channel
and let that feeling right because it
might feel weird for a second and you
might feel like oh when's the next one
coming but you good you'll be all right
you'll be all right more opportunities
they're coming they're coming out let's
see the Jermaine gum said depending on
if you have any leverage if you do keep
your Masters and if possible you're
publishing if possible
are you being on that if possible and I
understand why they like they're like
the comfort of publishing we know that's
that's where the money is oh there's a
clip I want you to see but if you don't
have any leverage you most likely won't
even get a 50 50 deal most likely you'll
only get around 15 for your music for
example which most people don't know
Bruno Mars when he had the hit out
called that's what I like he was only
getting around 15 off that song I found
that out when I was being taught in
Berkeley College of Music and music
business 101. so please be careful man
um I mean that's a nice comment that's a
nice comment I didn't know that about um
about kind of Bruno actually just
realized I corrected that because he
wrote berno but uh let's let's read a
couple other comments let me see Nate
James said just be wary of label execs
bro any label that would throw 10K at an
artist to see if they go anywhere
oh okay he said anybody any label will
throw 10K and the artist just to see if
they go anywhere and if they don't then
they can just dump you and move on make
sure you're ready and then hire a good
music lawyer to make sure you aren't
getting taken advantage of now
yes it is a part of many labels business
model 100 to put in a small investment
pump and don't
pump and dump 100 I see that bad boy go
if it don't go hey we keep moving and I
think this is the Catch-22 of these
artist friendly agreements yeah that we
see today we're like oh yes six months
licensing deal one-year licensing deal
or whatever with an option what we're
basically saying is hey I'm Gonna Give
You 10K 20K whatever the number is
and that's the number already worked out
in my investment strategy if it worked
cool if it don't work it's not great but
I'm good right so this is the money I'm
gonna put in There's an opportunity here
if things pop I have the option that's
the biggest thing people are just be
saying you know I got an option in my
contract no this ain't sports bra like
and even in some sports is different but
you don't have an option they got an
option yeah to say do you stay do you go
right so they have that option oh if
this works let's keep working right or
if I for whatever reason want to keep
you locked down even if it screw you
over let's keep keep working quote
unquote keep you under contract but
other than that
you lose
whatever period of time on your end what
else do you have to lose I mean the deal
if it really does work out it's great
you know
um depending on what you have but let's
just assume it's only a royalty
agreement you don't have to give any up
of your Masters anything like that and
you did a
let's say what would be a number like
maybe 50k for
20 percent
and that's that's very please don't
think that's a standard that y'all
should need to you know like sit by
making sure I'm just making yeah I'm
making [\h__\h] up that I know someone who's
done who's done that or whatever
whatever
um but here's the thing being locked
down really matters right
and I know it doesn't seem like it
because it is again it is more friendly
than what existed before but
like I know an artist that
uh drops this song
song takes off
and they promised him so much money
um in marketing budget let me see I
think it was 30 or 40K right and then
all this other money that would be will
come after they dropped the music video
and things really get popping right
let's say song drops in January
and
his manager
got into
uh combative moment with basically the
label
manager was kind of like flying off off
the top ends up having to break up with
the manager but then the manager says I
still own all this stuff or like he was
he was playing some weird game with them
and they end up being in court
for six to eight months uh yeah and the
label wouldn't do anything at all
until
they figure this whole situation out so
now he had a song that was pop
ping moving this is like SoundCloud but
it's moving crazy ridiculous numbers but
now he can't drop the music video until
12 months later basically it drops in
the middle of December
like nobody's checking for it you know
you already know what December looks
like that's enough with zero marketing
and they've made this entire
um
they had this entire argument that it
should be dropped on the specific
YouTube page and I told them I told him
the long a lot the whole way along that
this [\h__\h] didn't make sense like I
dropped on a YouTube page that wasn't
his that wasn't popping itself but I'm
sure that I was probably like their
homie or something like that or whatever
like so the strategy is all bad so you
can get caught up in a situation with a
label even if it's a short term
agreement where you end up following
such bad advice
or they have such power over you that
they manipulate your moves and they can
suppress what you have going on maybe
not intentionally that's not what
they're trying to do but they're so
worried about whatever their personal
incentives are at the time and for their
strategy
you just get undercut as like a stray
you know you can't just trade bullet and
there goes uh a huge moment in time it
could be your career so
like I've seen this happen
multiple times like to artists
especially even with these short-term
like contracts like and they [\h__\h]
artists up and it sounds like oh yeah
short term that's a great thing yeah 10
months is nice that it's a short-term
agreement per se but in music 10 months
can be long too yeah yeah it's [\h__\h] it's
[\h__\h] like it's crazy
um let's see if there's one last comment
that every labor isn't bad every labor
isn't good
let's go with that that one last
statement I'll say this
it's all people always people it's all
people yeah that's all it is right so
you might have some good people you
might have some bad people and no oh
here's another thing that happened in
that time with that that artist the
people he came in with
the entire organization got switched up
and let's do it that's a real do it it's
a high risk they wanted to change things
up there was a whole new guard so now
all these people who believed in you and
saw you in the first place were no
longer there those type of things happen
right so at the end of the day it's
people he went from a good situation to
a bad situation literally because of the
people
um and also the management situation and
that legal people right so some people
have a luck of the draw some people are
good in the sermon but however you can
praying you know rolling dice
blind luck whatever it is man like try
to find the right people you can in this
industry