ly if we're talking about social
everything's video driven it's not
picture driven now it's video driven I'm
saying especially for music your music's
not even audio driven per se
anymore right Discovery is all through
video so he's him being vide driven you
can see how he can Master the art of
that so we're join the ads worked out I
guess right yeah it was our first it was
our first way of actually getting to um
you know our first call audience um he
he hit me up after about two months of
doing you know the ads and he was like
bro we you know we're doing we tried
some radio stuff over here you know um
we hired some Consultants to step in and
say they can do this and that or
whatever and he goes I'm not seeing a
result from any of it like I can't even
measure I don't even know if it's
working or not really you I'm saying he
goes but I know every morning I wake up
there's like 200 people in my Facebook
Messenger like in in in the in the in
you know the direct messages at that
time right and he goes and they all
telling me they discover my and
they love my and you know what I'm
saying so he was just like whatever you
doing bro just keep doing it because I
know that's reaching people you know
what I'm saying and at right now as an
artist he goes I just I just want my
to be seen and heard he goes the
worst thing is I craft like some of my
dopest and someone don't see it and
he goes that's like the worst feeling as
an artist so he goes I just want to make
sure it's getting seen so whatever that
is you're doing just keep doing it and
then we that's kind of how we built and
then you know I would I would show him
the platform and show him how how that
work and then he learned from that and
he would apply it you know what I'm
saying and um yeah I mean I wouldn't say
it would work for everybody cuz you got
to you got to be able to have that
mindset to make that work you know what
I mean like you got to have the mindset
to make that work for you like even the
way from from the way he you know
directs his videos the way writes
records like he know knows how to put
the pieces together you know he like a
director first that's interesting cuz I
was going to ask you like what you feel
sets Joiner apart he a director first
like he he filmed first like over
everything like you know what I mean
he's he's a really talented like they
don't people don't get people only see
the final product they don't see like
how he actually does it or how what goes
into like I've seen this guy just come
up with something shoot it next day it's
done and it's like masterpiece
you know what I mean and it's like that
quick you know because he he just know
and he edits all his videos too all
right so he don't have to think about
I've got to shoot mad and then
figure out what I want to use he's like
shoot that shoot that shoot that shoot
that I got it we're
done cuz he's the one editing and so he
already know what he want yeah yes so
when you say he's he's he's video first
a lot of times is it to the point to
where he's sometimes coming up with
video treatments before the the song is
created and he's working backwards from
there that's crazy okay damn so he's
writing into a world that already exists
basically yeah it's Unique it's super
unique so you know and obviously if
we're talking about social everything's
video driven it's not picture driven now
it's video driven you I'm saying
especially for music your music's not
even audio driven per se
anymore right discoveries all through
video so he's him being video driven you
can see how he can master art of that
you know um and that's also why he's
also like one of those artists that's
not like overly like saturated online he
don't just post every single day you
know what I'm saying like he's not that
artist and I think it's because he has
like this level of like um Integrity or
what he wants to put out does that make
sense yeah he cares about the art yeah
at the end of the day and and and you
know that platform works for him
strictly for that so he treats that
equally as impactful if that makes sense
yeah you know I just saw a video he
posted May with within the last week
where it's like this one shot and the
cameras are going like around them and I
was just like this is crazy and then
here you basically saying it like he's
directing all this it just puts a whole
another level into what you saying want
that whole thing to be a one tape and so
you know what I mean and you go to the
will concept where he took like all the
movies that Wills ever did and green
screened all of them oh
yeah was able to write the song where
he's including the title of every song
without it sounding whack like you know
what I'm saying like just yo just such
an incredible Talent bro like you know
and for me it's a for me it's such an
honor to be able to like figure
something out and then be able to get
take that talent and apply it and take
it to the next level you know what I'm
saying that's crazy you know what I mean
cuz it's not it it for me it was like
I'm over here spending money on products
like promoting products like product
maybe I don't even care about because my
job was just to help the company put the
product out you know what I'm saying so
there wasn't a sense of
like um you know accomplishment if the
issue it was all numbers Hey I converted
at this rate you know you got the lead
for this cost you made x amount of sales
you know this is how much was spent this
is a platform that's working here's your
conversion pixels you know tied in so if
you want to retarget them I got all your
tracking set up you know what I mean
like it's all that type of stuff you
know what I mean like it wasn't um there
was no like huge reward or feeling out
of it you know so doing it for something
like this was yeah it was definitely
like a very satisfying feeling artist
managers there is no way you should ever
do a regular pre-save campaign again
because forever fan has forever saves
where a fan could pre save your music
one time and then automatically pre-save
every song you ever release after that
that's right forever and on top of that
forever fan has email and texting all in
one platform this is built out for
artists who don't have huge teams and
don't want to get overwhelmed doing too
many things in too many different places
so go to Forever fanm music.com No
Labels that's no labels with an S and
put in the code No Labels O2 to get
access and try it out for only a dollar
Forever fan is your go-to place for your
marketing needs as an artist so you can
stay organized have your own
infrastructure to make it a lot easier
to go to the next level again that's for
everfan music.com SL no labels and type
in the code No Labels O2 at checkout to
get access for only a dollar now back to
the episode especially with your
creative background it's like yeah yo
it's crazy getting into music bro like y
I grew up in London right and
so the person that got me into music
he's one of the biggest producers in the
UK so he went to my high school his name
still Bangles right and he he basically
like DJ ked the UK like he he the he he
the biggest you know he started he he
was a DJs at one point then he he was
always making beats and now he like the
biggest essentially producer out the UK
or the newest Talent come through him
you know what I'm saying and um he went
to my high school and so after high
school you know me and him actually got
close and um he's the one that put me on
to music and introduced me to like Fu
loops and that so um before I came to
the states I was working with him and um
you know I was the one that was like
building the site and copyrighting the
music and sending it out you know back
then to C I read this thing where to
copyright the music um you would you
would mail the CD to yourself and you
don't open it the seal so you you have
certified mail copyright yeah yeah and
you don't and you don't remove the seal
so cuz it's certified so so um I was
doing that with him back then mailing
the back and the certified seal cuz
you know like like that you know
booking gigs and you know they had these
um things in the UK called daytimers
right where
um I think it was a it was it was a way
of allowing like young people to go to
the club in a safe way you know what I
mean um but not at night
tunnel oh wow that's funny yeah yeah
yeah so um we finish high school over
there when you're
16 so they set up these day ERS in the
city where you'd go to these clubs and
you you know there would
be basically be a club but during the
day yeah day parties you know what I
mean so that was like where you know you
would be able kind of like you'd be 16
years old but you could still have like
that going out to party experience cuz
you leave high school when you're 16 so
you know you're going into college still
young though so uh yeah I would like try
to book
gigs you know copyright the music pay
for studio time you know my uncle he
leave for like 6 months out the year so
we' be at his crib and making beats on
the PC and so on the food Loops so
he t me how to like use food loops and
that's when I was like oh I'm going to
go music school so I can actually learn
it so that's why I moved to the states
and I went to
fep for that reason but then fast
forward he ends up being the biggest
producer in the
UK which is crazy cuz I was like almost
investing time into him too you know cuz
I I believed in him he he got a nice hit
rate man no no there there's definitely
some L's there between for sure there's
definitely something else you know what
I'm saying that we talk about but yeah
like but he waso he was so dope like at
that time he was like before his time
gotcha bro he was he was already like he
would listen to songs and Sample out
sounds out the song and throw them into
FL and arrange that one sound into the
drum pattern he was doing like that
in like
2002 right he was like playing like old
records he he show me like the song his
mom listen to or something and he was
taking sounds from there and throwing
them into beats he was Mak like he was
doing crazy back then you know what
I'm saying so he was he was already like
set for like greatness if you ask me cuz
he was already just so in tune with it
it was a matter of if he was going to
quit that was really going to determine
if he was going to become you know who
he could be in in in music right if he
quit then all right cool but if he was
going to stay at it like it was only a
matter of time and obviously you know
what I'm saying if you see he's at now
you know it shows that he's you know he
he stuck with
it yeah what I'm wondering man right so
we get a lot of people ask us about
music schools and and there's a part of
me that can kind of understand going
back then because industry was a lot
less accessible versus today where you
can kind of like damn near DM anybody or
you possibly a response back so do you
think if you were 16 year old now you
would you would still go to full Cale or
you think you would just feet to the
pavement just hit the ground grinding
the DIY way that's a tough
question everyone's at a different
starting point I think which is the most
like key thing so if you're like brand
new out of doing some thing out of your
bedroom and you don't really know enough
and you don't got resources around you
you know where they know enough so you
like don't really go anywhere to turn to
get what you know what you want to get
other than like Googling and finding
yourself yeah you
know school doesn't just like give you
information cuz you can get the
information anywhere you know School
almost it's like a personal trainer it's
like going to the gym and having a
personal trainer right a personal
trainer keeps you on track and make sure
you there every day at a certain time
and you're doing scheduling and so
school is your personal trainer you know
what I mean it's making sure you're in
the classroom you're there at a certain
time you're getting the information it's
testing you on it right it's holding you
accountable cuz otherwise you fail your
class right yeah so you know if you're
one of those people that needs that you
know where you need to be held
accountable you know then I would say
yeah school like school would probably
help cuz you're going to be accountable
um if you're one of those people where
you know you could wake up and put 5
hours 2 hours 6 hours some whatever time
you have into what you want to do then
um then maybe you don't need school
maybe you can do the research and you
know I never went to school for
marketing but that's because I was
willing to invest so many hours into bro
there was one point I invested so many
like when I met Joiner I was antisocial
I would even talk to people cuz I would
spent so much time just focused on a
computer I didn't care about outside
yeah I was like this is my value
right here right and I'm going call
every hour and time instead of hour you
going going out and doing this whatever
no I'm I'm putting it right here let's
take a quick commercial break to talk
about Spotify discovery mode one of the
most powerful tools when it comes to
marketing music today because it puts
your music in the algorithm on Spotify
to be listened to along with music
similar to you without you having to run
ads without you having to do any content
at all which is why a lot of artists
tell me they love it but a lot of
artists don't necessarily have access to
Spotify discovery mode unless you're a
two loss user because with two loss all
artists have a fair shot at getting
access to Spotify discovery mode just by
submitting through them and they pitch
all of their artist music to Spotify to
be considered for discovery mode so if
you don't meet the criteria if you are
in the position where some of the larger
artists are sign up for two loss
distribution at two loss.com that's to
lost.com because that's just one of many
extremely valuable features that t lost
offers to his artist to make their lives
easier and you can try out two loss for
free by using the code No Label that's n
o l b e l when you sign up so go to T
los.com and check out how you can get
your music heard everywhere