Most artists think that community
building means to post a lot and then
tell people to hit the Discord link. But
if we look real deep, that's why the
Discords are silent. That's why the
shows are halfpacked and that's why the
fans don't really feel connected to that
artist. But the artists who are thriving
are realizing that community building
isn't just another marketing buzzword.
It's a literal survival kit for the
modern-day artist. And so in this video,
I'm going to show you how you can spice
up your community building. You know
what I'm saying? Make the fans feel a
little bit more engaged. And I'm going
to show you a couple of real world
examples along the way. But before we
get into all that, if you look below
this video, you should see a join
button. We have launched our membership
space, no labels necessary, backstage
pass. If you click over there, you'll
find a lot of exclusive content,
extended versions of vlogs and
interviews. And you know, we plan to do
a couple of live streams. You know, I
got a nice little content review planned
for you guys that have been asking us to
review your content and give you
feedback. So, if you've been wanting
more No Labels Necessary content, click
through on that join button. And if not,
make sure you hit that like button,
subscribe, share this with an artist
that needs a little bit of gain today.
With that being said, let's get into it.
Now, I want to say this again. Community
building isn't just another marketing
buzz word. Even though you guys have
probably been hearing it left and right
from your different music industry
gurus, at this point, it is literal
survival. The industry is moving towards
a more communityoriented market. And the
artists that are smart and the artists
that are ahead and the artists that are
tired of playing the same game that
artists have been playing for the last
decades, you know, for being honest, are
starting to realize just how important
building a community that's authentic to
them and their music is. So for the
artists that want support that outlast
algorithms or survives label changes or
you know sticks with you through any
phase in your artist career, these are
the tips that you want to follow. So tip
number one is going to be to craft a
story that people want to live inside.
Now this is more about defining a
worldview than it is about defining your
personal story. Basically you're trying
to give people a why as to why they
should join your community. It sucks to
say, but fans today need a lot more than
just a good song or two to make them
want to be a part of, let's just call it
a movement, right? Or a part of your
community. And a lot of that energy and
a lot of that attention starts with the
story and the why you're giving them as
to why they should even think about
joining your community. So, I want you
guys to check out a couple of posts from
this artist named Qua Artist. He goes by
Black Star Boy on Instagram. And when I
think about an artist that I see
defining a story around their movement,
I I think about this guy. He's been over
my timeline, you know what I'm saying?
Heavy for the last two 2 3 weeks or so.
But check out this video that he put
out.
>> Lately, I feel like I've been running a
place. I'm working harder than ever. But
I feel like I'm not necessarily
increasing my value. That's when I
realized maybe the answer isn't to run
faster in the same system, but to blow
the whole thing up and start my own
thing. So, I came up with this. This is
my album. All you do is take this card,
plug it in your phone, and my 21 song
album is right there in your files app.
You own the music. Plus, you get the
highest quality files possible. If you
want it, go to my website and purchase
it now because my album is not going on
Spotify.
>> So, what is this artist doing, right?
He's setting up the tone for the type of
people that he wants to attract, not
only with his music, but with his
overall world he's building. And if I
was to look at this video and break it
down, he wants people that are
disruptors. He wants people that are
feeling like, "Hey, I'm tired of being
stuck inside of the same system, you
know, running my life like a hamster
wheel, and I too want to do something
different." Well, I too want to do
something that's typically against the
norm of whatever industry that I'm in.
So, we can already tell, hey, this video
and this move that he's about to make
with his career is clearly meant for the
disruptor archetype. And I want you guys
to check out another video that he puts
out because I think that ties all
together and reinforces that point even
more.
>> I'm not dropping my album on Spotify.
Instead, it's going on this. And I think
this has the potential to shake up the
entire industry. Why would I give my
album to a streaming service and just
hope the algorithm recommends it when I
could just give it right to you? All you
do is take this card, plug it in your
phone, and my 21 song album is right
there in your files app. You own the
music, so you can save it to your phone
and listen whenever, wherever, even if
you don't have Wi-Fi. Plus, you get the
highest quality files possible. If you
want it, you can purchase it now on my
website.
>> So, yeah. So, I think these videos kind
of get the gist right. And if you were
to go through the rest of his profile
and look at all of the content that he's
been putting out, particularly for this
this campaign that he's running, each
video is pretty much laying out a
breadcrumb for people who want to be in
the world with others who are
disruptors, who once again like to go
against the grain or who like to
experiment with new things. So, if I'm
someone that's watching this video,
right, I may not even like his music
initially because if you even pay
attention to those two clips I played,
we don't even hear his music in those
songs, right? we're being won over
strictly off of mission statement and
motivation for doing something like
this. And once again, there is a side of
your fan base or your potential fan base
that is interested in that. You're
telling me as a fan that you don't want
to put your music on Spotify or you want
to throw a show or you want to raise
$50,000. And you will be surprised at
how many fans would join and fold and
support if you just told them the why or
if you just took two seconds to sit down
and break down why do I even want people
to be a part of my movement beyond just
liking the music. Wait, quick pause
because a lot of you have been asking,
"How can I work with you guys
one-on-one?" And yes, we can run almost
any type of marketing campaign at this
point, but honestly, we prefer working
with clients from a consulting
standpoint because we actually get a
chance to deep dive into their music. We
can work on their brand. We can work on
their content strategy. We can tie it
all together into a marketing campaign.
Basically, we can give you a blueprint
on how to grow, monetize, and win. So,
if you're an artist that's serious about
getting their branding together, their
content strategy together, their
marketing together, then apply for a
call with our Country Brand Agency arm
using the link in the description below.
Serious inquiries only, please, guys.
So, if this sounds like something you
need, once again, hit that link in the
description. And if not, we still love
you anyway. All right, guys. Commercial
break over. Let's get back to the video.
Tip number two is going to be to give
fans bragworthy, identifiable items.
Now, this is where I think community
building starts to truly get unique for
every single artist that is selling
something to their fan base. One, these
items are going to end up becoming
collectibles and they're going to end up
becoming items that fans can use to flex
on other fans. That's a nice way to say
it, right? So, if I'm a if I feel like
I'm a high tier fan and I'm in your fan
base and another fan comes and
challenges me to the the ownership, you
know what I'm saying, of that spot. If I
have this exclusive item that only the
people who showed up to your San Diego
popup got and this person doesn't have
it because clearly they weren't familiar
with you back then or they weren't as
tapped in, I automatically pull a rank
in that situation. Let's let's call a
spade a spade, right? I get to feel good
and I get to feel uh more dominant than
your fan base within that situation.
Also, I think that fans start to see
these items as more worthy of their
money and their time because it feels
like you as the artist have actually put
time into something or into creating
something that I want to keep forever. I
don't just want a t-shirt or a sticker
pack or a hat. I want something that I
can remember forever. So, I want you
guys to check out this artist named
Mario Craft because I think that she did
an amazing job at putting together a
really unique merch item that her fans
are going to be talking about forever.
Check this out.
>> Do you remember when these came out in
2006? iPod Shuffle Generation 2 with the
little clip. So, you could literally
wear them as you listened or you could
put it in your hair as a barret. I mean,
the options were limitless with these
guys. So, I've been sourcing these all
over eBay. I've been bidding on them,
making sure that they are tested and
that they work and that they come with
charging docks. Some of them don't. So,
I've been sourcing charging docks. I've
collected 20 of them, and I'm releasing
my debut album 1 month early, only on
the iPod Shuffle. So, come with me as I
find out what's on this iPod Shuffle,
who had it, maybe make some assumptions
about their life, and restore it to put
on a new playlist of songs that I can't
wait to share with you. Into the dock,
Archie.
>> So, I'm not going to play the rest of
the video, but you guys get the gist.
This is a great collectible item. Not
only are you getting a vintage iPod,
right, which you're if you're someone
who's into their era of pop culture or
you were there, you know, and have just
some type of nostalgia moments attached
to it, you might buy it just off of
that. You know what I'm saying? I can't
even think of the last time I saw a iPod
in real life. Like I personally would
buy one just off the strength of
thinking that where else am I going to
get this. But if you go and you look
through her her page and you look at her
branding and you look at the the style
of music that she makes, this aligns
with that audience. You know what I'm
saying? She has a little bit of like a
like a One Tree Hill vibe going on. And
I can imagine that her fan base finds
things like these nostalgic. Now, you
might be thinking to yourself, "But
Corey, fans don't buy this type of
stuff, right? They want to buy a
t-shirt. They want to buy a lighter.
They want to buy the basic items." And
you're not wrong, right? Like the vast
majority of your fan base isn't going to
be someone that will spend $100 on an
iPod just to get your album early. But
those 10 or 20 or 30 or 40 or however
many people that do, those are going to
be the most diehard members of your
community, those are going to be the
ones that that scream your name to the
mountain tops. And those are going to be
the ones that are 60 or 70 years old
telling their grandkids about how they
got this iPod from one of their favorite
artists back in the day. And if you're
still skeptical about even if you try
something like this, if people will buy
it, check out this other video that she
put out.
>> Oh my gosh, it's been 1 minute. Okay,
we're we're live.
>> We're live. We're live. We're live.
Godspeed everybody. I'm nervous for
everyone. Let's see who's going to be
first. Oh, first one. Second one. Liz
Nelson. Congrats, Liz. You got the first
one. Orange. Oh, man. Oh, they're
rolling in now.
>> Yeah. Oh, man.
>> Oh my god.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh. Oh my god. It's 10:01. I
think they're gone. Is that
>> Every single color is sold out.
>> Every single color sold out, right? And
I believe she said that she was only
selling 20 copies. So, when you're
creating these items that are meant to
be these super unique and memorable
things, they just need to be connected
to your brand. They need to be in
limited supply. I can imagine that this
campaign would have went as well if she
had 10,000 to sell or 20,000, right?
Like a big box artist. But the fact that
there's a little bit of collectibility
here, I can be the person that has one
out of 20 or one out of whatever is
creative, right? is something that I
can't find every day and I'm not going
to find within every artist experience
that I'm a part of. And it's something
that a year from now, 5 years from now,
10 years from now, I can use to show my
devotion and my loyalty to this to that
artist. And you will be surprised at how
many artists never even realize they can
get things like this off of the ground
because they don't even try. Once again,
there's nothing wrong with playing the
t-shirt, hat, sticker game. But at some
point, if you really want to test the
the strength of your community or if you
want to give your community something a
little bit stronger to rally around or
or a product that will make them go
like, "Do I want to spend my last dollar
for my last paycheck on buying
something?" Items like this are what you
need to be looking at. And it doesn't
have to be an iPod like she did. Take
some time out to actually think about
what's unique about your brand and how
could you turn that uniqueness into a
product that people can collect forever.
And while we're on the topic of
unforgettable things, the last tip is to
create unforgettable experiences and
moments for your fans. Now, this is the
one where if I say that the items is
like medium high tier, the event
planning and the unique experiences is
where it gets really really high tier in
terms of being able to tell if a artist
is locked in around their community.
Now, the reality is is that a lot of
fans are tired of the traditional artist
experience. You know, like every fan
isn't willing to pay $20 or $15 to come
see you live at a show, right? Every fan
isn't going to want to go to a festival,
you know, buy a ticket to Rolling Loud
or One Music Fest just to hang out in a
hot, sweaty line and come see you. But
some fans would be more than willing to
pop out if they had something that felt
like, hey, I can't get this everywhere.
I can't just I can't go to this all the
time. And I want to show you guys this
video of an artist who I think provided
his fan base with exactly something like
that. So, if you check out your screen,
you'll see this really cool invite from
a rapper by the name of Black Sam. Now,
when Black Sam was rolling out his
album, he decided to do a really fancy
dinner party for his fans that pulled
up. And so, I'm going to read the the
the caption on the post for you guys.
Delaze the beat with Criminy Buff. So,
Mommy can deepen. On September 6th, the
legendary Black Sam is pulling up on us
for a Michelin Man dinner party to
celebrate his debut album held in an
undisclosed location. 13 songs, 13
courses. For more info, and to be added
to the wait list for tickets, comment
sumac and we'll reach out from the This
is Somewhere account. Right. So instead
of having a regular listening party
where you're sitting in a a music
studio, he decided to have a 13 course
meal to represent the 13 songs on his
upcoming album and let fans be a part of
their experience. And now I don't
believe that he put out any video of it,
but if we look at these pictures from
the event, like look at this night. You
know what I'm saying? Like doesn't this
look like something that you will want
to be a part of, right? So really fancy
vibes, really fancy dinner. And if you
would to check this artist out, um, some
of this I know just from having a
conversation with him. Some of this I
know from paying attention to him. He
himself is really into cooking. Like
he's talked on songs and in his captions
and on his stories and and in other
forms of content about how much of a
chef he is in real life and how much he
cares about cooking. So, he was able to
take something that if you're a fan of
him, you know, hey, Black Sam is
passionate about culinary arts. He talks
about it in his music and he's always
talked about doing something like this.
And then now you see that in order to
promote his event, he's putting together
an event that merges both of those
worlds. And going back to my point
earlier at the uh the beginning of this
topic, half the battle of creating a
unique experience for fans is doing
something that they're not going to get
out of any other artist that they're a
fan of. Right? Like I follow a lot of
artists outside of Black Sam. I ain't
really seen no other artist put this
together yet. Right? And I'm not saying
that no artist ever will do this idea or
that there aren't other artists out
there who have done this idea. But I'm
saying that from my fan world, from
where I'm paying attention, this is new
and unique and cool to me, right? And I
don't know how much he sold for tickets,
but I would assume for a 13 course meal,
man, I would think Bro came out, you
know, at least maybe like 150 250 for
tickets. You know what I'm saying? That
might be with him being cool with with
spending money. And you will be
surprised at how many fans wouldn't pay
15, 20, $25 to see you at a show, but
will pay $150 to go go-karting with you
or will pay $200 to go camping with you
or will pay $500 to, I don't know, like
go to a a spa with you and have a spa
day or something, right? Fans, when it
comes to these events, are really just
looking for something to do. You know
what I'm saying? Like, at this point,
you're no different than me planning any
other date night. you're no different
than me planning any other activity for
myself. And I think that where a lot of
artists are dropping the ball is that
they're not thinking about how I can
take unique things about myself and my
interest that I have shared with my fan
base and turn that into some type of
experience that fans can come live
alongside right with me. But the reality
is is that if you become an artist that
is doing something like that for your
fans, because the rest of that artist
that they follow are probably not even
thinking about this stuff or trying to
put together an event that's that's a
tenth as entertaining as something like
this. If you figure out what that looks
like for you, you will have much better
success with getting people to want to
be a part of your community because
they'll start to see that not only am I
attached to a story and a movement that
could possibly become bigger than me,
not only am I getting to spend my money
on items that I feel like represent what
I care for and they and they they give
me a conversation piece and it's
something that I feel is unique and and
valuable. You're also giving them a
memory, a lifelong experience that once
again they are not going to get anywhere
else. You know what I'm saying?
especially if you do a really good job
of making sure that the experience is
tied to something that is uniquely
linked to you. So, just to give you guys
a quick recap, one, you got to define
the worldview. Give your people a why as
to why they should be joining your
community. Two, give fans bragworthy
items. These items become marketing
tools in their own right, and they
become this memorabilia that your fans
will never forget. And three, create
events that create memories and
experiences that they'll never get being
a part of anybody else's fan base. And
with patience, strategy, good music, and
these tips, you'll have a dieh hard
community in no time. So guys, which
strategy are you going to try first?
Which of these parts of the community
building do you feel like you need to
work on and polish and develop and all
that good stuff? Drop in the comment
section below. And if you are an artist
that's already dived into the community
building, what have you been doing that
you have seen resonate really well with
your fan base and has made them want to
be a part of your community and grow it
stronger? And once again, if you feel
like you're learning anything, hit that
like button, share this button with the
arts in these little bit of game, and
hit that subscribe button. And with that
being said, I'll see you guys in the
next video.